My name is Max.
My world is fire and blood.
Why are you hurting these people?
It's the oil, stupid.
Oil wars.
We are killing for guzzoline.
The world is running out of water.
Now there's the water wars.
Once, I was a cop.
A road warrior searching
for a righteous cause.
--to the terminal freak-out point.
Mankind has gone rogue,
terrorizing itself.
Thermonuclear skirmish.
The earth is sour.
Our bones are poisoned.
We have become half-life.
As the world fell...
each of us, in our own way,
was broken.
It was hard to know
who was more crazy:
Me...
or everyone else.
Hello?
Where are you?
Where are you, Max?
Here they come again.
Max Rockatansky.
Worming their way
into the black matter of my brain.
Help us, Max.
You promised to help us.
I tell myself...
they cannot touch me.
They are long dead.
I am the one...
who runs from both
the living and the dead.
Hunted by scavengers.
Haunted by those I could not protect.
So I exist in this wasteland.
A man reduced to a single instinct:
Survive.
Max?
Is that you?
Where were you?
Help us. Where were you?
Where were you, Max?
Stop running.
You let us die!
You promised to help us!
Why?
Witness!
I got him.
We are War Boys!
War Boys!
Kamakrazee War Boys!
Fucacima kamakrazee...
War Boys!
Hooked on!
Today we're heading...
to Gas Town!
Gas Town!
Today we're hauling Aqua Cola.
Aqua Cola!
Today we're hauling produce!
Produce!
And today we're hauling...
Mother's Milk!
Joe! Joe! Joe! Immortan Joe!
Rev it up for the Immortan Joe!
Once again, we send off my War Rig
to bring back...
guzzoline from Gas Town...
and bullets from the Bullet Farm!
Once again, I salute my Imperator...
Furiosa!
And I salute...
my half-life War Boys...
who will ride with me eternal...
on the highways of Valhalla.
V8! V8! V8! V8!
I am your redeemer.
It is by my hand...
you will rise from the ashes...
of this world!
It's coming. Get ready.
Yes. Yes. Yes. It's coming.
Do not, my friends...
become addicted to water.
It will take hold of you...
and you will resent its absence.
Clear off!
Get them all off!
Get them all off.
Get off!
Signal Gas Town. Convoy's on its way.
I got a War Boy...
running on empty.
Hook up that full-life.
Hey! Careful. That's a universal donor.
Boss, we're not going to Gas Town?
Bullet Farm?
We're heading east.
I'll pass it down the line.
New orders!
Thunder up! Thunder up!
This is not a supply run!
Go. Go.
Ace, what's going on?
Go. We're heading east.
Why?
I don't know. That's the order.
Hey, Pa.
You know about this?
Your produce ain't going to Gas Town.
She's gone off-road...
into hostile territory.
Why would she do that?
Let me see.
Rictus.
I wanna see.
Go see what's agitating Dad.
Splendid!
Angharad!
Where are they?
They are not your property.
Miss Giddy?
You cannot own a human being.
Sooner or later someone pushes back!
Where is she taking them?
She didn't take them.
They begged her to go!
Where is she taking them?
A long way from you.
Hey. Hey, what's happening?
Slit!
What's going on? Slit!
Treason. Betrayal.
An Imperator gone rogue.
An Imperator.
Who?
Furiosa! She took a lot of stuff
from Immortan Joe.
What stuff?
Breeders! His prize breeders!
He wants them back!
Not a hand laid on them.
By my deeds I honor him.
V8.
V8! V8! V8!
That's my wheel.
I'm driving.
You're my lancer.
I just promoted myself.
Not today. Today is my day.
Look at you.
If you can't stand up,
you can't do war.
He's right, son.
I'm not staying here dying soft.
You're already a corpse.
I just need a top-up. More juice.
No time!
We take my Blood Bag.
We take my Blood Bag
and strap him to the lancer's perch.
It's got a muzzle on it. It's feral.
That's right.
High-octane crazy blood filling me up.
If I'm gonna die...
I'm gonna die historic
on the Fury Road.
Yeah. Yeah.
Organic, hitch up his Blood Bag.
Eh?
Right-o.
How much more can they take from me?
They've got my blood.
Now it's my car!
Immortan!
Immortan Joe!
He looked at me!
He looked right at me!
He looked at your Blood Bag!
He turned his head.
He looked me in the eye.
He was scanning the horizon.
No.
I am awaited.
I am awaited in Valhalla!
Confucamus!
Immortan!
Yeah!
Hey! Heads up!
Heads up!
Boss!
We got vehicles from the Citadel.
They're firing flares.
They want reinforcements from Gas Town...
and the Bullet Farm.
What is this?
Backup? Decoy?
It's a detour.
Eyes right!
Buzzards!
Buzzards right! Eyes on! Eyes on!
Buzzards right!
Eyes on!
Should we turn it around
and run them into our backup?
No! We're good!
We fang it!
Thunder up! Here we go!
Prepare the gunners!
Morsov!
Come on, attack!
War!
Ready!
She's ours, Slit!
She's ours.
First, we get the Buzzards off her back!
Form up!
That's my head!
Get up! You can do it!
Morsov!
No!
Witness me!
Witness!
Fly!
Mediocre, Morsov!
Mediocre!
Get ready!
Back me in!
They're coming!
We can't breathe down there!
Stay out of sight!
Now!
Go back!
Where's he going?
Hydraulics!
Yeah.
Now we bring home the booty.
She thinks she can lose us, Dad.
She thinks we're stupid.
She thinks she can lose us in there!
Fang it!
Why can't you stop?
Crew! Out of the way!
Out of the way!
What have you done?
Yeah.
We need counterweight.
Get the Blood Bag down the back.
Hunt them down!
Hey, head!
Say bye-bye to the neck!
We're going in!
Come on! We've almost got her!
Come on! Hold it steady!
Oh, what a day!
What a lovely day!
I am the man...
who grabs the sun...
riding to Valhalla!
Witness me...
Blood Bag!
Witness!
I live, I die, I live again!
We're not going back.
Water.
You.
Angharad, is that just the wind...
or is that a furious vexation?
I got it!
Glory me, Blood Bag!
We snagged her alive.
He's gonna shred her. Shred her.
Bolt cutters.
Chain.
Hey, hey!
Oh, look at them.
So shiny. So chrome.
He's gonna be so grateful.
We could ask for anything.
I wanna drive the War Rig.
What are you gonna ask for?
That's my jacket.
Sure.
You can ask for more than a jacket.
We're going to the Green Place.
Wait, it's you and me.
We're going to the Green Place
of Many Mothers.
How does it feel?
It hurts.
Out here, everything hurts.
You wanna get through this?
Do as I say.
Now pick up what you can and run.
Kill switches.
I set the sequence myself.
This Rig goes nowhere without me.
You can get in.
Not without them.
So we wait.
You're relying on the gratitude
of a very bad man.
You've damaged one of his wives.
How grateful do you think he's gonna be?
You're sitting on 2000 horsepower
of nitro-boosted war machine.
I'd say you got
about a five-minute head start.
You want that thing off your face?
Let's go.
Of all the legs you had to shoot,
that one was attached to his favorite.
Smeg!
You don't have to do it
just because he tells you.
What choice does she have?
He's not gonna hurt us. He needs us.
Why?
To bargain.
Oh, he'll hurt us.
Think he's coming to the Green Place?
Never! He's a crazy smeg...
who eats Schlesinger!
Nah, stay out of there.
Behind you.
The Gas Town Boys.
Don't damage the goods.
What do you see?
Big Rigs...
Polecats...
Flamers...
and there's the People Eater himself.
Coming to count the cost.
We're dragging something out back.
I think it's the fuel pod.
No, no.
I'll go.
Filth! You traitored him!
No unnecessary killing!
This War Boy wants me dead!
We agreed!
He's kamakrazee!
He's just a kid
at the end of his half-life!
No! I live. I die. I live again!
Hold him!
Tie him up!
Throw him out!
Chuck him out!
You got more friends.
Bullet Farmer.
They're coming from the Bullet Farm.
Yeah?
It's over. You can't defy him.
Just watch us, mate!
He is the one...
who grabbed the sun.
Look how slick he's fooled you.
He's a lying old man.
By his hand...
we'll be lifted up!
That's why we have...
his logo seared on our backs!
"Breeding Stock!" "Battle Fodder!"
No, I am awaited!
You're an old man's "Battle Fodder"!
Killing everyone...
and everything.
We're not to blame!
Then who killed the world?
I made a deal up ahead. Safe passage.
I don't know if it's still any good.
Get back in the hold!
Keep the hatch open.
I need you here.
You may have to drive the Rig.
You.
You stay.
You stay there.
Whatever you do, you can't be seen.
I'm supposed to be alone.
That was the deal.
Down here.
Hey.
What's your name?
What do I call you?
Does it matter?
Fine.
When I yell "fool"...
you drive out of here
as fast as you can.
This is the sequence:
One. One, two.
One.
Red. Black. Go.
You have it?
It's all here!
Three thousand gallons of guzzoline,
just like you asked!
I'm gonna unhitch the pod.
You drop the rocks.
You said:
"A few vehicles in pursuit.
Maybe."
We count three War Parties!
Yeah, well, I got unlucky.
Let's do this!
Fool!
That's our fuel!
Make way for the Ripsaw!
Come on! Move them!
Once I'm over...
clear the rocks
and bring everyone through.
Immortan!
Immortan Joe!
I got a War Boy!
Says he was on the War Rig.
You! Climb aboard!
Hey. Hey!
I got his boot!
I got the Blood Bag's boot!
Take me!
I got his boot!
All this for a family squabble.
Healthy babies.
Reload the clip.
I can't.
Gun!
Gimme the gun!
Not loaded yet!
Now!
We had a deal!
Rictus!
The wives!
No more flames.
Splendid!
That's my child!
My property!
Immorta--
Immortan. If I get on the Rig,
there's a way inside.
What is your name?
It's Nux.
I'll pike her in the spine.
Keep her breathing.
No.
Put a bullet in her skull.
Stop the Rig,
return my treasures to me...
and I, myself, will carry you...
to the Gates...
of Valhalla.
Am I awaited?
You will ride eternal...
shiny and chrome.
Rictus!
Help him aboard!
Ready?
Here we go!
Mediocre!
Schlanger!
Look out!
Angharad!
Get out!
No!
Angharad!
Stop! Turn the Rig around!
Go back for her!
No.
Tell him to turn the Rig around!
Did you see it?
She went under the wheels.
We keep moving.
No!
We keep moving!
He doesn't know what he's talking about!
Whatever happens,
we're going to the Green Place.
The stupid Green Place.
We don't even know where to find it!
You all right?
On! On!
Cheedo!
Cheedo, don't be stupid.
Stop!
He'll forgive us.
I know he will.
There is no going back!
We were his treasures!
Cheedo!
We were protected!
He gave us the high life!
What's wrong with that?
We are not things.
No!
We are not things!
We are not things.
I don't want to hear that again!
They were her words!
And now she's dead!
Wring your hands and tear your hair...
but you're not going back.
You're not going back to him.
Angharad!
Come on! Come on!
So...
where is this...
Green Place?
It's a long night's run, heading east.
We need inventory.
Match every gun with its bullets.
I'm gonna go and do some repairs.
We need someone down the back.
I'll go.
No.
I want you to stay together.
I can do it.
What are you doing here?
He saw it.
He saw it all.
My own Blood Bag driving the Rig
that killed her.
Stop doing that.
Stop.
Three times the gates were open to me.
What gates?
I was awaited in Valhalla.
They were calling my name.
I should be walking with the Immorta.
McFeasting with the heroes of all time.
I'd say it was your manifest destiny not to.
I thought I was being spared
for something great.
I got to drive a pursuit vehicle.
For a while even Larry and Barry
stopped chewing on my windpipe.
Who are Larry and Barry?
My mates.
Larry and Barry.
If they don't get me,
then the Night Fevers will.
Well, we've only got four for Big Boy here,
so he's all but useless.
But...
we can squirt off this little pinky
a raunchy 29 times.
Angharad used to call them Antiseed.
Plant one and watch something die.
Hold on, mate.
We are down 30,000 units of guzzoline...
19 canisters of nitro,
12 assault bikes...
seven pursuit vehicles.
The deficit mounts.
And now, sir...
you have us stuck in a quagmire.
Hey, Joe!
Boss!
Your girly's breathing her last!
What about the child?
Are you coming, brother?
Wait!
It's gone awful quiet in there.
Get it out.
Get it out!
Come on! I've been called to the torture!
Patience!
Oh, you stay here with your grief, Daddy.
I'll fetch them for you.
Be careful! Protect the assets!
Just one angry shot...
for Furiosa.
Hut!
Yeah!
Crying shame.
Come.
Another month...
could have been your viable human!
Was it a male?
Your A-1 Alpha prime.
Hey, Rictus!
You lost a baby brother!
Perfect in every way.
I had a baby brother!
I had a little baby brother!
And he was perfect!
Perfect in every way!
Come on.
Wouldn't wanna shoot the wives, sir.
Just probing.
He wants to help!
Who?
The War Boy!
Where did he come from?
I thought we threw him off the Rig!
There's high ground...
just beyond that thing.
He means the tree.
Yeah. Tree!
Leave him to me.
Say, anyone notice that bright light?
Encroaching gunfire?
Get out.
I can do this.
I know this machine.
He does. He's a Revhead.
You've got two left!
On him.
Don't breathe.
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
War Boy!
I'm gonna use the winch
around the tree thing!
Take this.
Let's get the engine plates.
You drive the Rig!
Hold up a flare!
I am holding a flare!
Closer!
It's right in front of your eyes!
Hut! Hut!
Blood Bag!
I am the scales of justice!
Conductor of the choir of death!
Sing, Brother Heckler.
Sing, Brother Koch!
Sing, brothers, sing! Sing!
Don't they know they're shooting at us?
Gun fever!
I never thought I'd do something
as shine as that.
How are the engines?
Very hot and real thirsty.
Hey. You need to take the War Rig
half a klick down the track.
What if you're not back
by the time the engines have cooled?
Well, you keep moving.
What do you suppose he's gonna do?
Retaliate first.
Let's go!
Are you hurt?
You're bleeding.
That's not his blood.
What is this?
It's Mother's Milk.
It's okay.
Sleep.
Get some rest.
How do you know this place even exists?
I was born there.
So why'd you leave?
I didn't.
I was taken as a child.
Stolen.
You done this before?
Many times.
Now that I drive a War Rig...
this is the best shot I'll ever have.
And them?
They're looking for hope.
What about you?
Redemption.
Hey, what's that?
I remember something like that.
Help me!
Help me, please!
Please!
That's bait.
Stay in the Rig.
Hurry! Please, hurry! They'll be back!
I am one of...
the Vuvalini!
Of the Many Mothers!
My Initiate Mother was K.T. Concannon!
I am the daughter of Mary Jabassa.
My clan was Swaddle Dog!
It's me.
There's something in the eyes.
Perhaps it is Jabassa's child.
This is our Furiosa.
How long has it been?
Seven thousand days.
Plus the ones I don't remember.
Furiosa.
What happened to your mother?
She died.
On the third day.
From where did you come?
The West. Citadel. Beyond the mountains.
The men.
Who are they?
They're reliable.
They helped us get here.
Where did you find such creatures?
So soft.
This one has all her teeth!
I can't wait for them to see it.
See?
See what?
Home.
The Green Place.
But if you came from the West...
you passed it.
The crows.
The creepy place with all the crows.
The soil.
We had to get out.
We had no water.
The water was filth.
It was poisoned. It was sour.
And then the crows came.
We couldn't grow anything.
Where are the others?
What others?
The Many Mothers.
We're the only ones left.
Look.
That's what you call a satellite.
Miss Giddy told us about those.
They used to bounce messages
across the Earth.
Shows.
Everyone in the old world had a show.
Do you think there's still...
somebody out there?
Sending shows?
Who knows?
Those are the Plains of Silence.
Stay right where you are, little Joe.
Kind of lost its novelty out here.
You having a baby?
Warlord Junior.
Gonna be so ugly.
It could be a girl.
You kill people with that, do you?
Killed everyone I ever met out here.
Headshots. All of them.
Snap. Right in the medulla.
Thought somehow you girls
were above that.
Come here.
Take a peek.
Seeds.
These are from home.
Heirlooms. The real thing.
I plant one every chance I get.
Where?
So far, nothing's took.
Earth's too sour.
So many different kinds.
Trees, flowers, fruit.
Back then, everyone had their fill.
Back then,
there was no need to snap anybody.
Can I talk to you?
I've talked with the others.
We're never gonna have a better chance
to make it across the salt.
If we leave the Rig here, and load
the motorcycles up with as much as we can...
we can maybe ride for 160 days.
One of those bikes is yours.
Fully loaded.
You're more than welcome
to come with us.
I'll make my own way.
You know, hope is a mistake.
If you can't fix what's broken,
you'll, uh....
You'll go insane.
Where are you, Max?
Where are you?
Help us. You promised to help us.
Come on, Pa! Let's go.
All right.
This is your way home.
We go back?
Back?
Yeah.
I thought you weren't insane anymore.
What are they saying?
He wants to go back from where they came.
The Citadel.
What's there to find at the Citadel?
Green.
And water.
There's a ridiculous amount of clear water.
And a lot of crops.
Got everything you need.
Long as you're not afraid of heights.
Where does the water come from?
He pumps it up from deep in the earth.
Calls it Aqua Cola and claims it for himself.
And because he owns it,
he owns all of us.
I don't like him already.
It'll take two weeks
to skirt the Wall of Mountains.
No.
I suggest we go back
the same way we came.
Through the canyon.
It's open. We know that. Right?
He brought all his war parties through.
So we take the War Rig and we charge it
right through the middle of them.
We can decouple the tanker...
at the pass.
Shut it off behind us.
And how exactly do we take the Citadel?
Assuming we're still alive by then.
If we can block the pass,
it'll be easy.
All that's left are his War Pups
and War Boys too sick to fight.
And we'll be with Nux.
He's a War Boy.
He'll be bringing us home.
Bringing back what's stolen, as he's meant to.
Yeah.
It feels like hope.
I like this plan.
We can start again.
Just like the old days!
Look.
It'll be a hard day.
But I guarantee you
that a 160 days' ride that way...
there's nothing but salt.
At least that way, you know,
we might be able to...
together...
come across some kind of redemption.
War Rig!
That's the War Rig!
That's them.
Why are they going back?
Do they wish to surrender?
They are heading for the canyon.
They're going back to the Citadel!
They know it's undefended!
Bollocks!
Roll up!
Go!
What are you doing?
Praying.
To who?
Anyone that's listening.
Here we go, girls!
That's mine!
He'll try to get in front of us.
Spike our wheels.
Don't blow my engine.
Gonna nudge him.
Just a little.
You filth! You traitored him!
Yeah!
Go.
Gotta back off.
Engine one is gone.
Two's about to blow.
Right.
Are you a Black Thumb?
All right. Engine one. Now.
You and me. Fifth wheel.
We'll unhook the tanker.
One man, one bullet.
I cannot see.
Maadi! Maadi!
I can't see.
Hey!
Harpoons and plows!
They're hauling us back!
Leave three bolts. Three.
Hey, you!
Are you okay?
I think she's hurt.
Hey!
No!
Hey.
Stay with me.
Hey! Are you there?
You finish that! I'll finish her!
Valhalla!
Engine one's good.
For now.
She's hurt! She's hurt...
real bad!
You hear that?
We're gonna see two airborne V8s.
I'm gonna need you to drive.
I'll get him out of our way.
Rictus!
Take me!
Cheedo!
What are you doing?
Good girl.
Come here.
Big Boy!
Here! Here!
Remember me?
He's dead!
He's dead.
When you're across safe,
I'll jam the throttle and follow you.
Come on!
Hurry! We're nearly at the pass.
Witness me.
Rictus!
Why is she making that noise?
She's pumping air into her chest cavity.
She's collapsing her lungs...
one breath at a time.
I know.
I am so sorry.
I know. I know.
Hold it there.
All right.
Put that on there. Press it in. Hey.
Hey.
Home.
No, no, no. No, no, no.
She's exsanguinated.
Drained all her blood.
Well....
Hold these.
We need that.
Needle.
Come on.
Take this.
Keep her awake.
Furiosa.
Okay, that's not retracting.
There we go.
All right, hold it up. Hold it up.
All right.
Sorry.
There you go. Okay. There you go.
Max.
My name is Max.
Yeah.
That's my name.
Brake!
Reveal yourself.
He's got something.
It's Immortan Joe.
The Immortan Joe is dead!
Furiosa!
She's back.
Let them up! Let them up!
Let them up!
Come on, let's do it!
Let them up. Come on.
Come on.
[English US]