Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Dust welcomes you to
a special viewing experience.
We thank you for joining us
to explore the depths
of the unknown in a dark,
isolated, and quiet place...
the ocean.
It goes largely unexplored,
and yet holds so much.
A different life exists
beneath its undulating surface.
You may have sensed its edges,
ventured only
to a shallow depth,
but science is our most curious
passenger, and it seeks more.
This is "Sea Fever."
Oh, thank you!
Aw, nice to meet you!
Good to see you.
Did you get some cake?
Not joining in?
I don't do joining in.
Look, this parasite
isn't hadal.
It's in totally
the wrong place.
No, you are in totally
the wrong place!
What time are you supposed
to be on board?
3:00? But this is important,
Professor.
And your doctorate isn't?
You wouldn't fail me
for not going?
I would have no choice.
Off you go.
But I-I know my strengths,
I'm a good observer,
I'm good at seeing patterns.
You are an excellent scientist.
That's not in question.
I need my own space,
I can't do other people.
This environment is much more
in the form of...
Siobhan! There's some
birthday cake over here.
Do you have any friends
in this department?
- But I...
- Get going!
Get your hands dirty,
make a few friends.
As I was starting
to think you weren't coming!
Sorry.
Skipper would have my guts
for garters.
That's a horrible thought!
There she is!
Niamh Cinn-Oir!
She's here!
.Okay...
Trick is, don't think,
just jump.
Go on, give her a hand.
Siobhan,
this is my auntie Ciara.
You're the scientist, I hear.
She's a charmer!
Have I ever let you down?
Apart from the times
I let you down, I mean.
We'll need a miracle.
Want to meet our student?
Ah, here she is at last.
I am Gerard the skipper,
this is Freya, the real boss.
She's a Viking.
Keeps us all afloat.
Siobhan, is it?
Gerard?
Don't forget to talk to Omid.
Johnny.
You're getting worried
about this.
It's our water,
it's important.
So when's the heir
to the throne arriving?
- Three weeks.
- Oh, yeah?
Then I'm definitely gonna start
looking for something else.
So your job
is up for grabs, huh?
Take it easy now, I said
I'm gonna start looking.
Yeah, you're always
saying that.
Alright, lads?
- Good to go?
- Yeah.
Just, uh,
checked over his work,
made some corrections.
Now listen,
- we owe you money.
- Aw, great.
You'll get your last share
on top of this share.
- What?
- Soon as we get back,
you have my word.
Sound okay?
Eh...
Skip, you know,
I have the baby coming.
I know, I know.
You'll get your shares.
Are we good to go?
- Yeah.
- Alright!
I'll make it up to ya!
We need a big
fucking haul this time.
So, what's your work?
Well, um...
I identify and extrapolate
patterns
from variations in deep sea
faunal behavior.
Then I generate algorithms
and computer simulations
to predict
ecological outcomes.
I meant what is your work
while you're on board?
I need to photograph your
catch, look for anomalies.
Won't be hard.
We get all sorts.
And, um,
I need to do a short dive.
Like under water?
Do you dive?
- Fishermen don't swim.
- Why not?
'Cause it's better
to go fast.
Nobody wants to drown slow.
Uh. Sudi!
You haven't met Siobhan.
Fucking hell, man!
Well she's pleased
to meet you too, mate.
Does the skipper
know about this?
He does now!
- A redhead.
- We've already spent her fee.
I know, but we can't
afford any bad luck.
So you think the color
of my hair is bad luck?
Oh, well there's two
schools of thought on that.
I can't change what I am.
I know, I know, but um...
Maybe just...?
Not such a bad idea.
Anchors away.
Alright then.
Pick a bunk!
- Why only four bunks?
- Oh, shift work.
Three people sleep
and three people work.
- How long's a shift?
- You get about 2 hours sleep.
What? Sleep loss
effects cognition.
- Oh, talk to me!
- You get emotional outbursts.
I barely know
who I am by the end.
Even psychosis?
Sea fever.
Happens.
Eejit, come on.
You're not on shift.
Protect us, oh, Lord, from
all the perils of the deep.
My Christ who filled the nets
of his disciples
deliver us
safely back to harbor.
Amen.
Make your last calls,
we'll be out of coverage
in a few minutes.
Fisheries are in.
Look at that.
Yes. Yes. Yes!
Our water filtration system.
You spend years at sea
and always have fresh water.
- It's magic.
- Magic?
- Where'd you go to school?
- Same place as she did!
Our doctoral student, Siobhan.
How many filters? z
Eh, three.
Ascending gauges.
- Ionizer?
- There.
- You designed this?
- Yes.
- Yeah, I did.
- It's brilliant.
Why don't you
have a better job?
Don't be fooled by her
winning personality,
- she can be quite blunt.
- No, I...
I just mean for such
a talented engineer,
it's a low status job.
Yeah, well you know, I...
I have been waiting for
the right opportunity I guess.
Hey, don't touch that!
- Ooh!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Yeah, sure?
- She needs a place to work.
- Not in here, I'm sorry.
- Too dangerous.
- I'm not hurt.
I'm afraid I might be.
I don't mind
you working there.
It's not always quiet, but...
Oh, it's great, thank you.
Are you cold?
Mother of Jesus, a redhead.
Take that thing off ya.
You're here now,
we better get used to ya.
Niamh Cinn-Oir
to Coast Guard. Over.
Freya, did you pick
up my e-mail?
Coordinates are for
the exclusion zone. Over.
Fuck!
Bang on top of our fish!
Okay. We'll steam through
the exclusion zone. Over.
No, not allowed.
Whales and calves in the area.
Over.
Roger that. Over and out.
Good luck out there.
Coast Guard out.
There goes our catch.
We'll get the hassars.
Oh, you don't want it? Okay.
Um...
Are ya hungry?
No! No, no, no, no. I'm fine.
I'll just, um...
I'll, uh...
Turn it off!
You out here every night?
Oh, come look, come!
It's a bioluminescent
phytoplankton.
It's one of the stories
of Niamh Cinn-Oir.
She was so sad about
losing her lover Oisin,
she gave herself to the sea.
Drowned herself?
No.
No. She is immortal.
That's her hair,
lights up the sea.
Thanks.
Wow!
Out here?
Whales on starboard,
lads.
What?
- Oh, yeah, look!
- Yeah, I can see!
There's two of them.
- Can you see it?
- Yeah, yeah, I see it!
And I think there's a calf.
Look there's another one,
just behind.
Can you not see them?
No, I can, it's, um...
It's just that whales aren't
usually around fishing lanes.
They don't like the noise.
Something's wrong.
Don't start that.
Whales are a good omen.
Whales are a very good omen.
Another shoal dead ahead,
less than a mile.
It's a big one.
Freya?
What?
That shoal's moving
pretty fast.
- You alright?
- Oh, Jesus Christ!
Jesus, what did we hit?!
Omid, what's the damage
down there?
Omid? Omid?
Yeah, uh, can you send down
the student?
Siobhan?
Hey, something's changing
the texture of the wood.
We letting in?
No, no, we're okay.
Go get the small gauge
timber plugs. Now.
Come on, fast, now!
Tell me you know what that is?
It's like we're caught
on something!
Niamh Cinn-Oir to Coast Guard,
come in.
come in?
You took us into
the exclusion zone.
What is that?
Chemical spill, maybe?
- What's happening?
- I don't know!
- Are we sinking?
- What?
- Siobhan, Jesus Christ!
- Are we sinking?
- We are not sinking.
You're a fucking eejit,
do you know that?
Christ knows what we're tangled up in.
It could be anything!
Good Jesus...
Is this what's
stopping us moving?
Yeah, something's getting
through the hole.
Christ!
What is that?
Could be a species
of barnacle.
Do you have your scuba gear
on board?
I do.
And you have to do
a dive anyway.
- Yes.
- So you could do your dive
and take off
the barnacles for us.
But that could be anything!
It's what you're here for,
anomalies, no?
Here, listen.
I've got you, yeah?
It's a gutting knife.
Just do your best.
I'm never going back down
there again!
- What?
- What happened?
Describe
what they looked like.
- What?
- It's...
It's... It's one animal.
It's one huge animal.
Wait, what,
as well as the barnacles?
No, i-i-it's not barnacles,
it's, um...
It's connective tissue.
- Connected to what?
- Like tendrils,
like, like a lot of tendrils.
Water's cloudy, she doesn't
know what she saw.
Freya...
A squid!
Bet you
it's some kind of squid.
It's more like some kind
of cnidarian, but, um...
It could be a squid.
But if it's a squid,
it's bigger,
it's bigger than anything
on record...
- It's... It's huge!
- Giant squid!
- You want the winch?
- Oh, yeah!
- All hands on deck, come on!
- No...!
Please!
- We need to call for help.
- We'll be fine.
Squid can't hold their own
bodyweight in shallow water.
We lift it even a bit,
it'll have to loosen
its grip on the boat.
That's how we get free.
Johnny, winch her up.
Keep it going.
Gerard.
Let go of the winch.
Oh, fuck... Oh, fuck!
Right, someone hit the brake!
- Get the fucking brake!
- Ow!
Fuck! Ow!
Sorry, sorry...
Sorry. Take it easy.
Easy, easy now!
- There's another boat!
- What?
That way!
Bastards.
You're unbelievable.
We'd have
to split the profits.
They might have
a better winch.
And a radio.
Gerard can't row over there
on his own.
I'm not getting in beside that thing.
No way.
It's a bad idea. Let's just
wait for the Coast Guard.
Come on!
Big commercial boat over there,
they'll be able to help us.
I'll go.
- I'll go as well.
- No.
Ger... Three of us.
Hello?
Anyone aboard?
Fine mesh trawling.
Desperation makes you
do things.
Hello?
They smashed the radio.
Why would they do that?
I don't understand.
Shh, listen.
I can't hear anything.
That's what I mean.
We should just go.
Hello?
Johnny, go on.
Come on, Siobhan.
Hello?
Jesus Christ...!
Fucking hell.
Must have gone mad.
Oh my God...!
Oh...! Fuck...
- Sea fever.
- What?
No sleep. One fella loses it.
Spreads like wildfire.
That might explain the
suicide, but the eyes?
Might've been the birds.
Listen, say nothing
about this.
- Nothing at all?
- Nothing at all!
How will we get home now?
Omid?
Hey, how'd it go?
They have a winch?
Ah, they've
their own problems.
No help at all.
We wanna show you guys
something.
That thing let us go,
we're free!
Didn't I tell you
we'd be fine? Ha!
Animals don't trap
something and just let it go.
Maybe it got injured when
we tried winching it up?
Could have secreted something
defensive, I suppose.
- Sounds plausible.
- Or venom.
And we're immune.
Or a digestive substance.
And the boat's inedible.
Large mass heading
this way, lads.
Or it's coming back for us.
Freya, we've no catch.
And if that thing
grabs onto us?
We'll net it before
it gets near us.
We know now.
God, it's a risk.
Have I ever let you down?
Huh?
Listen, if you want, we can...
we can steam home right now.
But if we do that,
we'll lose the boat.
We'll lose the boat.
- Shoot the net.
- Yeah!
Yes!
We're on a roll!
Woo!
So, what'll you do with
your shares?
- Parts for the new bike.
- Ah, Omid's old rust bucket?
Hey, come on,
it's a good bike.
Hey! It's not a bike.
It's a love machine.
What's her name? Alice...?
- Alison O'Reilly.
- O'Reilly!
Alison O'Reilly.
We're hitting the highway.
Just need a new sump.
Sump. Every girl's dream.
Oh God... Fuck.
You okay?
No, actually,
I'm bloody knackered.
Is it always like this?
No. Sometimes it's scary.
Things happen at sea.
Yeah, but things
like that other boat?
Coast Guard'll deal with it.
And listen, I've seen worse.
You've seen worse?!
Look.
Can I give you some advice?
Listen, we're here.
We're safe so just...
Let it go.
For a minute.
Rest.
What would I do instead?
Are you making a pass at me?
No.
'Cause I've had people make
passes at me before!
- Yeah, I'm sure you have...
- No, I mean...
What I mean is...
It would be okay if you were.
Best catch we've
had in months.
Bad luck's streak's
finally over.
Yeah, it was about
fuckin' time!
- Hey, hey, guys.
- Oh, bollocks!
- Watch your head, man!
- Hey, is there no free towel?
You already took a shower.
Look at you, man!
Slime on me,
that shit is everywhere.
Johnny, your auntie said
you're on kitchen duty tonight.
Yep. Sounds about right.
Hey, you guys okay?
Hey, come on, sit down.
- Omid.
- Yeah?
Are you ready for the
responsibilities of fatherhood?
You look hot.
Thank you. I was going to
say the same about you
but you got there first, so.
I mean you might
have a fever.
Nah, I just had a shower.
Yeah, for fucking
half an hour!
You smell that guys?
You smell something?
Oh, it's the shit from...
Excuse me, excuse me!
Have you looked in the mirror lately?
There's this black thing
on your face!
Everyone, everyone.
Redhead or not,
best student we've ever had,
- am I right?
- Hear hear!
- Nerves of steel!
- Yeah, she is.
Yeah, as long as she's not
trying to find the winch brake!
Sure, you were worse.
We had to teach you
how to eat spaghetti.
No, spaghetti is stupid and you know
it, okay? You know...!
Hey, who was it that nearly
- destroyed the engine, huh?
- No, I'm going...!
Let his rope fall
around the propeller.
Rope around the prop.
It was bad.
- It jammed. Killed the engine.
- Hey, at least I make a good
ship's engineer one day,
right?
Anyway, here's to the best
student we've ever had.
Cheers to that.
You okay?
Come on, let's go for a swim.
Wait, what did he say?
He said he wants to go
for a swim.
- Well fucking stop him!
- Jesus Christ.
Where's he going?
- Johnny, stop.
- I'm fine! I'm fine!
Leave me alone. I'm fine.
We're going in,
we're going...
We're going for a dip.
Look, 30 seconds, it's just
a dip basically isn't it?
- Don't!
- Come on.
- We're going swimming.
- You're not going in.
- No, no, no!
I'm grand!
Take it easy now, come on.
Lunatic. There's a
motherfucking monster out there!
What kind of eejit goes diving
off a trawler to impress a girl?
- What the fuck, Johnny?
- What are you on?
Nothing.
If you brought drugs
onto this boat...!
I didn't and I wouldn't.
- Did you give him something?
- No, he's hot.
I think his hand might be
infected.
- Let me see your hand.
- I'm fine. I'm fine.
I need to sleep is all.
Johnny, would you like me
to look at your eye?
What?
- I think I saw something.
- Let me see.
Come here now.
Can't see anything.
Bloody hell, you nearly
had me going there.
Jumping at shadows.
Relax the head. You...!
Get some sleep.
Right, well, I'm just
gonna... over here...
Fuck!
Jesus, Johnny!
Take it easy!
- Let me see, let me see!
- What is it?
You're okay, take it easy!
I-I... I can't...
I can't see.
Johnny!
No! Noooo!
Oh, God!
- Shhh!
- Help! Let me up, please.
What is it?
Johnny, Johnny, shh!
You're okay.
Oh, my God!
Oh, Johnny!
Oh, Jesus!
Move back.
Don't touch anything!
Move back! Move back!
Come with me, right now.
Come with me.
I love you.
Listen, um, they were
parasites in his eyes.
- What? How?
- They went into the water.
I'll go turn it off.
Where's Sudi?
Sudi! Turn off the shower!
- Fuck off!
- We're not fucking joking!
Turn off the shower now!
Sudi! Sudi?!
Sudi, please! Listen to
me! Open up the door!
Oi! Bastards!
Now Sudi!
Turn off the shower!
Turn off the water!
Hey, listen to me.
Open the door.
Open the door right now!
Sudi! Sudi, please,
listen to me!
Alright. You're alright.
You're alright.
It's okay.
Come here.
Okay...
Shhh... Johnny...
I have ya.
You're okay.
Straight through the steel.
Jesus Christ!
Oh! Agh!
Fuck!
It's okay, it's the filter.
Where does this flow to?
Nothing can get in or out now.
Except through the lid.
We need to open it.
Are you crazy?
If I can identify them
it'll be helpful.
Put these on.
Hey, please, careful.
What are they?
I don't know.
But I think...
Maybe they're larvae.
We need to get those things
out of the tank.
So empty it!
What are you waiting for?
Fuck's sake!
- How? We've no pump.
- Exactly.
- And we need fresh water.
- We'll boil it.
And what do we do
for drinking water?
Fish them out of the tank!
They bit through the steel
water filters.
They'll probably be dead
in the next few hours.
Alright, alright.
We're all grieving.
What did you say?
If I'm right...
they're saltwater larvae
in fresh water.
They'll be dead
in the next few hours.
Right. She's... She's right.
Did Johnny get
bitten like this?
No! No, he didn't.
Let's just focus, huh?
What did they say,
on the other trawler, huh?
Nothing.
They're all dead.
It was sea fever.
They took their own lives.
Alright?
Now...
We need to keep our
heads clear, yeah?
Omid,
get Sudi to bed.
And um...
You and Siobhan
will check the water
- in two hours time.
- Okay, good.
We'll say a prayer
for Johnny at dawn.
Let's all get some rest now.
You take first watch.
- What?
- She's fine, Ciara.
Okay?
Yeah? There you go.
She doesn't even
know my name, man.
Alison O'Reilly.
I haven't even spoken to her.
What are you talking about?
I was just waiting
for the right time.
The right time?
And then you...
You're alright.
I just can't believe...
It's time.
- Are they dead?
- I think we're good.
Yeah?
Not long til they eat
through the tank.
They're weaker. I think
there's fewer of them.
We'll just have to wait.
He who puts himself
in my hands,
though he were dead,
yet shall he live,
and whosoever trusts in me,
shall never die.
Se do bheatha, a Mhuire,
ata lan de ghrasta,
Ta an Tiarna leat.
Is beannaithe thu idir mna,
Agus is beannaithe toradh
do bhroinne; Iosa.
Have you something
to help you sleep?
Listen, burn the engine
if you have to.
Just get us home fast.
What are you doing?
You're still bleeding.
Everything is fuzzy.
Is this what happened
to Johnny?
No, he had a fever.
You've just lost a lot of blood,
so it's affecting your eyes.
You mean I'm going blind?
- Yes, might be temporary.
- Might be?!
Listen, I'm sorry,
I can't help you right now.
I need to focus.
Fucking redhead.
None of this would have
happened without you!
You're confusing
coincidence and cause.
My hair and this happening
is coincidence, but...
It was the slime!
The thing that attached
itself to the boat.
It mistook our boat
for an animal.
Probably a whale.
And when it latched onto us,
i-it produced a progenerative
substance.
And Johnny had an open wound.
So, uh, the slime got into
Johnny's blood
and there were eggs
in the slime?
Not were... are.
They're still alive.
Sudi's got open wounds,
we've all got cuts.
We're all vulnerable to get
infected just like Johnny.
If we're not already.
Any good news?
We need to kill those eggs
right now.
- Fucking how?!
- I don't know!
I study behavior patterns
in a lab.
You kill things.
Give it here.
Here.
This won't work.
So what do we do?
Can you make a UV light?
Why?
Other hadopelagic species,
their spawn,
you can kill it with intense
UV light.
You have a smart phone?
I learnt this in a bar
at Tishreen University.
Where's that?
Syria.
You met your wife there?
- How'd you guess?
- I don't guess.
I study behavior patterns.
You were touching
your wedding ring.
- It's tiny.
- Just do the test.
We can figure out how to
make it bigger later.
It's too tiny anyway.
How long til we're home?
I'd say about 30 hours.
We'll all be infected
by then.
Omid.
I have another stupid idea.
Are you mad?
Disinfectant doesn't
kill the eggs,
UV light doesn't either.
So you want
to electrocute the Niamh?
Yes.
We use the ARC welder.
Sea water as a conductor and
run a current around the boat.
Come on, as long as we're
all wearing rubber boots
there's no risk to us.
And you'll take
responsibility?
Hold on!
What about the motors?
The engine?
I'll try and insulate them.
Oh, you'll try!
And what about
the risk of fire?
Are you insane?
No!
Fucking no!
You can't risk my boat!
It's a risk either way.
You risk the boat or
you risk our bodies.
Fuck's sake!
This is insane!
Pretty sure Omid'll
sort it out.
Okay. Do it.
Omid?
Are we on fire?
No, it's just... just surface
electrics.
Did it work?
- I think so.
- Thank you.
We can go ashore once
we know we're clear.
We are clear.
It took Johnny at most
36 hours from exposure.
So obviously we have
to wait 36 hours
- from when we destroyed the eggs.
- We're making port tonight.
Freya, if any of us
is infected, then...
Then we'll be better off
in hospital.
Freya, wait!
You know Christmas Island?
- What?
- It has the world's
biggest population of red
crabs, it used to.
- So?
- So, a few yellow ants arrived
and they blinded the red crabs.
Just a few ants.
Now there aren't
anymore red crabs.
Do you see what I mean?
Yeah. The crabs should
have gone to hospital.
This is what I do.
- Faunal behavior in spe...
- Yes, in a lab.
But this is the real world,
with real people!
And in the real world,
if we go ashore
and one of us is a carrier,
then those things will spread,
really fast.
Sudi is my responsibility.
And he's bleeding
to death in there.
We can't just
think about Sudi.
I am not losing
one more crew member.
Omid, I need your help.
Yeah, what?
When we get to port, help me
keep everyone on the boat.
That'll never happen.
First sniff of land, we'll
all be off and gone.
Just until we know
we're not infected!
Have you seen Sudi?
Have you seen him?
He needs help now.
Where do you live?
Galway.
200,000 people
in Galway, right?
- Yeah, it's about that.
- Yeah. We can't say
we're so important that it's
worth risking the lives
of 200,000 people.
Yeah, maybe.
But who are you to say that
this poor kid has to die
so someone else
can avoid the risk?
Are my eyes open or closed?
Open.
Shh, you'll be alright.
Shhhh.
You'll be alright.
Sudi?
God is our hope and strength.
God is our hope.
We will not fear,
though we be in
the midst of the sea,
God is with us,
and we will not be removed.
Amen.
We need to quarantine
ourselves now.
Maybe you've no life,
but we have responsibilities.
Listen.
Omid's wife is pregnant.
We need to get them home.
If they want, they can
get themselves to hospital.
- Now seriously, fuck off!
- But you don't understand!
Did you not hear me?!
Huh?!
You okay?
How's Ger?
Not infected if that's
what you mean.
Aw, no.
Oh, no, no, no!
Fucking... Fuck...
Come here.
Why has the engine stopped?
Tell them.
I disabled the boat.
What?
- Agh!
- Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
What the fuck's
your problem?!
- We've all got cuts.
- But we killed the eggs!
We could have got infected
before that!
- So we get help!
- There is no help!
So...
You want us to sit
out here and die?
I want us to stay on the boat
until we're sure
that none of us is infected.
- Your bloody 36 hours.
- It's not mine.
It's your family's.
It's your husband's,
it's your baby's.
Blame me if you want.
We have to take action.
We have to
take responsibility.
Listen,
I know I caused this.
Don't.
I let you do it.
We could have gone back home
when that thing let us go,
but I kept us here.
It's not all on you.
God knows who's next.
You saw something in Johnny's
eye before he died, didn't you?
Yes.
I want you to test all of us.
I don't see anything.
- Want me to do you?
- Mm-hmm.
- I don't see anything.
- Look again. It's really faint.
No, I don't see anything.
Do me.
Not you. Omid.
Come on. Just let her do it.
I think you're fine.
Okay. My turn.
I don't see anything.
- Okay.
- She scuppered us for nothing.
You haven't done me.
I don't need to do you.
What?
Give me that thing.
Fuck!
- Oh, God, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- It's alright, it's okay.
It's okay, it's alright.
- It's alright.
- No. No. Listen.
- That place.
- Gerard, no.
We weren't meant to be there.
- What?
- What do you mean?
I changed course and I didn't
tell anyone.
I took us into
an exclusion zone.
That's why we saw the whales.
Come on.
- You changed course?
- I changed course.
So do the Coast Guards
know where we are?
Did you know about this?
Hmm?
- Ger, come on.
- Ciara...
- I think you should go.
- Come on.
- You fucking bastard!
- Stop it!
- Johnny's dead!
- We're family!
Oh, yeah?
I had my own family.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Little blondie head on her.
Little Niamh.
I thought nothing this bad
could ever happen to us again.
I don't mind going.
'Cause I'll see her again.
Wait!
O, a chuisle...
Freya.
Freya!
Are you taking a rowboat?
Double your chances
of being found.
Just stop, please! Listen!
You're three fucking days
from shore in that thing!
- Call it quarantine.
- Come on, Freya, please?
There's white spirit and
stuff in the forepeak.
Make a flare. There's also
the inflatable boat.
Hey, please.
What about the
Niamh Cinn-Oir, huh?
Do what you want with it.
It's just a boat.
That's inside the boat.
Freshwater?
They're alive in freshwater!
- That sounded like one animal.
- Yeah.
So they ate each other like
tadpoles. One animal wins.
How... How do we get
the one animal out?
We stun it.
We run electricity
through the tank.
No, that doesn't...
Only works in salt water.
Okay. Okay, okay.
It's a parasitic life cycle.
It's hadopelagic.
But pressure is not a problem.
Yeah?
It's um...
It's hadopelagic.
Yeah, you said that.
So it likes the deep cold.
We heat the tank.
- What, will that kill it?
- No.
- But it will slow it down.
- Enough for us to kill it?
Enough for us to safely
return it to the wild.
Oh, wait, what like,
are you insane?
- It's a rare animal.
- Yeah, so are we.
- We're intelligent.
- T-That's debatable.
This is our duty!
It's in the wrong place.
It only wants to survive.
Just like us.
So you risk dying
to protect something
that wants to kill you?
How do we heat the tank?
Let's find out.
Now?
Omid!
Agh!
Right through the hull.
Get the food.
- We're sinking?
- We're sinking.
White spirit.
- We can make a beacon.
- With what?
Okay, you ready?
No.
Let's go.
Omid! Hurry!
I-I can't swim!
Omid!
Grab my hand!
Grab my hand! Pull!
No! No! Oh!
Omid! Oh, carry on...!
Thank you!
Thank you...
Siobhan.
Siobhan. Look! Look!
I'm infected.
No. Let me see.
Okay. We'll just...
Okay, we'll, listen...
We'll just...
We'll just tourniquet
this area, okay?
Stop the poison
from spreading.
Okay. Yeah?
Hey. You might be immune.
Okay? We're going home.
- Okay.
- Omid...
Omid...
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org