Oh, how's it morning already?
[vomits]
[rumbling]
Jarrod.
Jarrod,
wake up.
It's OK.
What is that?
I don't know.
[woman] Hey!
Stay here.
- What's wrong?
- He's gone!
[woman] Jarrod! Jarrod!
Jarrod!
[air hostess]
We'll be starting beverage service.
For a complete list of choices,
please see the last page
of your in-flight magazine.
I can't decide.
Elaine, you pick the last one.
J- Rock? T-Money?
Oh, no, we were...
we were ahead of our time.
We're bad.
- You haven't changed a bit.
- Neither's Terry.
You'll see. He's the real deal.
Can't wait.
[♪ Royce Da 5'9": Where My Money At]
Well, you should have thought about that
before you shot the piece of shit.
- What are you doing here so early?
- [woman] It’s a beautiful day.
Don't I know it.
Ray called again
about the robot sequence.
Tell him to handle it.
No business on my birthday.
- Hey.
- God, does she always have to be here?
She's working. Show biz, baby.
Mm. You're all sweaty.
[slap]
Hey. You feelin' all right?
- Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
- OK.
Here. Let me get that for you.
There you go.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
That's my fine hero.
Let's go.
[Jarrod laughs]
Yeah, that's us.
[Jarrod] Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
- You better not get used to this.
- Who, me?
[woman] Penthouse.
- All right. Come on.
- Going down.
How's the second most talented guy
I know?
- I don't know. How are you?
- I’m good.
Happy birthday!
- Oh, my God!
- You must be Elaine. Welcome.
[whirring]
This is amazing.
Automatic living at its finest.
My own personal place in the clouds.
[Elaine] The view is incredible.
Let me ask you a question.
You keeping my boy in line?
Don't answer that.
- Hey.
- It’s a full-time job.
Well, whatever he's paying you,
I'll double it.
Well, it looks like
you've got your hands full already.
I like her, yeah.
That's your room right there.
- You guys wanna hit the pool?
- Absolutely.
Baby! Pool time!
[rap music]
- Baby, get me a cosmo.
- Absolutely. Hold this.
Hey, bar's this way.
- You really did it, man.
- Yeah.
Just like everybody
knew you would, but...
- Hey, guys.
- Hello.
Couldn't have done it without you.
- What'd I do, decorate the walls?
- They do look nice.
- Mm-hm.
Happy birthday, Terry.
Yeah. Happy birthday to me.
I can't thank you enough for this, man.
I’m the one who should be
getting you a gift.
I got some ideas on that. Come on.
I see everyone's getting along famously.
- Baby.
- Yeah.
Where's my cosmo?
Oh, my bad.
Denise, get me a drink.
- Anyone else?
- No.
Hey, this definitely beats
Brooklyn in December.
- I kind of like having four seasons.
- We got one of those down the block.
Tomorrow we gonna hit the high seas.
I’m gonna take y'all out
on my Sunseeker.
67 footer. My starter yacht.
Homeland Security.
They must be here because they know
tonight's party's gonna be a bomb!
Baby... Oh!
[slow rap music]
[all] Cheers!
[woman] Happy birthday, Terry.
- Hey, man.
- Nice job, man.
- How's it going, man?
- Happy birthday, Terry.
There's somebody
I want you to meet. Ray!
Hold on.
What's up, man? Happy birthday, man.
Thank you.
How's the robot fight coming along?
Dude, it sucks. But the director
loves it, so, you know...
- Hey, is this the boy wonder?
- [Terry] Yeah.
And his lovely lady, yeah. Right.
- Hey, it's good to meet you, man.
- Good to meet you too.
I’m psyched
you're gonna join the crew.
- Huh?
- Did you find a place to live yet?
I’m telling you,
Venice is where it's at.
- We'll keep that in mind. Thank you.
- I live there, so I’ll show you around.
I have to go use the little girls' room.
Excuse me.
No... Babe...
- Elaine!
- Bro, she's smokin'.
- Nice job, dude.
- Excellent.
- Way to go.
- What's he talking about?
What's going on, ladies?
- I’m sorry.
- What was that about? Jeez...
OK, look,
cat's obviously out of the bag.
I've been thinking...
You should move to LA.
What am I gonna do out here?
I’m barely surviving back home.
- I could use you.
- I don't need any charity, all right?
OK, fine. I need you.
I don't know
anything about effects, man.
- That's bullshit. Come on, man.
- That's not bullshit.
You got the eye and you know it.
The computer is just a tool.
I just... I don't know, OK?
I never saw myself out here.
Where do you see yourself? You got
a five-year plan I don't know about?
Look, it's not about the money, OK?
It’s always about the money.
What about Elaine?
I can't handle everything.
You gotta take care of that yourself.
[Denise] Terry,
there's a call for you upstairs.
You think about it.
[rock music]
Elaine.
Come on. We're supposed to be
having fun. What's the problem?
Just forget it, all right?
Look, Terry sprung this whole
California thing on me today, all right?
- I had no idea. I didn't come out...
- I’m late.
What do you mean, late?
Late.
Oh. Sorry.
- Since when?
- I don't know.
I’ve been feeling sick all week,
so I took a test and...
Why didn't you tell me?
I wanted to.
Believe me, I just...
I didn't wanna ruin your trip.
You didn't...
Shit.
Is that all you have to say?
What do you want me to say?
- I don't think I’m ready for this.
- You're not ready, Jarrod?
- What about me?
- It’s not...
Hey, will you get...
Is that what we have to look forward to?
Lainey...
[Ray] Right! Ready!
Here we go, here we go!
I think we've got a live one! Whoo!
We have a wiener!
That's what I’m talking about! Whoo!
Oh, yeah! Go!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Oh, my God! No!
- God, no!
- No!
No!
- Oh, my God!
- [doorbell rings]
Pardon me, ma'am, but we've received
a few noise complaints.
From who?
- The building's half empty.
- I understand that.
But the other half is trying to sleep.
So if you don't mind, just...
- Fine.
- OK.
- Another one for the books.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, well, well.
- Mm-mm. I call the couch.
- Oh, come on.
- There's plenty of room for both of us.
- I like my space.
Whoa. All right.
Beggars can't be choosers.
- [bleeps]
- Good night.
[rumbling]
Earthquake?
Probably just a tremor.
What the...?
Turn off the lights.
Ray.
What are you doing?
What is that?
Ray!
Stay here.
- What's wrong?
- He's gone!
Jarrod, no.
Jarrod, no!
- Jarrod. Jarrod. No!
- [Terry] What the hell's going on?
Terry, please! Terry, help!
What's with you, man?
Jarrod.
Oh, my God. Jarrod, Jarrod.
- Jarrod!
- Please. What's happening?
- Jarrod?
- [Elaine] Jarrod. Oh, God. Oh, my God.
Jarrod. What is that?
What's wrong with him?
Jarrod. Oh, my God.
- Where's Ray? Where's Ray?
- Terry, no.
- No, no.
- Jarrod?
- Where is he?
- He's gone.
- What do you mean?
- He's gone!
- Did he fall? Did he jump?
- No! I don't know, I don't know.
[Elaine] Please. Please. Please.
He went outside, to the light.
And then he... he just disappeared.
- [gasps for breath]
- Baby.
Terry, please.
Jarrod, look at me.
What did you see, huh? What did you see?
Careful.
Jarrod, what happened?
I don't know.
I was being pulled...
...towards this light.
[crashing]
Hey, open the blinds.
- No.
- Open the blinds!
- No!
- God!
- There's something down there.
- What?
Jarrod, check this out.
I don't see anything.
- There are people on the roof.
- [Elaine] What are they doing?
I don't know.
- We should check it out.
- You don't know what's out there.
- Yeah, OK.
- All right.
I’m calling the police.
- I’ll try and get some pictures.
- You can't go out there.
I can't let him go out there alone.
It just keeps ringing.
A gun? Really?
Just check the news
and find out what the hell is going on.
- Terry...
- We'll be right back.
- Jarrod.
- Look at me.
Let's go.
Hurry back.
Stairs are this way.
[clanging]
- [barking]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Dammit, Walt.
- What's going on?
- We're going to check it out.
- What are you doing with a gun?
Get back in your apartment. Go.
And keep it down.
Hey...
You sure about this?
There's been nothing new since 4 am.
Denise, check the TV.
It’s calm.
Dammit, Jarrod.
- You didn't tell me to hold it open.
- I thought it was common sense.
I’m sorry.
- [crashing]
- Get down.
What now?
Let's get a better look.
[ringing tone]
Hi, this is Jackie.
Please leave a message.
- [bleeps]
- Mom, it's me. Something's happened...
Pick up. Please just...
Call me back as soon as you get this.
- [engaged tone]
- [crashing outside]
[crashing]
Holy shit.
I can't see it.
Is that what I think it is?
Oh, my God.
- Just run.
- What is it?
- Run!
- Go!
Come on, pull! Back up! Back up!
Come on! Come on!
- [Terry yells]
- Come on! Come on!
Come on!
[Jarrod] Elaine, no!
Move. Move!
Come on. It’s OK.
Baby, are you OK?
I feel like I’m on fire.
Come on, baby. I’m here.
Give me the... Give it to me.
It'll pass in a few minutes. Look at me.
Look at me.
You looked too.
How?
Oh, my God.
All those people.
- What do they want with them?
- I’m not looking to find out.
[woman] God, I can't believe this.
I mean, how?
[Jarrod] Once you look at the light...
...it grabs hold and it's like...
It controls you.
I mean, who wouldn't wanna look
at something so beautiful?
It’s kind of brilliant, actually.
Enough of this shit. I got an idea.
- Where are you going?
- Walt.
- [Jarrod] What for?
- I worry about him.
- [Denise] Terry...
- Everything's under control.
Are you OK?
- Yeah, it's nothing.
- Let me see.
I said it's nothing.
All right.
[whispers] Walt.
Yo, Walt.
Walt.
Are you in here?
[barking]
[growling]
- What the hell are you doing?
- Hiding.
I saw the people in the sky
like a goddamn rapture.
Come on. We're taking your car and we're
getting the hell out of here. Let's go.
- I’m not going out there.
- [whirring]
- [barking]
- Get down. Get down.
- Shh!
- Shut the dog up. Shut the dog up.
Shh!
- No!
- No! No! Walt!
[Walt screams]
[gunshots]
Did you hear that?
What's up? Talk to me.
We're getting on my boat
and getting out of here.
- What happened?
- They took Walt.
They got Walt?
What are you talking about?
This one was different. It came in
the building and it just snatched him.
- Then we should just go.
- Hold on a sec.
Am I the only one who saw those photos?
That's all happening right outside,
right now. They're everywhere.
No, they're not everywhere.
They're not over the water.
That's right.
Yeah, well, it didn't take 'em very long
to find you on the roof.
We can drive there in two minutes.
You have no idea
what they're capable of.
Elaine, I know you're scared, OK?
We're all scared.
But I’m not burying my head in the sand
and hoping this goes away.
- I’m not saying that.
- Just take it easy, man.
- There's nothing easy about this!
- I understand...
They're in the fucking building!
- Terry...
- It’s the timer.
[Denise] Oh, my God.
Shit.
[Terry] All right. Go, go, go! Move!
Shh.
- You're disgusting.
- What the hell's the matter with you?
- We'll talk about that later.
- Yeah, we will talk about that.
- Still wanna stay?
- I don't want any of this.
But it didn't see us or hear us.
- So if we stay here and stay quiet...
- [Terry] For how long?
They're taking people out there,
plain and simple.
The further we get out of the city,
the better off we are.
- He's right.
- Jarrod.
If we get to the boat, we have a chance.
- Yeah, but we don't...
- We have to...
We have to try.
Get your stuff.
Pack food and water. Let's do this.
[Terry] Let's go.
All right, come on.
Look, the sooner I get there,
the sooner the boat's ready to go.
Right here.
- Hey.
- Come on, let's go.
- What...
- What are you doing?
Driving. I know the way.
Why don't you take your slut?
Candice.
Get in the car.
Terry, I’m sorry.
- Hurry up.
- What do you think I’m doing?
- Hey, slow down.
- No.
Just stop.
- You need any help?
- No, just go. We're fine.
- Yeah, but maybe he can help us.
- Enough, all right? I said we're fine.
Terry!
Terry, get up!
- Terry! Terry!
- My God! Terry!
I got you!
Jarrod, get your ass back in here now!
Drive! Drive now!
- [man] What are you doing?
- [woman] Get in the car.
[Jarrod] Come on! Come on!
Open! Oh, shit!
- [Elaine] Come on!
- Open! God!
Come on.
[Candice] Open, you piece of shit!
Back up! Back up! Back up! Go!
[screams] Oh, my God!
Help me! Help me!
[screams]
- Help me!
- [Elaine] This way!
Candice, where's the key?
Candice, the key! Turn the key!
[woman] Oh, my God.
- You all right?
- I’m OK.
- Hm.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
- Miss, we have to go.
No, he...
He's alive!
God!
Help me!
[screaming]
Come on, let's go!
Oh, my God!
Go! Go!
Make for the back door.
Run!
Move!
Go!
Don't stop!
Open the door!
- Get it open!
- Back up.
Open it!
Come on!
- Where are we going?
- All the way to the top.
- The safest place I could think of.
- We were just up there.
[crashing]
You wanna stay down here with that,
be my guest. Go on. Let's go.
Come on, quickly, quickly, quickly.
[Elaine] Jarrod...
I should have held onto him.
Hey. Come help me with this.
It’s better than nothing, right?
Yeah, if you say so.
What are you doing, huh?
Like it or not, this is happening.
You gotta be strong.
Is everybody OK?
Are you hurt?
- No.
- I’m OK.
- What now?
- We stay here. We keep watch.
- And we pray that someone comes.
- He's right.
Someone's gonna come.
This can't go on forever.
Right?
- Elaine...
- It’s best if we stay together.
I can't. The smoke.
Given the circumstances,
I think a smoke is more than reasonable.
Candice...
I’m pregnant, all right?
And I just thought that...
...between all the stress...
It’s OK.
I never even got to tell my mom.
Come on, boss.
Let's let the girls get some sleep.
You and I will keep watch.
Both of us?
They try that light stuff,
we got each other's back.
I hate LA.
I haven't seen a soul all night.
Maybe the worst is over.
Maybe not.
What do you think
those things really are?
I don't know.
Does it even matter?
It just doesn't seems real.
Well, it is real.
You better wake up.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- The city's a vacant lot.
We need to survive.
There's not gonna be many of us left.
[clattering]
[crashing]
Let me see.
Somebody's fighting back.
- What are you doing?
- I wanna see what's out there.
[Elaine] Oh, my God.
Turn that off. It’s too bright.
- No.
- We can't risk it.
[Elaine] Oh, my God.
Did you sleep at all?
- Is it getting worse?
- What?
The marks on your skin.
When I looked in that light,
I couldn't stand for ten minutes.
Who knows what it did to us?
To our bodies.
You remember that first moment when you
saw it, when it completely took over?
Somehow you... you still felt...
...powerful.
I still do.
Why don't you take a seat, relax?
All right, I’ll bite. What's your plan,
boss? I know you're dying to tell me.
Nothing to say?
We're sitting on the marina
for Christ's sakes.
I’ve noticed that.
There are hundreds of boats
right across the street.
We've been through all this.
Remind us
how that worked out last time.
We go quietly this time.
And search every boat
till we find the key?
- If we have to.
- Great plan, Jarrod.
I can't believe you'd even suggest that
after what happened.
You make it sound like it was my fault.
I was practically begging,
but you wouldn't listen.
And you think Terry
would have listened to me?
All right.
Let's say we make it
out of the building,
across the marina, down the dock,
we even find the boat and everything.
Then what?
- Then we get the hell out of Dodge.
- Where to? Carolina? Down the coast?
- Anywhere is better than here.
- How do you know?
We're here. We're alive.
[jet engines]
What was that?
What do you see?
Hallelujah.
[man] Come on, come on, come on.
[yells]
- [crashing]
- Everybody get down!
[Elaine] Jarrod?
Lainey?
It worked.
I don't believe it. Is it over?
It worked. It worked.
- Do you mind?
- [man] By all means, boss.
[Elaine] Do you think there are
more planes where they came from?
Yes. Now they know what to do,
they'll be sending help in no time.
What?
- What is it?
- They're not dead.
They're just really, really pissed off.
Something is happening.
We got to cover these windows.
Come help me with this.
- Get back over here!
- Look, I’ll find something.
Here.
Jarrod, what are you doing?
The only thing we can do.
What's this really about, huh?
Those things are coming for us.
You think I haven't noticed
that mess under your shirt?
We stay here and hold up for good.
I agree.
Now he gets to decide everything?
We have no water, no power.
Yeah, but you saw what's out there.
Yeah, and I would rather make a run
for it than stay in a 20-storey target.
Between those things and the radiation,
we are dead up here.
[helicopter overhead]
Go! Go!
Go, go, go, go! Cover the flanks!
Look.
- Get off me!
- What do you think you're doing?
- We have to let 'em know we're here.
- We'll let everything know.
You've been saying to wait for help.
Well, help is here.
Does that look like a rescue chopper
to you? Don't you get it? We're at war.
Where are they going?
Those choppers are coming back for them.
We have to go. Come on.
We'll get to the roof.
They'll pick us up.
What if they don't come back?
Look what happened to those planes.
- What good is a helicopter?
- We have to take a chance.
A chance? They just nuked the city.
And you wanna wave hello?
Seriously, you need to back off.
We have to...
[Candice] Oh, shit.
You just gonna stand there?
What happens when the rest of the blinds
fall? We don't have enough bed sheets.
- Come on.
- How can you be so sure?
Let's just go.
You're in no condition
to decide anything.
Who knows what side you're on?
I’m warning you...
[Elaine] Stop it, both of you!
Look at his face. He's sick.
- Don't make me hurt you.
- Oh, don't worry.
I am not leaving here without my family.
And there is nothing
that you can do to stop us.
Lainey, you have to trust me.
It’s me.
It’s still... me.
I know.
We have to go.
He's gonna get her killed.
Come on.
All right, let's go.
You see anything?
Right there.
- [Jarrod] Hey! Help!
- Help us!
- Don't move!
- Don't shoot!
No, no, wait! We need help! Please!
Oh, no, no!
No!
- Hey! Yeah!
- Hey!
Hey!
[indistinct voice over radio]
[man] Copy that.
I’ve got a visual right now.
Mayday! Mayday!
- [man] Hang on! We're going down!
- No!
[Elaine] Oh, my God.
Come on.
Get off of me! Get off!
Go! Go! Go!
The scaffolding. It’s the only way down.
Come on, come on.
[gas hisses]
Jarrod!
- Jarrod!
- Elaine, run!
Vaya con dios, you son of a bitch!
Help me! Help me!
Help me!
Jarrod.
Look at me.
Look at me, Jarrod.
Gotta get up. Come on.
Come on. It’s our only chance.
Lainey, please. You have to go.
I’m not going anywhere without you.
[groaning]
[gasps]
Jarrod.
[rapid heartbeat]
My baby!
[screams]
[screaming]
[rapid heartbeat]
Jarrod.