(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
As the Earth continues to heat up
and devastating droughts
and famine plague the population,
science is looking for a new planet
on which human life can thrive.
And it finds that in year 2063.
ASTROPHYSICIST: The blue
indicates water.
The red is oxygen.
This is our best chance
to find a habitable planet.
One we can colonize
and so ensure the
survival of our species.
With the deteriorating
situation here on Earth,
it's essential we send
a scouting mission
as soon as possible.
The voyage there will
take 86 years.
So, the crew will
reproduce onboard the ship,
and their grandchildren will be
the ones who reach the planet.
TECHNICIAN: Nobel
laureate in physics,
say hello to
MIT bio-engineer.
(BABIES WAILING)
Our first challenge was finding
30 qualified crew members
able to cope with the stress
of prolonged confinement.
That and the knowledge that
they won't be coming back.
Our solution,
breed and raise our own crew.
Train them in isolation
so they won't miss Earth.
Then the next
step is to assess
when they'll be
ready to go.
The younger they are,
the longer we can conserve resources
and extend the timeline
of the mission.
But they will be on
the ship alone.
And while I have every
confidence in our education
and management system,
I'm most concerned
that they
be able to combat
the dangers
they may face
along the way.
Some we're just
beginning to understand.
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(DOOR WHIRRING, HISSES)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Decontamination complete.
- Richard!
- CHILD 1: Richard!
(CHILDREN SHOUTING EXCITEDLY)
(RICHARD EXCLAIMS
AND CHUCKLES)
CHILD 2: Richard.
(COMPUTERS BEEPING)
How would you
solve that one?
(COMPUTER TRILLING)
Good.
RICHARD: Sleep well,
Christopher.
Sleep well, Sela.
Sleep well, Zac.
I'm scared.
Of what?
I don't know.
There's nothing
to be scared of.
You're safe.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
RICHARD: I want
to go with them.
It's a one-way
trip, Richard.
There is no
coming back.
You'll die up there.
I'll die down
here eventually.
Seems the same
to me.
The whole reason
we're raising them this way
is for their
mental health.
So they don't miss wide open
spaces, sunlight, people.
Now you,
on the other hand,
are going to have a hard
time dealing with...
I wouldn't miss a thing.
It's not part
of the plan.
I know, I know,
but think of it like this.
You'll be able
to launch sooner
if I go with them.
Four years instead
of seven.
Someone should be
there to raise them.
To protect them.
You know I'm right.
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
LAUNCH DIRECTOR ON RADIO:
T-minus 15 seconds.
We are go for launch.
13, 12, 11...
Switch from GLC to OBC.
...6, 5...
- (SHIP LAUNCHES)
- Go main engines.
...3, 2, 1...
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- All right.
- MALE TECHNICIAN: You good?
Yeah.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Hatch closing.
TEN YEARS LATER
(METAL CREAKING)
(BELL TOLLS)
(DOORS SLIDING)
MALE AUTOMATED VOICE:
You are the link between past
and future generations
and have been entrusted with
the survival of our species.
You will have children
onboard the ship,
and your grandchildren will be
the ones to reach the planet.
FEMALE AUTOMATED VOICE:
On-ship reproduction will occur
via artificial fertilization
and incubation
during each generation's 24th year
in order to maximize resources.
(TRAY CLATTERS)
(SCANNER BEEPS AND TRILLS)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING
OVER HEADPHONES)
(VOLUME INCREASES)
SELA: Well, we're the first generation,
so we won't ever see the planet.
We'll never know
what they discover.
That's true.
Our lives
are unimportant.
No, your life,
my life is as
important as anyone's.
Here or on Earth.
Let me show
you something.
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
Not supposed to let
anyone see these.
That is my father
and his parents.
My grandparents.
I never knew them,
but I know they lived an honest life.
You know, they took care of their
family, they provided for the future.
That's all any
of us can do.
(METAL CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
(ALARM BEEPING)
What's up?
There's a toxin in
the irrigation water.
Well, replace the filter
and test it again.
It's coming from us,
it's in our urine.
Yeah, it's from
something we've eaten.
Are we eating
something toxic?
Maybe toxic for a plant
that relies solely on water,
but you're stronger
than that.
What is it?
What's the chemical?
I don't know.
Just change that filter.
CHRISTOPHER: Hey.
What do you
make of this?
It's an ingredient
in something we eat.
Why would that
be unavailable?
(SOFTLY) Let's go.
How'd you get
past the firewall?
CHRISTOPHER: By connecting
directly to the processor.
It's the same way I got
into the design plans.
(CHRISTOPHER SIGHS)
(BEEPING)
- Hmm.
- Try "Nutrition."
It's not there.
Is it some kind
of vitamin?
Maybe
medication.
CHRISTOPHER: Here we go.
"...the active ingredient
in daily beverage A.02."
"Combine with blue
alkaline syrup
"to counter
stomach irritation."
Blue.
It's the blue.
"...effect is enhanced when
consuming it with food."
What effect?
I thought it was just
an enzyme for digestion.
"...personality
becomes dull and docile..."
"...eliminates sexual
desire and sensation..."
"...decreased pleasure
response..."
Decreased pleasure
response?
I want
increased pleasure.
(SCOFFS)
They're drugging us.
ZAC: So they
can control us.
Pacify us.
They don't want us
to reproduce naturally.
to have sexual relations.
So we don't feel what
that feels like.
And so we don't
overpopulate the ship.
To conserve food.
I don't care.
I'm not
drinking it.
So, Richard
lied to you.
The mission lies.
What else aren't
they telling us?
Well, Christopher found
a hidden compartment.
In the
ship's plans.
Where is it?
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
In Pod-23.
Unmarked behind
a wall.
What's inside?
I don't know yet.
KAI: Don't tell Richard
you went off the blue.
He's going to force
them back on it anyway.
Yeah, maybe. By then,
we'll know what it feels like.
What does it
feel like?
Has anything changed
since you stopped?
- Yes, but...
- Where's my pleasure?
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
- (GROANS SOFTLY)
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Here.
Ow.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
(GRUNTS AND CHUCKLES)
A little jolt.
- A bolt.
- A bite.
You know that's a
waste of electricity.
Go away.
RICHARD: So...
What have you been thinking
about since our last session?
Nothing.
Come on,
nothing?
Well, I guess
I was wondering
why do you lie to us?
What do you think
I lied about?
Well, I found
out that...
What?
There's an unmarked
compartment.
Pod-23.
Well, mission withholds certain
information for various reasons.
You know,
even from me.
It's not quite lying,
but I get what you mean.
How'd you find it?
I just did.
What's inside?
I don't know.
I don't know. It must be
for the third generation.
But why's it hidden?
Aren't you curious?
I am...
It's probably
reserved for them.
It's for
your grandchildren.
That's a profound thought.
I mean, you're going
to have children,
and you're going
to have grandchildren.
What do you
think about that?
RICHARD: Yeah,
they're normal kids.
They're sensitive
and smart
which means they know when I'm
not telling them the truth.
And that's my point.
I want to be honest with
them about everything.
Otherwise, they'll lose
faith in me.
So...
I'm going to need a quick
response from you on this.
That's all for now.
(SCANNER TRILLING)
(HEARTBEAT THUDS)
(HEARTBEAT FADING)
Sela?
SELA: What?
You look different.
I'm the same.
No, you're not.
Neither am I.
What are you
talking about?
I don't know.
You've changed.
Everything about you.
Yeah, I've grown up.
That's exactly what I
want to talk to you about.
You have, but you're not
feeling what I'm feeling.
No grabbing, Zac.
I wasn't grabbing.
RICHARD: Easy with the hands.
You know the rules.
(SLOW SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CHRISTOPHER GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Yeah!
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTH WHOOPING AND LAUGHING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(METAL CREAKING)
(CREAKING STOPS)
C'mon.
ZAC: I hate
those noises.
Anything?
No.
So what's causing
the sounds?
Richard says
it's the cooling
and contracting of the
ship when we power down.
I don't think the
temperature differential
is enough to affect
the structure that way.
Plus, Richard's a liar.
(CHRISTOPHER CHUCKLES)
So what is it?
You think it's something
on the outside, don't you?
If there's life on the
planet, why not out here?
What else can
explain those sounds?
(SNIFFS)
What is it?
Sage.
Plant that grows
in warm climates.
(SNIFFS)
- Pine needles.
- (SNIFFS)
- It's beautiful.
- Hmm.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION
CONTINUES)
(SELA READING
INDISTINCTLY)
You see that?
He can touch her.
But I can't.
RICHARD: We've lost
contact with Earth
because overnight there was a
malfunction in the LCT transmitter.
I'll have to go
exterior to fix it.
Zac will come with me.
And the rest of you
know your roles.
CREW MEMBER 1:
Right here.
- CREW MEMBER 2: Here you go.
- Thanks.
This sensor goes on your
wrist and it attaches here,
but it's tricky because
it can come loose,
so just
make sure...
Make sure you
pull the cuff over
the inner sleeve
so that it...
(SELA GASPS)
(SELA GRUNTING)
Hey! Hey! Hey!
(GRUNTS)
What's happening here?
Zac, what are you doing?
You're going to lose food rations if
you don't tell me what's going on.
You okay?
SELA: I'm fine.
Zac!
Zac.
Phoebe, have you
seen Zac?
No. But I heard
what he did.
Has he done anything
like that before?
I don't know,
but he stopped taking the blue.
Are you sure?
I saw him
pour it out.
RICHARD: Christopher.
You seen Zac?
You heard
what he did?
Oh, you think
that's okay?
No.
Good, I'm glad
to hear it.
He's not taking
the blue. Are you?
Why would I?
It's a drug.
You're drugging us.
Mission made a decision
to administer medication
to help with
impulse control.
(SCOFFS)
To prevent exactly this kind
of thing from happening.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
It's the only way to
deal with living like this.
We didn't ask
to be here.
Nobody chooses what
they're born into.
But you have to find
a way to live your life.
You gotta
decide what kind of person
you want to be.
You gotta try to be good.
Why?
We're just gonna
die in the end,
so why can't we do
what we want?
What's the difference
whether we're good or not?
- There's a big difference.
- Well, I don't see it.
Are we still
doing the repair?
Yeah.
C'mon.
All right,
put this on.
- Why?
- You're coming with me.
(SCOFFS) I don't
want to go.
Look, I get that
you're angry,
but I need your
help with this.
And the sooner
we fix it,
the sooner you can
voice your objections
to mission control.
I'll back you up.
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(COMPUTER CHIMING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Depressurization in progress.
(AIR HISSING)
90%.
80%.
RICHARD: Kai, you ready
in the systems room?
Yes.
Control room set.
SELA ON COMMS: Med Bay
on 1 with vital signs.
(DOOR OPENS)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Depressurization complete.
Opening hatch.
Who's with him?
KAI: Christopher.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
RICHARD ON COMMS:
We're at junction box 1.
Starting the repair.
Shut down power
to LCT 1 transmitter.
Copy that.
LCT 1 shutting down.
(DEVICE CLICKS)
RICHARD: Opening
junction box 1.
KAI ON COMMS: Copy that.
RICHARD: LCT 1 repair complete.
Going to LCT 2.
KAI: Copy that.
LCT 2 shut down.
(METAL CREAKING)
There it is.
It's just the ship.
Richard told us
what it is.
(THUDS)
Do you see anything?
Because there's
nothing there.
- (GRUNTS)
- (ALL WHIMPERING)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANING)
Richard!
ANDA: Richard!
Do you read me, Richard?
- CREW MEMBER 1: What happened?
- CREW MEMBER 2: I don't know.
- Switching to emergency power.
- (ALARM BLARING)
CREW MEMBER 3:
Check the breakers.
CREW MEMBER 4 ON COMMS: We have
a fire in the systems room.
(ALARM BLARING CONTINUES)
PHOEBE: Navigation errors.
CREW MEMBER: I don't know.
We're trying to check.
Negative. No effect.
Communications.
The whole system's down.
We're not transmitting or receiving.
SELA: No, keep the oxygen.
We're going to go again.
- (EKG BEEPING)
- (DEFIBRILLATOR BUZZES)
(FLATLINING)
(DEFIBRILLATOR BUZZES)
It's not working.
Are you pronouncing
him dead?
It says the chief medical
officer should note
the time of death.
(SELA BREATHES SHAKILY)
Okay.
14:35 ship time.
CHRISTOPHER:
I just don't understand.
What actually happened?
You didn't see it?
I was facing
the other way.
There was
that sound.
Creaking.
Just before
it happened.
Was anyone watching
the monitor?
Yes. We didn't
see anything.
I did.
CHRISTOPHER: And?
What'd you see?
It looked like...
Like a force
jumping into him.
What do you mean?
Like a meteoroid?
He means
something else.
Something alien.
- What?
- (FEMALE CREW MEMBER GASPS)
(SOBBING)
It's okay.
It's going
to be okay.
What's going
to happen to us?
We'll be okay.
Whatever it was,
it was on the outside.
We're safe
inside the ship.
But without
Richard...
We were going to be on our
own at some point anyway.
It just happened early.
If we keep it together,
we'll be all right.
(CREW MEMBERS MURMURING)
- (ALARM BUZZES)
- (ELECTRICITY POPS)
(SYSTEM POWERING UP)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
System restarting.
(BEEPING)
Did you get an image?
Everything
recorded is gone.
So we can't see
what happened?
EDWARD: The fire
in the systems room
destroyed the
surveillance archive.
(CREW MEMBERS MURMURING)
The program says we need to
choose a new chief officer.
I'll be
chief officer.
I'm head
engineer now,
it makes sense
that I be chief.
Well, what
about Sela?
She's head
medical officer.
I don't want
to be chief.
It says everyone
gets a vote.
We have an election.
(SCANNER TRILLING)
(SCANNER TRILLS, CHIMES)
PHOEBE: And the new
chief officer is...
Christopher.
(ALL CHEERING)
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
First thing we have to
do is repair the damage.
The LCS is down,
so we won't be hearing from
Earth until we fix it.
We're on our own now,
but we can work our
way out of this.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
CHRISTOPHER: We'll need
the entire crew
in the damaged area
working on the repairs.
The fire knocked out
most of the systems room.
We'll look at electrical
and communications first.
Pull out all the burned
equipment and replace it.
Then we'll work
on the surveillance system.
Try to get it up and running
so we can see what
really happened to Richard.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Okay.
PHOEBE: Edward said the fire
destroyed all the surveillance.
CHRISTOPHER: Yeah.
The connections
are burned.
But maybe the drives
are still intact.
(SNIFFS)
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
What are you
doing in here?
I'm supposed to destroy
his personal archive.
Why?
It's in
the program.
They don't want
us to see it.
Do I have to do it?
Yes. Of course.
SELA: That's Richard
when he was ten.
That's his sister.
That's his parents.
His parents...
We only have
genetic donors.
It's the same.
Is it?
We still get our
natures from them.
Why did he show
you all this?
He wanted someone
to talk to.
What else?
What do you mean?
We saw...
We saw him
touching you.
And we thought that
you and Richard...
I didn't do anything
with Richard.
We were just friends.
He showed me his things.
He would tell me about his life.
But why?
He felt
alone.
Day 1,240.
I'm not gonna be able
to keep up the count...
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
It's hard to explain.
On one hand, I...
I didn't feel like I had
anybody at home.
The kids
seemed like my only
relationship, so...
I didn't want to lose that.
And then,
on the other hand,
I believe
it's a noble mission,
in the great tradition
of exploration. You know...
What's out there?
Why are we here?
Where are we going?
I won't get to
see the answer,
but maybe I can move us
a little closer to it.
But I think the real
reason why I came is,
I wanted to make
sure they're okay.
And I want to protect them.
Protect us from what?
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(LOUD THUD)
Everything okay?
Yes.
How's it going with
the surveillance?
Not sure yet.
Where is everyone?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey, what's going on?
Why isn't everyone
at their jobs?
We have to repair
the damage.
We have to secure
the ship.
What are you
doing in here?
Bit of an emergency.
That short circuit cut the
power to the refrigerators.
We're doing
everything we can
to get them back before
we lose any food.
Oh.
Somebody should
have told you.
- Can you fix it?
- Yes.
But there's a bunch
of food we need to eat
before it goes
bad and...
I was thinking we
could have a party.
A feast.
What for?
To celebrate our
new chief officer.
(CHUCKLES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
AND LAUGHTER)
(SCANNER TRILLING)
Don't drink the blue.
Don't drink it.
Why not?
Zac says
we shouldn't.
It's medication
to control us.
(SCREAMING)
(LAUGHS)
- MAN ON VIDEO: Richard.
- Yeah.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(RICHARD TALKING
INDISTINCTLY ON VIDEO)
(JULIE GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CREW MEMBERS CHEERING)
(EERIE, DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXHALES)
JULIE: Kai!
(JULIE GIGGLES)
(LAUGHS)
(SHRIEKS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (SNAKE HISSES)
- (LION ROARS)
(ANIMAL SQUEALING)
(WOMAN MOANS)
- (GUNSHOT)
- (SOLDIER SCREAMS)
(GUNFIRE ON TV)
What are you doing?
Get out of here now.
(LOUDLY) Everyone go!
(GRUNTS)
Get out.
(BEEPING)
Just remember,
Richard isn't here
to protect you.
I don't need him
to protect me.
Is she all right?
She doesn't want me
to touch her.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
(EXHALES)
(KAI GRUNTING)
(BOTH PANTING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
ZAC: Sela?
You in there?
Looking
for Sela?
She's in the Med Bay.
I just saw her.
Hi.
Everything all right?
- Yeah.
- (KNOCKING AT DOOR)
ZAC: Sela?
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (DOOR OPENS)
SELA: Stop.
What are you doing?
What does it
look like?
Looks like you
got here fast.
Get out.
Wait.
- Whoa.
- You're just like him.
No, you don't
understand.
He was coming in
here to get you.
I was trying
to help you.
Why don't you help
the rest of the crew?
It's getting out of control.
You're the leader.
You should do
something about it.
ZAC: Why'd you do that?
What?
You knew I was going
to find Sela,
and you went
right to her.
You need to
leave her alone.
You think 'cause
you're chief officer,
- you can tell me what to do?
- No.
- Good.
- I'm telling you as a friend.
Stay away from her.
I'll do what I want.
(METAL CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
(LOUD THUDDING)
(BOTH PANTING)
(GRUNTS ANGRILY)
(GRUNTING)
JULIE: Kai!
What are you doing, Kai?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PETER WHIMPERING)
(KAI GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
AND LAUGHTER)
TAYO: What's up?
No, I'm good.
(CHUCKLES)
Tayo...
Tayo, get down from there.
Don't sit
on the table.
PHOEBE: That's right.
You're not supposed put your
feet where you're eating.
- Shut your face.
- (ALL LAUGH)
All right.
That's enough.
- Kai.
- What?
- (GRUNTS)
- (KAI SCREAMS)
CHRISTOPHER: No, no, no! Stop!
Stop!
(CREW MEMBERS CLAMORING)
(PETER GROWLING)
Let go!
- Let go!
- CREW MEMBER: Let it go.
- Let it go!
- CREW MEMBER: Come on!
- FEMALE CREW MEMBER: Let go!
- Stop!
(CHRISTOPHER GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Let's get them treated.
And then I want everyone
in the common room.
(ALL MURMURING)
There's no more fighting.
It has to stop.
It's not how we resolve
our conflicts.
Do you understand?
Also, some of us
aren't doing our work.
No one's
maintaining the ship.
Why should we if
no one else does?
CHRISTOPHER: Because
if you don't, who will?
It isn't fair.
We have to repair the damage
and safeguard the ship.
I want everyone
finishing those two jobs.
The ship
is secure.
We've done
our job.
Then everyone should
be in the systems room.
No. Now we're working
on the food supply.
This is more important.
More important
than food?
No, you're wrong
about that.
You haven't been working
on the food anyway.
You haven't been
doing anything.
No one has.
And if we don't,
the mission won't survive.
KAI: Who cares?
We won't make
it anyway.
But somebody will.
And it's our job
to support them.
To lay the groundwork.
For our grandchildren.
Who cares about them?
We'll be dead.
Listen, we're going to get that
whole section up and running,
and everyone's going
to work on it.
I don't want to work
in the systems room.
- Why not?
- I just don't.
He thinks the alien
is living in there.
What? That doesn't
make any sense.
It's on
the outside.
He says we brought it
inside with Richard.
Christopher
brought it in.
Now it's hiding in
the damaged area.
That's not true.
I, for one,
don't know if there is an alien.
Who cares what
you don't know?
If we repair
the damage,
we can watch the
surveillance video and see...
Shut your fat,
pus-filled face.
I've got
a right to talk.
You talk too much as it is,
you bloated, wheezing blister.
- (ALL CHUCKLE)
- Zac, she can talk.
You shut up, too.
Who are you?
Telling people what to do.
I'm chief officer.
Why should that make
any difference?
Because I was chosen.
It's in the program.
It's in the rules.
Who cares about
the rules?
Zac! Come on.
We're strong,
we can do what we want.
(FEMALE CREW MEMBERS GASP)
Stop it!
Both of you. Stop!
I'm not listening to
Christopher anymore.
He's chief officer.
You're not
a commander.
- You're not a leader.
- I'm trying to keep us on track.
Anyone who wants
to follow me can.
- I'll make more food.
- That's our food, too.
And I'll protect you
from the alien.
Especially if he's
inside the ship now.
You're just trying
to scare them.
Are you calling
me a liar?
Zac, why are you
doing this?
We need a new leader.
He doesn't know
how to feed you.
He can't protect you.
And I'm not going to
listen to him anymore.
Anyone who wants to be a
part of my group is welcome.
We'll have more food,
so we're strong...
Strong enough to fight
the alien, strong enough
to kill it.
Anyone who wants
can come with me.
(CREW MEMBERS MURMURING)
ANDA: What if Zac is right
about the alien?
CHRISTOPHER: If we can just
get that surveillance drive,
then we can see what
really happened.
You don't think it's living in
there, do you?
I don't know.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Where's Christopher?
I... I don't know.
ZAC: Who's in the
systems room?
No one.
You all stay here.
Don't let anyone
come in.
KAI: What do you think?
What's through there?
(THUDS)
(METAL RATTLES)
ZAC: What is that?
(METAL SCRAPING)
- Get behind it.
- KAI: Try to close the door.
(LOUD CRASH)
- (CREW MEMBERS SCREAMING)
- ZAC: Go! Go! Go!
Close it! Close it!
EDWARD: What was that?
What happened?
- What was it?
- (PANTING)
(METAL RATTLES)
The surveillance drive.
- There was really something in there?
- What was it?
- I don't know.
- Not Christopher?
- No.
- What did it look like?
It was dark.
We couldn't see.
Okay...
(BEEPS)
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
RICHARD: Start shutting down
the transmitter circuits now.
SELA: It's pretty damaged.
You can't
see anything.
- KAI ON VIDEO: Copy that.
- Let's try a different angle.
(STATIC)
I can clean this up.
It's not as bad as it looks.
(PANTING)
Everything all right?
No. (BREATHES SHAKILY)
What is it?
Zac and Kai were in the systems
room right after you left.
ALEX: They said they
saw the alien.
- They fought it.
- SELA: What?
It wasn't there
when I was inside.
And the room
looks destroyed.
There are pieces of the
surveillance unit everywhere.
The alien did that?
Or they did it
themselves.
It doesn't matter.
We have all the
data right here.
But if it was
Zac and Kai,
they did it
for a reason.
To destroy the record.
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
ZAC: Who's with him?
Christopher.
ZAC: It was supposed
to be me.
KAI: Richard looked for you.
RICHARD: All right,
go into LCT 2.
Copy that.
Shutting down LCT 2.
You should give him a
little zap for his trouble.
ZAC: For my trouble...
A little spark.
- A sting?
- A stab.
You could do it.
- I know I could.
- KAI: He'd be surprised.
- He'd be shocked.
- (CHUCKLES)
(METAL CREAKING ON VIDEO)
You hear that?
Yeah, it's just
the ship.
SELA: He knew it
was the ship all along.
This one?
Yes.
KAI: He didn't feel it.
Nothing.
ZAC: Is he touching the cable?
KAI: Yes. But his gloves
are insulated.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Murder...
(POWERING DOWN)
Don't mention
this to anyone.
Not until we decide what to do.
SELA: How could Zac do that?
Why have they
all gone crazy?
Maybe they haven't.
Maybe this is what
they're really like.
We have our rules
that keep us in line,
but deep down,
maybe this is our true nature.
No.
It can't be.
I'm not like that.
You're not like that.
You're not.
And the crew will be on our
side once they know the truth.
I'm not so sure.
They don't care anymore.
Sometimes,
I don't either.
You care.
I know you do.
I should leave
you alone.
No.
I want you to stay.
(SOFT MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
ZAC: Time to
wake up, Sela.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Go away!
(ZAC CHUCKLES)
ZAC: Oh, we're not going away.
We're coming in.
(KNOCKING IN SEQUENCE)
(DOOR BEEPS)
- (KAI AND ZAC CHUCKLE)
- What are you doing?
What are
you doing?
I see I'm breaking up a
nice little thing here.
What do you want?
KAI: We're having
a celebration.
Right now?
Yes.
Sela's invited.
I guess you
are, too.
Come eat.
If you want.
Don't if you don't.
- (DOOR BEEPS)
- (SELA SIGHS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (PHOEBE GASPS)
- (LAUGHTER)
- You okay?
- Mmm-hmm.
Get some food.
You must be hungry.
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
All right, listen up,
everybody.
(CHATTER STOPS)
Now I know we've had some
disagreements in the past.
We're going to put
all that behind us.
I'm chief officer now,
and that's the way
it's gonna be.
From now on,
we'll do the work,
but we'll do it when we
want and how we want.
We'll make the rules,
and anyone who breaks them
will have to answer to me.
The alien's somewhere
in the ship.
We'll fight it again if we have
to, and we'll defeat it.
You'll be safe now
'cause I'll protect you.
- (COMPUTER BEEPS)
- Hey, what are you doing?
Sit down.
Richard was killed
at 13:58:37.
- KAI: Copy that.
- He was electrocuted.
KAI: Shutting down LCT 1.
ZAC: Who's with him?
KAI: Christopher.
ZAC: It was supposed to be me.
You should give him a
little zap for his trouble.
A little spark.
- ZAC: A sting?
- KAI: A stab.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- ZAC: This one?
- KAI: Yes.
He didn't feel it.
Is he touching
the cable?
Yes,
but his gloves are insulated.
- (ELECTRICITY BUZZES)
- (CREW MEMBERS GASP)
(CREW MEMBERS MURMURING)
- Zac killed Richard.
- (CREW MEMBERS MURMURING)
There is no alien.
Not out there, not in here.
There's only Zac.
He's been lying to you
the whole time.
But now you
know the truth.
You've seen it
with your own eyes.
Zac should go to his compartment
while we consult the program.
Then we'll decide
what to do.
It's true.
I did it.
I killed him.
But I did it for you.
I did it to protect you.
I did it because I saw
the alien in him.
The alien was in Richard,
and then Christopher
brought it inside.
That's not true.
(CHUCKLES)
ZAC: He shouldn't have.
He knew something was
wrong, but he did it anyway.
He brought the alien
into the ship.
Just watch the rest
of the video.
You'll see he's lying.
I killed Richard
to protect the crew,
but now the alien's inside
the ship somewhere.
We need to find out
where so we can stop it.
So we can kill it.
That's right.
We'll kill it.
ZAC: We'll take
back control.
We've been drugged and betrayed
and programmed by liars,
but we're not going to
follow the program anymore.
We can't escape this life,
but we won't just lay
down and give up.
We won't be afraid.
We won't be terrorized.
We'll fight back,
we'll find it!
There's nothing
to find.
Where is it now?
First,
it was inside Richard.
Now maybe it's hiding
in someone else.
One of you.
It could be you.
Or you.
(CREW MEMBERS CHATTING
INDISTINCTLY)
Or you.
We'll kill it.
Yes. We'll find it
and kill it.
- KAI: Kill it.
- JULIE: We have to find it.
- CREW MEMBER 1: It could be you.
- CREW MEMBER 2: Or you.
Or you.
Or him.
It's him.
- CREW MEMBERS: It's him!
- KAI: Him...
CREW MEMBERS: It's him!
It's him.
FEMALE CREW MEMBER: Him.
ALL: Get him!
(CREW MEMBERS CLAMORING)
(WHIMPERING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
- (ALL GRUNTING)
- (PETER GROANING)
Stop! Stop it!
(CREW MEMBERS GROWLING
AND GRUNTING)
(TENSE MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(SOBBING)
KAI: It's okay.
He had the alien
inside of him.
- I don't know.
- He did.
Don't worry.
Unless it's you
who has it inside.
No.
It's not me.
ZAC: Grab anything that can
be used as a weapon.
Scalpels, scissors,
anything sharp.
We have to arm
ourselves to fight.
We need something that
will make him back down.
Maybe we should
just give up.
We can't give up.
But there's nothing
we can do right now.
We accused him of murder.
He's not going to forget that.
We should join
his group.
I mean, that's all he
really wants anyway.
Maybe later
we can detain him.
ALEX: That's right.
When things calm down.
Eventually,
things will calm down and be okay.
Right now,
it is too dangerous.
We can't
stay separate.
There's no way
to fight him.
We don't have
any weapons.
(WHISPERS) Weapons.
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
You know where they are.
I do?
He said you did.
- Who did?
- Richard.
I was watching his video diary,
and he said you knew about the weapons.
(KEYPAD BEEPS)
(DOOR BUZZES)
(ALARM BLARING)
(JULIE CHUCKLES)
(ALARM STOPS)
- (EXHALES)
- (METAL RATTLES)
KAI: Chief.
Wake up.
(WEAPON WHIRRING)
(METAL SCRAPING)
- (LOUD RATTLING)
- (CREW MEMBER GRUNTS)
Was it the alien?
It was Christopher.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(KAI GRUNTING)
- (DOOR CREAKING)
- (KAI STRAINING)
(STRAINING)
(CREW MEMBERS MURMURING)
Must be for the third
generation.
When they reach
the planet.
No, these are for us.
(BELL TOLLS)
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
KAI: Chief.
They want
to join us.
Why should
we let you?
What else
can we do?
Is the alien
inside you?
There isn't an...
No. It's not.
Where're they hiding?
CHRISTOPHER: There they are.
PHOEBE: What are they holding?
Weapons.
(SCOFFS) And we just
have this.
That's not going
to help us.
Maybe it will.
We can say we want
to join his group.
Like Anda and Alex.
He'll never believe it.
All we need is a moment.
PHOEBE: Why?
So we can get close.
And then what?
And then I'll kill him.
Kill him?
Or he's going to kill us.
- No, he's not.
- They're moving.
(SYSTEM SHUTS DOWN)
They cut
the power.
- What do we do?
- We stay in here.
No.
We should go out there,
talk to them.
Tell them we don't want
to fight. And then...
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
They're here.
(ALL BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DOOR RATTLES)
Don't do anything.
- Don't resist.
- (CREW MEMBERS CLAMORING)
(TOYA AND JULIE GRUNTING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
Grab him.
Get off me!
CREW MEMBER: This way.
SELA: Wait!
Wait a minute!
(PANTING)
Get back, Sela!
Zac.
You can't stop us.
Let me talk to you.
What for?
Privately.
You can say whatever
you want to say right here.
I want to be with you.
ZAC: You want
to join my group,
or you want
to be with me?
Both.
I bet you do.
I do.
I'm glad you've finally
come to your senses.
I have.
I'll do anything
you want.
I'm sure you will.
Only problem...
...is I don't
want you to.
You want to be with me,
but I don't want
to be with you.
- (CREW MEMBERS LAUGH)
- (SCOFFS)
- Maybe someone else does.
- (LAUGHTER)
But not me.
PHOEBE: Have you
all gone crazy?
Have you?
Don't you see?
All of this is
against our nature.
This is not
who we are.
This is who
we are.
But we don't have
to act this way.
We can think.
We can decide
to be different.
Shut up,
you genetic defect.
We can decide
which is better.
- Shut up.
Let me speak!
We're trying to make sense
here, and you're not listening.
Shut up.
- Shut up.
- CREW MEMBERS: Shut up.
Shut up.
Which is better?
To have rules
and agree, or...
Or to run wild
and fight?
- To run wild.
- (LAUGHTER)
Do you want to listen to
reason and figure out a plan,
- or do you want to...
- (GUNSHOT)
- (BODY THUDS)
- (GASPS)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
You see?
You see what I can do?
(WEAPON CHARGING UP)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHIMPERS)
(BOTH GASP)
Which way?
You go that way.
I'll check down here.
This way.
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
Check in the vats.
Check in the refrigerators.
Tayo.
Check in there.
No way they
could fit.
Check all of them.
This one's been opened.
Move back, Tayo.
- What?
- Get out of the way.
(AIR HISSES)
Zac, that's
for our food.
Go see if
we got them.
(SELA BREATHING HEAVILY)
- SELA: We should stay...
- (LASER FIRES)
Check the drawers,
try to find something.
(OPENING DRAWERS)
(WHIMPERS) Next to you,
in the cabinet.
(DOOR CREAKING)
- (GROANS)
- (LASER FIRES)
ZAC: They're in
the Med Bay.
ZAC: Hey!
You're okay.
Get into a space suit.
If we go out,
we'll never get back in.
(ZAC YELPS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Close hatch.
Close hatch.
Emergency oxygen released.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SELA AND ZACK YELPING)
Enter closing code.
Hatch closing.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Oxygen level 70%.
(SELA WHIMPERING)
Oxygen level 50%.
- (ZAC GRUNTS)
- (SCREAMS)
- Oxygen level 30%.
- No!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- (ZAC GRUNTS)
- (YELPS)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Pressurize now.
(SELA GRUNTING)
Hatch stopped.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BEEPING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Tayo.
Put your guns down.
Zac's gone.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
How do we make sure
it doesn't happen again?
So tomorrow we go.
And as we begin our journey,
I think about the world
we are leaving behind.
And how I've seen it
at its best and its worst
and how
we'll have our own bad times.
I mean, they're coming.
There is nothing I can do about it.
But I also know that
you will prevail.
And our best will live on.
That we are worth saving.
(SCANNER TRILLS, CHIMES)
CREW MEMBER: And the new Chief is...
Sela.
We are voting
on everything now.
Trying to reach consensus.
It's not easy, but it's how
we want to move forward.
And we've decided
to not go back on the blue.
We feel that it is the
best course of action.
That we can do better.
(SOFT, HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
CREW MEMBER: Hey, Chief,
we just started those updates.
Still been
having headaches?
SELA: She just kicked.
(BABY CRYING)
(BABY FUSSING)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(UPLIFTING MUSIC PLAYING)
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull