[dramatic music]
[dramatic music continues]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
[audience shouting]
[announcer] Let's
welcome Mr. Bruce Lee
from Jan Fan
Kung Fu Studio.
[audience clapping]
[thumping]
[grunts]
- [Bruce grunts]
- [Hartman groans]
[tranquil music]
[thwacking]
[light buzzing]
[doctor] Mr. Ip.
Your x-ray result shows
that your tumor is malignant.
Even though it is still
at an early stage,
the cancer cells
are spreading rapidly
for it to be controlled
by standard medication.
Nowadays, hospitals
offer chemotherapy.
It can control cancer cells.
You should think about it.
First, you must quit smoking.
Don't smoke anymore.
[somber music]
MRS. IP, CHEUNG WING-SING
[wooden dummy clonking]
THIRD FLOOR
[instructor] No.
Turn your stance more.
Rotate your torso.
- [aggressive grunting]
- [instructor] That's right.
[wooden dummy rattling]
Yeah!
No. Come on, man.
- That's not right.
- [instructor shouts] What?
- What are you doing?
- Whoa, chill, chill. Relax.
I'm just tryin' to share
my thoughts.
Does anybody know
what he's saying?
No.
No more shows for you.
- Relax, we're kung fu brothers.
- [instructor] Leave.
- It's fine.
- Just listen to me.
- Calm down, man. Easy, easy.
- I don't understand you.
- Just leave.
- Just listen to me!
- What's wrong with you?
- Are you nuts?
Do you want me to beat you up?
- Get lost!
- Don't push me.
- I said get lost!
- I said don't push me!
Here to challenge us?
Okay.
[tense music]
[both grunting]
[groans, exhales]
- [thumps]
- [grunts]
- [light tap]
- Hmm?
[groans]
- Master.
[Billy] Grandmaster!
Yes!
I'm so happy to see you! Woohoo!
- [student] Why is he so excited?
- [instructor] Huh?
[all gasping in surprise]
I'm a student of Bruce Lee.
My name's Billy.
I have something for you.
Sifu wants you to come to the
Karate tournament in the US
which takes place next month.
Here, this is a plane ticket
for you he prepared.
And this book, he wrote it.
He wants you to have it.
- Bruce.
- Bruce?
Bruce Lee?
He is good?
He's doin' fine.
He has a Kung Fu school
in Seattle.
And I'm from his newly
opened one in San Francisco.
Billy.
Tell Bruce...
maybe I have no time.
- Thank you.
- Oh.
[light tap]
Thank you.
What is going on?
[somber music]
[door creaks]
- Give this to Grandmaster.
- [instructor] Hey!
What is it?
[Ching]Give me back
my comic book.
[grunting]
[groaning]
Give it back.
[student groaning]
- [loud thwacking]
- [pained grunts]
Mr. Ip.
This is Ip Ching's
expulsion letter.
We can't keep him
in our school anymore.
Headmaster.
Can you give Ip Ching
one more chance?
I promise he will behave.
Please give him another chance.
Let him stay.
It's not his first time
getting into a fight.
[principal] Last time
was already his last chance.
Since he is so sportive,
it may be better for him
to study abroad.
It's not serious.
They're just minor cuts.
But be careful next time.
Thank you, doctor.
The nurse will patch you up.
Where is your family?
Doctor.
Master Ip.
[Ming] It has been a while.
I am Ming, Ms Luk's son.
Your kung fu studio used to be
on our rooftop.
- Oh.
- [laughs]
My mom sent me
to study in America
since I was too naughty.
[Ming] I just came back.
I work in this hospital now.
It's really something
to be abroad on your own.
[Ming] Not really.
Master Ip.
Ching is fine, don't worry.
- See you later.
- Thank you.
[hurried footsteps]
[mellow music]
[mellow music continues]
[doorbell buzzing]
Answer the door, Ching.
[buzzing continues]
- Master Ip.
- Hi, Bob. Please come in.
What's the matter?
America is so far away.
Why are you leaving so suddenly?
I am going to San Francisco
to look for a school for Ching.
Good idea. Mr. Ba also sent
his son there recently.
One can earn much more
after studying overseas..
- [Ip] Please take a seat.
- Okay.
- [Ip] Have some tea.
- Don't bother.
Ching.
- Greet your elder.
- He did, he nodded.
- [Ip] Have some tea.
- [Bob] Thank you.
- Bob.
- Yes?
Can you please come to check
on Ching while I'm away?
Not a problem.
While I'm in America,
I will phone home at 10:00 p.m.
Hong Kong time every day.
Okay.
[Ching] You don't have to call.
I won't answer it.
Don't worry.
I will be here on time
to make him answer the call.
Right, don't be too soft
on your son.
- You're spoiling him.
- No, I have to.
I want to send him abroad
so that he'll have
a chance to experience
- how it is to be independent.
- That's right.
[Ching] I won't go.
If you want to go,
go by yourself.
If you have something to say,
come here and say it, okay?
- [Ching sighs]
- [paper rustles]
There's no way
I'm going to America.
You can't make me.
I have told you many times.
I don't like studying at all.
I'm not cut out for it anyway.
What can you do
if you don't study?
I can teach martial arts.
I like kung fu.
Who'll let you teach
martial arts?
Why can't I?
Aren't you doing it yourself?
Why don't you tell your students
it's useless to learn
martial arts?
- Enough.
- If nobody learned martial arts,
you'd be starving already.
You don't practice
what you preach.
You always think that I'm wrong.
Someone took my comic book,
it's my fault.
He failed, it's my fault.
- I want to teach kung fu.
- Enough.
It's also my fault.
You are always right
and I am always wrong.
You are never supportive of me.
If Mom was still alive,
she would have...
Don't.
Get out.
Get out!
Shut up.
Hey.
He's still a kid.
Be patient with him.
Don't be angry.
[exhales]
[keys clanking]
Bob.
I'll leave it to you.
Please sit down.
[dramatic music]
[indistinct chatting]
[coughing]
[pilot] Ladies
and gentlemen,
we are approaching
San Francisco Airport
where the local time
is 11:15 a.m.
[plane roaring]
- [chiming]
- [indistinct chatting]
[woman] Passengers for flight
43EI to Miami
and stops at Atlanta
and Toronto.
The departure gate has
been changed to Gate 21...
Mr. Ip.
- Mr. Ip, it has been many years.
- Yes.
- Are you tired from the flight?
- I'm all right.
My car is outside. Let's go.
Let me carry this.
- Thank you.
- Let's go.
[engine starts]
[Gun] It has been nearly
eight years since we last met.
[Ip] That's about right.
- Hey, Gun.
- [Gun]Huh?
[Ip] Why did you move
to America?
[Gun] It wasn't my plan.
My newspaper office sent me
here for the US and Canada edition.
There are more Chinese residents
here now.
Many people send
their children here to study.
It's the right time
for Ching to come.
Is the recommendation letter
for school admission
from the Chinese Benevolent
Association ready?
I contacted them.
Mr. Wan, the chairman,
would like to meet you first.
Once we arrive at Chinatown,
we'll head to the association.
[jazzy music]
CHINATOWN
[Chinese instruments playing]
- It's not long enough.
- It's not?
[Ip] Has Mr. Wan
been here for long?
[Gun] Ah, his family
has been here for generations.
His grandfather came here
during the Gold Rush.
He really does care
for the compatriots.
[brake clanks]
[car door closes]
Let's go.
[Gun] Mr. Gwai.
- Hello, Mr. Gwai.
- Mr. Leung.
- [Gwai] Hello.
- This is Master Ip.
- Hello, Mr. Gwai.
- A pleasure to meet you.
Has Mr. Wan arrived?
- [Law] Master Ip.
- He's here.
Master Law.
[Law] It has been a long time.
- Yes.
- [Law] It's really me.
I didn't know you moved here.
I've been here with my family
for a few years already.
So are you visiting
to prepare to move here as well?
Master Law, Mr. Ip
is not moving here.
Shall we sit and talk?
- Sure. After you.
- After you.
[Gun] Masters, allow me
to introduce you.
This is Master Ip Man.
Hello, fellow masters.
[tea cup clanks]
[tense music]
[Law] Take a seat.
Sit.
[Law] Let me introduce everyone.
They are all kung fu masters
from Chinatown.
Master Lau of Choy Li Fut.
Master Chen of Eagle Claw.
Master Han of White Crane.
Master Chiu
of Seven-Star Mantis.
Master Chiang of Xing Yi.
Master Lui
of Eight Trigrams Palm.
Master Tam of Tam's Kick.
As for me, let's spare
the introduction.
We are old friends.
Last but not least,
Chairman of the
Chinese Benevolent Association,
Master Wan of Tai Chi.
[Ip] Master Wan.
Thank you so much for your help.
Master Ip.
[Wan] Don't thank me just yet.
I've heard so much about you.
You're here
at just the right time.
I'd like to ask Master Ip
a favor.
How can I help?
Here in San Francisco's
Chinatown,
there is
a long-established rule.
All kung fu studios
should only accept
Chinese students.
Your apprentice, Bruce Lee,
not only accepted
Western students,
but he even published a book
to explain Chinese martial arts
in English.
[tense music]
[book thumps]
[rasps]
[Wan] Since Master Ip is here,
why don't you help us
solve this issue first?
[Chiang] Does he think
he can be the spokesperson
of Chinese martial arts?
Your apprentice is too arrogant.
[Han] He even said
he would compete
in the karate tournament.
He is provoking us.
[Chen]
He is clearly provoking us.
Exactly.
[Ip] I have read this book.
It's well written.
What's wrong with teaching
Western students?
[mocking laughter]
Master Ip.
Have you heard of the story
of Mr. Dong Guo?
[Wan] A wolf
was sieged by a hunter.
Mr. Dong Guo saw this.
He saved the wolf
and put the wolf in his bag.
Once the hunter left,
the first thing the wolf did
was to eat Mr. Dong Guo alive.
Animals are animals.
They won't be grateful.
[Wan] I will use one
of your Cantonese sayings.
"You offer them rice,
then they betray you."
[scoffs]
That's a bit dramatic.
[giggles]
[Wan] Master Ip.
We're strangers
in a foreign land.
[liquid sloshing]
You don't live here.
You won't understand.
How about this?
Drink this cup of tea...
and you are one of us.
I'll write the letter for you.
[rasps]
[Ip] Fellow masters.
Mr. Wan.
You might have
misunderstood Bruce.
In fact, Bruce just wants
Chinese martial arts
to have a wider following.
I think it's a wonderful thing.
[hard tap]
Marching to a different beat
to make a name for oneself.
[scoffs]
Like student, like master.
Do you two have what it takes
to be the exemplars
of Chinese martial arts?
[rattles]
[rasps]
[wobbles]
[dramatic music]
[cracking]
[cracking continues]
It's going to break.
Mr. Ip, let's forget
about it, shall we?
[glass shatters]
[Ip] Sorry to bother you.
Excuse me.
[Gun] Excuse us, everyone.
Mr. Wan, excuse us.
[slurps]
[door clicks, opens]
[switch clicks]
- Thank you.
- Mr. Ip.
I am sorry about what happened.
- I didn't expect that.
- It's not your fault.
- Gun.
- Hmm?
Is the recommendation letter
essential
for meeting
the school principal?
[sighs]
Yes.
After all, we are immigrants.
Schools here only acknowledge
reputable people.
- A recommendation is a must.
- Mm-hm.
Don't worry.
I have some American friends.
I'll ask them
to write the letter.
- [Ip] Okay.
- I won't keep you.
Get some rest.
- [Ip] Let me walk you out.
- Sure.
[Ip] Take care.
- Bye, Mr. Ip.
- [Ip] Thank you for your help.
[cranking]
[operator] Operator.
Where would you like to call?
Hong Kong.
"Eight, four, two,
six, three, nine."
[operator] Okay,
one moment.
[Bob] Hello! Hello!
Hello, Master Ip!
It's me, Bob!
I can hear you, Bob.
Loud and clear.
Really?
How are things over there?
I heard the air
is fresher there.
It's a huge country.
It's so vast that you can't
even see the buildings across you.
Not exactly.
Right. Is Ching there?
Can you put him on the phone?
Ching. Come take the call.
[Bob] Hurry up.
Long-distance calls cost a lot.
He won't answer.
That's how they are.
Defiance is the trademark
of youth.
[Bob] Listen, this is important.
My wife heard that there
are some meds
that are only sold in the US
and not in Hong Kong.
Can you help me
get some just in case?
No problem.
Please write them down.
[Bob] It's in English.
I will spell it out slowly.
Write them down.
The first one is...
"L-I-U-Q-I-D..."
[Yonah] Dad.
Why are you late again?
I am exhausted today.
I just finished
all the assignments.
I took a nap before I came.
[scoffs]
You're not exhausted
when practicing cheerleading,
but you are when it comes
to martial arts, huh?
You don't get tired
of doing what you like.
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
Come.
Brush knees and twist steps.
[calm music]
Part the horse's mane.
- [light tap]
- [nervous gasp]
Sink the shoulders.
Drop the elbows.
Round form.
See how terrible your moves are.
Look at yourself.
How can you join
the Mid-Autumn Festival?
How can you go on stage?
God, this is so tedious.
How many times have I told you?
In here,
you have to speak Chinese.
[Gun] Hi, Mr. Wright.
How are you?
I thought I was gonna be
speaking with your boss.
[Gun] Actually, it's not
my boss who send me.
I have something perhaps
you can help me with.
[Wright] Okay, what
can I do for you?
This is my friend, Ip Man.
How do you do?
He is looking for a school
for his son
to attend in America.
So maybe you can help him
by writing
a recommendation letter.
Can I have a minute
with you, please?
Mr. Leung, nowadays, many people
fancy comin' over here
to try and find a better life.
Your luck is your ability.
And you achieve
because you choose
to work with a great boss.
But your friend here...
He is a Chinese kung fu master.
[Wright] Look, I don't really
know you that well.
I certainly don't know him.
How do I know that he isn't
some kind of fugitive
just like all of the other
illegal aliens
that get deported every day
from Chinatown?
[Gun] I think you're
being biased.
Not all Chinese
are criminals, Mr. Wright.
Listen, sonny.
The only reason that you're
standing here on my property
wasting my valuable time
is because of your boss.
[Wright] I'm only doing this
for the sake of my friend.
Not you. You understand?
[birds chirping]
[Gun] Mr. Ip. I am sorry.
Don't worry.
- We'll find a way.
- Mm.
[audience cheering]
[clapping]
[camera shutter clicking]
[Bruce Lee yells]
[cheering]
[applause]
Great stuff, man. Really good.
I love that swing kick.
- Here, let me.
- This is crazy.
[clanks]
This match is fixed.
Just a gook dance.
Phonies.
- [loud thump]
- [chair squeaks]
[loud applause]
Woo!
[whistling]
[indistinct chatter]
Enjoy.
[Ip] Congratulations, Bruce.
Your performance tonight
was fantastic.
Thank you, Master.
Thank you for inviting me
to America.
[exhales]
You are welcome.
Actually, I'm also here to try
to find a school for Ching.
You know,
a recommendation letter is
needed for school application.
So, do you mean
those folks from the association
refused to write you a letter?
I have a student
who is a lawyer.
He should be able to help.
Don't worry.
- Thank you.
- Mm.
- [Hartman] Master.
- Hey.
- [Billy] Master.
- Over here.
- [student] Master.
- They're my students.
- Grandmaster, how you doing?
- Hartman, come and sit.
Hey. Hello.
- Amazing.
- [Ip] Hello.
- Master.
- Grandmaster.
This is Hartman.
He's one of a kind.
He's a Marine Staff Sergeant.
He's very much
into Chinese martial arts.
He always tells me he wants to
introduce Chinese martial arts
to the Marines.
In America, most people don't
know about Chinese martial arts.
[Hartman] I have practiced
Wing Chun for a while.
Its centerline theory
for both attack and defense
is useful for combat.
I'd recommend it to my officer.
[Billy]
What do you think, Grandmaster?
Great idea.
[laughing]
- [laughs]
- Hey, yo, kung fu man!
[karateka] I saw you
at the tournament tonight.
I think your stuff is bullshit.
I don't buy it.
[tense music]
What's up, man?
- You wanna try it?
- [Bruce] Hartman.
Let's take it outside.
[scoffs]
I'll kick your ass, man.
I'll kick your ass too.
- Let's take 'em out here.
- I'll take you outside.
[Bruce] Master.
This happens all the time.
I'll be right back.
[yells]
Mm, mm, mm!
Hmph.
[all yell in unison]
[aggressive grunting]
- [glass shatters]
- [metal clanks]
You.
[grunts]
[steam hissing]
- [metal roars]
- [grunts]
[yells]
[scoffs]
The door won't fight back.
But I will
[thumps]
[thwacks]
[scoffs]
[exhales]
[yells]
[thuds]
[taunting]
[dramatic music]
- [Bruce grunts]
- [pained groaning]
[yells]
[groans]
[taunting]
[yelling]
[clattering]
[successive thumping]
[blabbers]
[grunts]
[tapping]
[thumping]
[heavy breathing]
- [nunchucks clattering]
- [yells]
- [groans]
- [clasps]
- [loud thump]
[panting]
[exciting music]
[yelling]
Uh...
[yells]
[panting]
[groans]
[metal clanks]
[loud thump]
[heroic music]
[heaving]
[chuckles]
[loud cheers]
[Bruce] Master.
Here's the recommendation letter
prepared by my student.
It should be okay.
[door creaks]
How do you do?
- Hi. How are you today?
- It's very good.
I have a appointment
with the principal.
- "Mr. Ip Man," right?
- Yes.
Do you have all
the required documents?
- Yes.
- [secretary] Okay.
Follow me, please.
[Mr. Spencer] Is everybody okay?
If anybody needs any help,
just let me know.
[student] Mr. Spencer.
[Mr. Spencer]
You, sir. Fire away.
The principal
is very busy today.
She's in a meeting.
So would you mind waiting?
- Yes. No problem.
- Okay.
[coach] One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,
- [cheering]
- [coach] And good job, girls!
Okay, the contest is over.
I have made my decision.
Yonah, you will be
the new cheerleader
for away games starting
this mid-semester.
- Well done.
- [cheering]
She doesn't deserve it.
What?
[Becky] She changed the routine
all on her own.
She cheated.
- Ah...
- She should be disqualified.
Okay, I don't remember saying
that improvisation
wasn't allowed.
Since I haven't finalized
the routines,
anyone's input is welcomed.
Yonah's... her, her move
was amazing.
[coach] And so is she.
We all have the same goals.
Why don't we try
to work together?
Well done.
[claps]
Class dismissed.
[cheering]
[hurried footsteps]
Mr. Ip, I am so sorry
to keep you waiting.
- No problem.
- I was stuck
in a very important meeting.
- No problem.
- Come, please.
[principal] This lawyer
who wrote the letter,
is he your lawyer?
Actually, he is my student.
Student.
So you're a teacher too?
I am a teacher.
I teach Chinese kung fu.
Chinese martial art.
Like a gymnast?
Yes, something like that.
Well, as you already know,
this is an exclusive
private school.
I can accept this letter
as a referral.
But you still need to get
a recommendation
from the Chinese Benevolent
Association
as they act as guarantors
for late school payment.
- However...
- I understand.
If you can donate $10,000
to our school,
to be one of our sponsoring
board of directors,
we can waive
the recommendation letter
and accept your son right away.
[bell rings]
[indistinct chatter]
Speak of the devil.
Bitch!
[giggling]
Showtime.
[Becky] You think you look
so great out there.
You look like
a little yellow monkey.
We're not gonna
follow your lead.
In America, people like you
follow. They don't lead.
What do you want?
Just leave me alone.
If you're not happy,
then go back to Asia,
This has been our land
for generations.
What do you people want from us?
Now I know why they call you
a stupid blonde.
America has always
had immigrants.
[Yonah] The Indians
are the only real Americans.
Your ancestors
stole their land, paleface.
What did you just say to me?
[indistinct chatter]
[suspenseful music]
She's the one.
Grab her.
[thumping]
[loud smash]
- [boy] Get her there.
- [grunting]
I dare you to stay
in cheerleading.
- Go at her! Come on, hit her!
- You've got your long hair.
You think you can beat me?
[Becky] You could never beat me!
[boys cheering]
[Yonah screaming]
- Oh, god!
- [boy] You, come back here!
[captain] Go, go!
Come back here!
Where are you going?
[boy] Get her, man!
- [shrieks]
- [loud thwack]
I'm gonna cut all of your hair
since you got lice anyway.
Get that good.
- [shrieking]
- [giggling]
- [thumps]
- Ah!
[groans]
- [boy] Get her! Get her!
[captain] Close the door!
Close the door!
Smash it! Smash it!
[gate clanks]
- [smashes]
- [groans]
Stay out of this, old man.
Oh, you want some too?
- [stretches]
- [groans]
[groaning]
[yells]
Stop! No.
No...
No! No more! No! I'm sorry.
- I can't anymore.
- Let's take off.
[wood clanks]
[Yonah] I am Yonah.
What's your name, sir?
[Ip] You can call me
Mr. Ip, Yonah.
[Yonah] Mr. Ip, can you
hold this for me?
Mm-hm.
Mr. Ip, please take a look
from behind.
Please help me cut it
if it's not neat.
[snipping]
- Done.
- Thank you.
[paper crumpling]
Mr. Ip, are you okay?
You were slammed by the gate.
- I'm okay.
- Let me take a look.
[Yonah] Whoa!
I am really fine.
I have some herbal ointment
at home.
It works like magic.
About what happened
at school today,
does it happen often?
It's not the first time.
But I am not afraid of them.
- Does your family know?
- Yes.
My dad always asks me
to put up with it.
He is very strict.
Mr. Ip, why were you
in our school?
I was there to apply for my son.
Then you must have met my dad.
He is the Chairman of the
Chinese Benevolent Association.
I have met your dad.
He must have given you
the letter, then.
Mr. Ip, when will your son come?
He'll have a hard time
getting used to life here.
I can help out.
Actually, your dad didn't help
with the letter.
How come?
You are not a foreigner.
Does your dad have an opinion
against them?
Yes.
He always says that they
are very bad to the Chinese.
They only discriminate
and bully us.
[Yonah]
It has always been like that
since he came here
with Grandpa as a kid.
The way the Chinese are treated
here has always been unfair.
That's why he founded the
Chinese Benevolent Association
to protect us Chinese.
[crying]
Sweetheart.
What's happened?
Oh, my god!
[Gabrielle] What happened?
This Chinese girl.
[Gabrielle] I need you
to come home right now.
Becky's been attacked.
I wish you weren't away
on this business trip.
We need you here.
Come home now, okay?
[revving]
[Yonah] Dad.
This is my friend, Mr. Ip.
You always say Chinese people
should help each other out.
So please write him
a recommendation letter.
Come over here.
Did you get into a fight again?
No.
Yonah.
You know how I hate liars.
I will ask you one more time.
Did you get into a fight?
- No.
- [slaps]
- Hey!
- They were jealous of me!
Because I was made leader,
they cut my hair
and had people beat me up.
How can I put up with it?
You want me to put up with it.
Then what's the point
of practicing martial arts?
- Shut your mouth!
- [Ip] Mr. Wan.
Your daughter was bullied.
It's not wrong
to defend herself.
Master Ip.
[Wan] As I've told you before,
you don't understand
since you don't live here.
Let me tell you.
We live here.
This is our home.
Those people keep trying
to get rid of us.
They even want
to get rid of Chinatown.
Don't you understand?
Have you tried
to get out of Chinatown
to communicate with them
directly, to fight for a change?
[scoffs]
[sighs]
Are you preaching me now?
Yonah.
You can change too.
[Wan] Ip Man.
If you want your letter,
don't use my daughter.
Show me what you've got.
Let's have a match.
[drum beats]
[thwacking]
[clatters]
[grunts]
[rasps]
[squeaks]
[glass shatters]
[thwacks]
[clanks]
[tense music]
[thumping]
[grunts]
[breathes]
What happened?
Old wound?
[knuckles crack]
[hard thump]
[metal clanks]
[grunting]
[hard thump]
[loud thud]
[rasps]
[chair clatters]
[tense music]
[low rumbling]
[grains rasp]
[chandelier clangs]
[rumbling intensifies]
[loud shatter]
[clanking]
Yonah! Yonah!
- Are you all right?
- Dad, I am fine.
[coughing]
[shatters]
[metal clattering]
Yonah. Yonah!
[Wan] Yonah.
[Yonah] Dad.
[Yonah coughs]
I am here.
I am fine.
ALL CHINESE ARE ONE BIG FAMILY
Ip Man.
It looks like we'll have to wait
until the Mid-Autumn Festival
to decide who's the winner.
Winning or losing,
does it really matter?
Shouldn't we use
Chinese martial arts
to change the biases against us?
I brought Yonah back
because I wanted to protect her.
I'm not here for the letter.
[somber music]
[Ching] You are always right
and I am always wrong.
You are never supportive of me.
If Mom was still alive,
- she would have...
- [slaps]
[dial clicking]
[phone ringing]
- Hello?
- [operator] US Trunk Line.
Yes, collect call, please.
Hey, hey, hey, Master Ip.
- Bob.
- [Bob] Yes.
Where's Ching?
He went out to buy
some late-night snacks.
[Bob] Right, how are things
getting on with you?
Is it going well?
Mm...
There's a bit of a hiccup.
It might take a few more days
before I can return.
Back in a few days?
That's very good.
Good luck. Be safe.
Thanks a lot.
- Bye bye.
- [Bob] Okay, bye bye.
- [sighs]
- [phone clanks]
- [commander] Left, right!
- [recruits] Left, right!
- [commander] To the left, right!
- [recruits] To the left, right!
- [commander] Left, right!
- [recruits] Left, right!
[Gunny]
Pick up the pace, devil dogs!
You are warriors.
You are killing machines.
Earn it like you got a pair.
Kick that bag, boy!
Wear that EGA with pride!
Get the banana
out of the tailpipe!
Move it! Move it! Move it!
You gotta earn it, devil dog!
[yells]
[Colin] Move!
[grunts]
[groans in pain]
[colored recruit]
I surrender, sensei!
What did you just say?
Did I just hear you say
that you surrender?
Did I?
You know what
our motto is, recruit!
Trained to kill! Ready to die!
Do you understand the meaning
of those words?
- It's hurting me, sir!
- Oh, it's hurting you, is it?
Hurting you. You know,
this is the problem.
You know there is a rumor
going around this base,
people saying that I'm racist.
I'm not racist.
See, I don't hate you
because you're colored.
I hate you because
you're a cowardly colored!
[groans]
- Get off the mat!
- You, Jackson. You're next.
Staff Sergeant Hartman,
do you mind explaining to me
what exactly
this contraption is?
It's a Wing Chun dummy.
A kung fu training aid, like
a punching bag, if you will,
but for Chinese martial arts.
- [chuckles]
- [hard thumping]
Let me ask you something.
Did you fall out of your crib
this morning
and bang your little head?
[Gunny] Where the hell
do you think you are?
Does this look like a museum
for preserving your ancient
Chinese heritage?
Wing Chun is improvising
and adapting,
just like a Marine.
I've been practicing
for months now,
and I find it practical
for real combat.
I'm certain the practicing it
will be beneficial
for Marines on the battleground.
Oh, you're certain, are you?
So this kung fu bullshit's gonna
allow us to kill our enemies?
Is that what you're
trying to say?
Outstanding, Staff Sergeant.
[Gunny] You're a goddamn genius.
Get this thing off my base now.
You know nothing
of Chinese kung fu.
[Gunny] Zero!
[tense music]
All right,
Staff Sergeant Hartman,
I'm gonna allow you
to prove those words.
If you can defeat Colin
in a fair fight,
then I'll consider,
maybe allowing
your wooden girlfriend
to stay on the base.
Is that understood?
[dramatic music]
[yells]
[groans]
[taunts]
[shuffling]
[chuckling]
Come on, Colin. Smack him up.
[thumping]
[groans]
[loud thud]
[clapping]
- [applause]
- [Gunny] Outstanding work.
Very nice.
You see this, men?
Now this is karate.
Your Chinese kung fu is only
good for folding laundry.
It stays where it belongs and
that is the hell off my base.
Now, because of
the Staff Sergeant's stupidity,
all you Chinese will run
an extra 30 laps today.
And the Staff Sergeant himself
will run an extra 30 after that.
Are we clear?
Good.
Carry on.
[Hartman] One, two, three, four!
[recruits in unison]
One, two, three, four!
[Hartman] One, two, three, four!
[recruits in unison]
One, two, three, four!
Left and right and lei ho!
- Left and right and lei ho!
- [fire crackles]
[coughing]
[coughing continues]
[knocking on door]
- [door squeaks]
- Mr. Ip.
- I have great news for you.
- What's up, Yonah?
[paper rustles]
Mm.
Mm?
[sighs]
Did you forge the signature?
Don't worry, it looks
the same as Dad's.
I am sure no one will notice.
I don't understand what you kids
are thinking nowadays.
[Ip] You guys act without
thinking about the consequences.
[Yonah] What are you doing?
It took me a lot of effort.
[sighs]
Did it cross your mind that
your dad would be very upset?
I don't care. He doesn't care
if I'm happy anyway.
Why do you say that?
I think he cares about you.
He only cares about himself.
He always pushes me
to practice Tai Chi
and to perform
at the Mid-Autumn Festival.
Just because he likes it.
[Yonah] But I don't.
If you don't like Tai Chi,
just tell him.
I did. He wouldn't listen.
In his eyes,
everything I do is wrong.
I fight back when I'm
being bullied, it's my fault.
I like cheerleading and dancing,
it's my fault.
I am always wrong.
He never supports me.
[Yonah] I don't believe
that's how other dads are like.
At the very least,
you are not, Mr. Ip.
[pensive music]
Is cheerleading your passion?
Not really.
I do it because I like it.
Mr. Ip, you are
so good at fighting.
Isn't it because
you like martial arts?
Ah! At the Mid-Autumn Festival,
why don't you do
your cheerleading dance?
Right, why haven't I
thought about that?
[Yonah] That's a great idea.
Mr. Ip, will you come?
Sure.
Great.
- Now go to school.
- Okay.
Off you go.
- Bye bye.
- [Yonah] Bye bye.
[Gabrielle] You finally decided
to come back, then,
Andrew, thank you.
I was in Washington DC,
Gabrielle.
I came back as soon as I could.
How's Becky?
She was almost disfigured
by a Chinese girl at school.
[Gabrielle] And I don't
understand the grounds
they let a Chinese student
in anyway.
What do you intend
to do about it?
What are the INS going to do
about those Chinese savages?
Get rid of them. Send them home!
Becky, honey, who...
who did this to you?
Yonah Wan.
She's the daughter
of the Chairman
of the Chinese
"Benelovent" Association,
or so she claims.
Chinatown.
I'll handle this.
[film reel rustling]
[clicks]
Really impressive.
- So this is Chinese kung fu?
- Yes, sir.
It's really amazing.
I mean really amazing.
Thank you, sir.
This brochure has
a brief introduction
and here is the transcript
that I've prepared.
Actually, sir,
there's a martial arts event
taking place in Chinatown
during the Full Moon Festival.
With your permission,
I'd like to go film it
and do some more research
so that we may further
investigate this matter.
- Chinatown?
- [Hartman] Yes, sir.
Granted.
Just don't make this
a waste of my time.
- Definitely not, sir.
- All right.
- [knocks on door]
- Come in.
Sir.
Please excuse
the Staff Sergeant's intrusion.
What the hell
are you doing here?
My job, as a Marine.
So that's all right.
So let's start
to explore the idea
of incorporating Chinese kung fu
into our hand to hand
combat training.
Now, Staff Sergeant Hartman
is gonna go to Chinatown
for research.
[commanding officer]
I'd like you to start learning
something from this handbook.
Here, take it.
- Gentlemen, that's all.
- Sir.
[Gunny scoffs]
[thuds]
[Colin] Fix your base, recruit.
[approaching footsteps]
You have no power, Mr. Creese.
Instructor!
A word.
[Colin] Bow.
Gunny?
You know there is not a doubt
in my mind
that karate is the best form of
hand to hand combat. Bar none.
But do you know what that
backstabbing son of a bitch
- Hartman's gone and done?
- Tell me.
Convinced our commanding officer
that his bullshit kung fu
is more effective
than our karate training.
[heavy sigh]
I'm gonna need you to right
that wrong, Colin.
You just let me show
those people
the meaning
of real combat karate
and I'll shut those
kung fu charlatans up for good.
- Good, man.
- Gunny.
[Colin] Continue.
Move!
[lion dance music]
[cheering]
[cheering continues]
- Good.
[camera clicking]
Grandmaster.
More! More!
Oh! Mm!
[man] I loved it!
Mr. Ip, you are late.
I saved you a seat
next to the masters over there.
No worries.
I'll stay where I am.
But the view is better there.
How about you go back
and get ready to perform, okay?
Go on.
All right. I'll go, then.
- Mr. Gwai.
- Uh.
Huh?
That's how you're dressed
for stage?
Yes.
Where's your dad?
Didn't you come with your dad?
No, I came first.
I didn't see him.
- Maybe he will show up later.
- Ah.
[pen scribbles]
[hard thump]
[tires squeak]
TO MASTER IP
[doors squeak]
[door thuds]
[Walters] Mr. Wan Zhong Hua.
We're the United States
Department
of Immigration and Customs.
We're here to take you
under custody for questioning
regarding the presence
of illegal aliens
- residing in Chinatown.
- [paper rustles]
[yells]
Go.
- Good.
Good.
[cheering]
- They're my students.
- Good.
[tense music]
[gasps]
[indistinct jeering]
When did we invite
these white people to perform?
I don't know.
- [Han] Who are they?
- Who invited them?
Get down from there!
Scram!
Get lost!
- Get down!
- Leave!
[Colin] Hey, Chinaman!
You wanna try to break
these bricks with your kung fu?
Huh?
Cowards.
[people jeering]
- Go away.
Scram!
[yells]
[clatters]
[gasping in surprise]
[crowd murmurs]
I'll go and look for your dad.
My name is Colin Frater.
Fourth Dan black belt
in Kyokutan Karate.
And I'm here to show you
yellow bitches
the taste of real combat.
Fight me with your
hokey-pokey kung fu.
I dare you.
- What are you talking about?
- Get down!
[Law] Screw you!
I will fight you now!
- [San] Eh, eh.
- Huh?
Mr. Gwai, what happened
to Mr. Wan?
What do you mean by that?
I just saw
some immigration officers
- take Mr. Wan into a car.
- Huh?
Let's make it quick.
[Colin] You understand
I will go all out?
You are begging to be killed.
- Come on, then.
- I won't hold back either.
[cheering]
- [thwacks]
- [screams in pain]
- Master Law.
Are you okay?
Bullshit, why is the stage
so small?
- Be careful.
- Help me.
- Who's next?
- Freaking yankee!
- I'm in.
- Good.
- Come on!
- Go!
- Master!
Master!
[groans]
- Be careful!
- Master!
- [bones crack]
- [yells in pain]
- Master.
- Master Chiu.
- Master Chiu, are you okay?
Help him first.
[sighs]
Lady, I'll show you no mercy.
Don't hold back.
Mind yourself first.
- [loud thump]
- [grunts]
[thumping]
- Master Chiang.
- Master!
- Beat him, Master Chiang.
- Beat him!
- Get up!
- Master!
[grunts]
- You can do it!
- [groans]
- [loud thump]
[thumps]
Enough.
- Bravo!
- Master Ip, bravo.
- Master Ip, bravo!
Come on, Mr. Ip!
- Master Ip!
All the best, Master Ip!
[continuous thumping]
[groans]
[Colin grunts]
[rapid thwacking]
- [hard thump]
- [groans]
[yells]
[loud thump]
[nervous breathing]
[hard thumping]
[bones crunch]
[loud thud]
[Colin groaning]
[crowd roaring]
Great, Master Ip!
[pained groans]
Yes! Yes!
[student 1] Sensei.
- Help him out.
- [student 2] Sensei.
All right, here we go.
Mr. Ip, that was fantastic!
Mr. Ip, you are the best!
The best!
That was amazing!
The most amazing Mr. Ip!
Woo! Woohoo! Woo!
Yonah! Yonah!
I have bad news. Ms San told me
your dad was taken
by the immigration officers.
- Huh?
- [Gun] I'll drive you there.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
[Walters] We've reopened the
cases involving the CBA.
We suspect that these Chinamen
have identities
that are fraudulent
and that you've helped them
by writing falsified letters
of referral from the USA,
making you an accomplice
of these illegal aliens.
This is a setup!
Would you know?
I'm going to arrest
every single person
in the CBA tonight.
[Walters] You and the CBA
will be gone for good.
He has a broken rib
but he will be okay.
[Gunny] Chinese kung fu my ass.
I'll shut them down
in my own way.
[clicks]
[engine revs]
[INS officer] The Full Moon
event has concluded.
Those Chinamen must be back
at the Chinese
Benevolent Association.
Thirty minutes to CBA.
Bring them all in.
[INS officer]
Call the wives, boys.
We're staying late.
We're going to Chinatown,
arresting every Chinamen
in the CBA.
[Billy] This operation
makes no sense, sir.
Shut up, do-good marshal.
Do as you're told.
[door creaks]
Mr. Ip.
Excuse me. Anybody here?
I need some help.
- What now?
- [Billy] Let me check it out.
Whoa, it's way past office
hours. You can't be here.
My father, Wan Zhong Hua
has been taken by mistake.
I need to see him right now.
- [Ip] Billy.
- I can't let you in.
- Grandmaster.
- [Ip] Billy.
- Can you help us?
- [Billy] I wish I could.
Her father, Mr. Wan Zhong Hua,
what happened?
I have no idea, sir.
But please take my advice.
Stay away from the Chinese
Benevolent Association tonight.
Tonight, don't go there.
All right? We're gonna raid
that place tonight.
I gotta go. But remember,
don't go there.
[tense music]
[tires screech]
Masters.
Who incited those karate guys
to come here?
They made a scene for no reason.
It must be Bruce Lee.
He dragged us into this.
[Chen] Don't make
false assumptions.
His master helped us.
[phone rings]
Hello.
Master Law, leave
the CBA right now.
[Gwai] The immigration
- is coming to make arrests.
- [Tam] Who are you?
- Is that you?
- What are you saying?
- What are you doing?
- Hello?
- [men groaning]
Bad news.
[thwacking]
[clatters]
[shatters]
[groans]
Is that it?
Is this your Chinese kung fu?
- [Gunny] Huh?
- [groans]
What about this guy?
Your chairman, hey! Where is he?
I don't know!
You tell me
or I'm gonna break your arm.
- [bones crunching]
- Ah!
[Law] Ah!
INS. Immigration.
- Good boy.
- [bones crunching]
What happened?
Master Law.
Master Ip.
A yankee just showed up
and attacked everyone
like he was coming for revenge.
[Gun] Mr. Ip, the immigration
officers will be here soon.
[nervous music]
[INS officer 1] They're gone.
Check in back.
[INS officer 2] All right, guys,
let's get a sweep.
Looking for any clues that
might tell us where they went.
[revs]
[clicks]
[suspenseful music]
[Gunny] Officer.
I'm looking for a Chinaman
by the name of Wan Zhong Hua.
Where is he?
Uh, what do you want with him?
I'm Gunnery Sergeant
Barton Geddes,
Second Battalion, Fifth Marines.
One of my men was assaulted
in Chinatown tonight.
Wan Zhong Hua is the chairman
of the Chinese
Benevolent Association.
I need him back
on my base tonight.
This man made me look bad.
[Gunny] It's personal.
So why don't you cooperate
or things are gonna get
pretty bad for you too.
Do you understand?
So go and get him
and I'll worry
about the repercussions.
Follow me.
You're now officially in the
custody of the US Marines.
Just don't let him stay
in the country
when you're done
with him, all right?
My karate coach was defeated
in a fight tonight
by Chinese kung fu.
Since you're the representative
of Chinese kung fu,
I'm holding you
personally accountable.
[Gunny]
These Chinamen right here,
I just crushed all of them.
You're the only one left.
I need to fight you.
Dad.
[Walters] What are you
doing here? Get out of here!
You're Becky's father, right?
Listen, it's all my fault.
It's nothing to do
with my father.
I'm sorry.
[Yonah] I beg you.
Please let my papa go.
Please. Please.
[Wan] Yonah.
Get up!
Yonah!
Don't kneel to these people.
You are right.
If you can't take it anymore,
then just don't.
I will fight you.
Let's go.
[Yonah] Dad, don't.
- [chains rattling]
- [hard thumping]
[Ip] Bruce.
Master.
[Jeep rumbling]
I want all recruits in the
PT Gauntlet straight away.
[guard] Aye-aye, Gunny.
Especially
Staff Sergeant Hartman.
[commander] Reveille! Reveille!
Get your asses on the line!
Move it! Move it! Move it!
Out! Out! Out!
Good!
Move your asses, Marines!
Move it!
Move that ass!
Double time! Double time!
Left hand, left knee.
Right hand, right knee.
Aye, sir.
Sit down! Sit down! Move it!
I try to be a fair man.
[Gunny] So since
Staff Sergeant Hartman
so desperately wants his
Chinese kung fu
to be part of our curriculum,
I'm happy to give up
my rack time
and give a Chinese
representative
the chance to prove
their kung fu is actually useful
in a real combat situation.
Master Wan.
You don't have to accept
his challenge.
I have to.
If I back down,
I'm no longer Chinese.
[Gunny] No rules.
Fight till you drop.
Make sure you get
all these on film.
[recruit] Sir, yes, sir!
- [hard thump]
- [groans]
[breathing]
[loud thud]
[aggressive grunt]
[groans]
[loud thump]
[aggressive grunt]
[yells]
[hard thwack]
[tense music]
[breathing]
[thumping]
[groans]
[hard thud]
[coughing]
Master Wan, stop!
[breathing]
[hard thwack]
- [bones crunch]
- [screaming in pain]
[grunting]
[grunting in pain]
[panting]
You know what I just realized?
You and your daughter look
a hell of a lot alike...
when you beg.
Enough!
[groans]
Uh...
[Hartman] Master Wan.
Master Wan.
[Gunny] Don't you think
I deserve a round of applause?
[applause]
[Tam] Those white people
always pick on our Chinatown.
They made a scene tonight
at the association.
They are getting way
out of line.
[Lui] That's right.
It's not the first time
the immigration officers came.
They harassed us for no reason.
[Chen] Yes.
My grandfather came here
as a hard labor worker.
He helped them
build the railway.
He helped the Americans connect
the east coast with the west.
It's all thanks
to Chinese labor.
Yet the American government
was never willing to acknowledge
our contribution.
They keep trying to kick us out
with all sorts of excuses.
The white guys are too arrogant.
[Lau] There's no equality here.
Bruce.
- We were too...
- Hey.
It's no big deal.
I didn't take it to heart.
Don't worry.
[relieved sigh]
[Chen] Master Ip.
- Thank you very much...
- [Ip] Hey.
Not at all.
All of us are Chinese.
We should help each other out.
[Law] That has always
been my belief.
Chinese people must help
each other out.
Right? Right?
- Yes.
- Spot on.
- Master Law is right.
- He's right.
[phone ringing]
[Tam] Okay.
- Hello.
- [Hartman] Master.
At the Mid-Autumn
Festival tonight,
the masters in Chinatown
had a conflict
with people from the army.
Master Wan is...
He is severely injured.
[Hartman]
He's now at the hospital.
[somber music]
[sniffing]
[inhales]
[coin clanks]
[rattling]
[clatters]
[phone ringing]
[beeping]
[door opens]
[keys clank]
Little prick, you're
not answering the phone again!
- Hello.
- Bob.
Where is Ching?
He is practicing
with the wooden dummy.
[sighs]
[dummy clattering]
[Bob] Master Ip, long-distance
calls are expensive.
Bob.
I have cancer.
[somber music]
[sobs]
Are you serious?
Actually, the reason
I hurried to America...
is to have a look here
and see if it's right for Ching.
Please let me talk to him.
Hold on.
[Bob] Your dad
is asking for you.
Answer the phone.
I won't take his call.
[Ching] No way!
Listen to me.
I will only say it once.
Your dad has cancer.
He went to America
just to find you a school.
- [Ching] Dad.
- Ching.
[Ching sobbing on the line]
It was my fault
for hitting you last time.
I am sorry.
[Ip] I know
you like martial arts.
I will teach you when I'm back.
Dad.
[Ching] When will
you be home?
I still have something
to take care of.
Once it's done,
I will be right back.
[Ip] Bye bye.
[sobbing]
[phone clanks]
[inhales, exhales]
Take me to the boot camp.
[Yonah] Mr. Ip, don't go.
I don't want anything bad
to happen to you.
I'm a martial artist.
In the face of injustice,
I must stand up and fight.
[Ip] That was why
we took up martial arts.
This is something I want to do.
Just like you want
to do cheerleading.
[Gunny] If you're lucky enough
to come to America,
set foot on our soil,
then you ought to learn
everything about my culture.
Consider yourselves incredibly
honored to be here.
Incredibly honored!
'Cause America
is the greatest and most
powerful country on earth.
Land of supremacy,
and that
is an undisputable fact.
Is that understood?
[recruits in unison]
Sir, yes, sir!
[tense music]
[Gunny] But last night,
I had the unfortunate
but necessary task
of demonstrating how
an inferior race
can and should be defeated.
I'm sure you will all agree the
results were quite definitive.
So don't even think about
bringing your filthy cultures
to my Marine corp again,
is that understood?
[in unison]
Sir, yes, sir!
[Hartman] Racist asshole!
Look around you.
We are the culture.
Your supremacy
is pure hatred and bigotry.
This, this is Master Ip Man.
He defeated Colin last night.
And he's here to kick your ass!
No rules.
You fight till you drop.
[drum beat]
[thumping]
[taunting]
[hard thump]
[groaning]
[thwacking]
[exhales]
[continuous thwacking]
[hard thump]
[crackles]
- [groaning]
- [loud thud]
[thwacks]
[bones cracking]
[coughing]
Is that it?
Huh? Is that all you've got?
[coughing]
You see this?
You're nothing but another
little yellow chink!
[Gunny] Come on!
- [Ip coughing]
- [Gunny] Let's go!
That's it.
[groans]
[crunches]
[loud thud]
[continuous thwacking]
- [groans]
- [hard thump]
[bones crackles]
[groans]
[bones crushing]
[loud thud]
[coughing]
[dramatic music]
Take the Gunnery Sergeant
to Sick Bay.
- Johnson! Harris!
- [commander] Move! Move! Move!
[groaning]
[exhales]
[claps]
[applause]
ALL CHINESE ARE ONE BIG FAMILY
[Wan] Master Ip.
This letter is a bit late.
I am sorry
to have kept you waiting.
I appreciate it.
Hey...
Right.
When will you
and your son come here?
[exhales]
Actually, the grass
is not really greener
on the other side of the fence.
[laughs]
[Yonah] Mr. Ip.
I bought all the medicine
you asked for.
I even got you
candies and chocolate.
This is my favorite chocolate.
Your son will love it too.
- [laughs]
- Thank you.
You're so thoughtful.
[plane engine roaring]
[hurried footsteps]
Dad.
[tranquil music]
[Ching] I have
thought it through.
I don't want to
go to America.
I really like
martial arts.
Dad.
Teach me.
Okay.
Self-confidence
is the most important thing,
no matter where you are.
[dummy clattering]
Ching.
I will demonstrate once.
Film it.
[sad music]
[thumping]
[clattering]
[heroic music]
[heroic music continues]
[victorious music]
[victorious music continues]
[tranquil music]
[dramatic music]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org