"Wing chun master cheung tin chi
defend the community with martial arts"
"cheung tin chi challenged martial arts
masters and become the grandmaster"
"Wing chun versus wing chun cheung tin chi
fights against ip man behind closed doors"
"produced by: Raymond wong & Donnie yen"
"directed by: Yuen wo ping"
"wing chun master cheung tin chi
walks away from the world of martial arts"
after cheung tin chi was
defeated by ip man,
he took his son cheung fung,
and left the world of martial arts.
I'm done.
I have another job in 2 days for you.
Target's a hoodlum.
Someone who's had enough
wants to teach him a lesson.
I'm out
no children, no women
and no nice guys.
So this guy isn't against your rules.
Look I'll double your pay.
Think it over.
I said I'm done.
All you know is fighting.
Walking away now?
What a pity!
I want a simple life.
Nothing to pity about.
Hold on!
I have a question.
So which is faster?
Your fist or my gun?
Over 7 paces,
gun's faster.
Within 7 paces,
my fist.
We're around 7 paces apart.
Stop!
People pay you.
To solve their problems.
Since even money can't change your mind.
I'll respect your decision.
Go!
Lifting your jacket is
what slowed you down.
Fung!
Fung fung!
Time to get up for school.
Get up.
What's for breakfast?
Plain congee and breadsticks again?
Can we eat something else?
Okay.
I'll get something else tomorrow.
You say that every time.
Liar!
Tin chi!
Morning, auntie luk!
Papal!
Today's a big day.
You have to get off work on time.
Boss,
I just started working.
You want me to get off already?
Don't be lazy.
Okay!
Let's check the delivery list.
Soy sauce, 10 bottles...
Chilli sauce, 6 bottles...
Peanuts, 5 packs.
Give me hand.
Auntie luk
could you watch my store
while I make a delivery
oh sure! Don't you worry
thank you!
Auntie luk I'm going to school!
Good boy!
Hey!
Hey! Cheung fung
there you go.
Papal!
Remember we have plans tonight.
So be on time okay?
You're the one who needs to
remember to be on time.
Don't get detention.
You hear me?
Don't worry!
The bus is here!
Be careful.
I will! Bye!
Bye!
You...
Hey Nana!
You forgot to pay me.
Fat lung,
same as before.
Put it on my tab.
Hey, your tab is a mile long
you must pay it all today.
Tomorrow.
I'll pay you tomorrow. Promise.
It's not my decision
tell the boss yourself.
Hey boss!
She's broke again.
Sorry, kit.
Here boss.
Who needs your sympathy?
Make a call.
Get someone to bring money.
If you don't pay up now
I'll sell you to a brothel
in the south pacific.
Excuse me!
Can I see the black bat?
Sure!
I'll take it.
Please wrap it up for me.
Eat!
Julial
well look who's here?
I brought the money.
Let her go!
Count it.
I'm warning you.
Don't sell opium to her again.
But she wants me to.
Talk to her, not me.
You beat her up.
I'm letting that slide.
If you hit her again,
I'll make sure you pay for it.
Hold on!
This is just the principal.
What about interest?
I need 500 more.
You won't get another dime,
Nana's coming with me.
I'd like to see
what you can do about it.
With no more money you're not leaving!
Grab them!
You broke my present.
Get lost!
Go!
Go on!
Police!
What's going on?
Freeze! What are you doing!
Freeze!
Arrest them all!
Stop!
Police business!
What's going on?
Why were you fighting?
- Officer...
- You're coming as well.
Move it!
Sit over there!
What's your name?
Cheung tin chi.
Where do you work?
Tin kee store.
Our records show,
cheung tin chi
is active in underground boxing arenas
as a fighter.
You were arrested,
at the west union shipyard
for gang fighting before.
We have it all here.
I was helping someone.
Oh like you did today?
That's right!
He was helping us.
I'm not talking to you.
Listen up,
fighting anywhere in public
is against the law.
You!
Sir?
It's just self-defense
let them all go.
Huh?
This is an order!
No problem sir.
Why'd you get in a fight
let them all go.
Hey!
Why can they leave and we can't go?
Who the hell are you?
I'm chiu kam fu's sister.
That's the guy who owns gold bar.
What a pain!
Yeah you can go!
Thank you... lets go
Officer,
when can I go?
Take a new statement from him.
You can go after that.
It's almost 10 o'clock. Where is he?
Fung!
- Quick hurry!
- You're late!
Give me back my allowance from last month.
Okay!
- I know! I'm changing.
- Take off your pants!
- I'm changing okay?
- Hurry!
I'll help you...
Papa! Hurry!
I'm coming
hey your zipper is down!
Okay!
Here! Come on.
Quick!
Papa! Hurry hurry!
Coming coming!
Hello!
Sorry, we're closed.
Birthday! Birthday me!
Sorry, young man.
All of our chefs have
gone home for the night.
Come back anytime.
Okay? Come back!
It's your fault!
You can't have steak,
but you still have a present.
Wow! It's black bat!
Papal!
There's no music!
How come?
It can't be.
Papa it's alright, it's a gift from you.
I love it
So boss.
Other than steak,
what else do you want to eat?
Braised beef,
fried beef with Kale...
Tomato and beef stew!
Nothing but beef?
You have something against beef?
Very well.
Let's go.
We'll have a beef feast.
Cheung lok
is the number one gang,
not because we have the most members
or the most money.
But because we have trust.
But I just found out
one of our own has been stealing from us.
My father used to say:
Without trust,
a man has nothing.
Remember that uncle hung?
I remember!
Your old man and I started out together.
These scars you see here.
Helped him carve out his
turf and make his name.
So what if I took some money?
What's the problem?
There's no problem.
Even if you're a founding member
doesn't mean you can break the rules.
Take him home.
Today,
I want to discuss something
important with you.
It's about cheung lok's future.
I am planning
to legalize our business
completely.
In 3 years,
I want cheung lok
to be squeaky clean.
Your decision
will have a major impact on business.
That's right!
Been a gangster all my life.
It's the only thing I know.
And trading
isn't as profitable as smuggling.
Listen!
I can't guarantee that
we'll make as much money
as we do in the black market.
But I can promise you
that from now on.
No one will have to go to jail
or get himself killed.
If you ask me,
it's the opposite.
Cheung lok now has clout.
We should capitalize
and we expand!
Consolidate our position.
With enough weight,
neither side of the law
will dare mess with us!
Since we have different opinions,
let us vote to decide.
Those in favor of legalizing cheung lok
raise your hands.
You're the boss,
you call the shots.
Thank you!
From now on,
we should refrain, from using violence.
Let's work together
to transform cheung lok.
Wow black bat is so amazing!
He took out all the bad
guys with 3 punches!
Well...
My dad is more awesome.
He can knock down the
baddies with one punch.
He's the grandmaster of wing chun.
That's a lie, cheung fung!
My father is the grandmaster.
He runs a martial arts
club and he's brilliant.
Papa used to own a club as well.
My dad is the best around!
Used to?!
Now he runs a tiny store.
He's a grocery man.
Grocery man...
Papa is the grandmaster of wing chun.
He's a grocery man.
Let's eat...
Not hungry?
They call you a grocery man.
And that's what I am.
You're not!
Papa,
I'm sorry... l
forget it.
Let's eat.
Papal!
You won't teach wing chun anymore?
Go sleep.
"Cheung tin chi,
the rising star in martial arts world"
"cheung tin chi, undefeated in wing chun"
Papa, help me!
- Papa!
- Fung!
I'm scared!
Papal!
- Fung!
- It's on fire!
- Papa!
- Come, don't be afraid
- papa I'm scared!
- Don't worry!
Papa is here, don't worry.
Papa hurry up!
Don't worry.
- Almost done!
- I can't breathe! Papal!
Hurry!
Papa hurry!
Come here, fung!
Here use this!
Fung!
Papal!
Don't worry...
Here come, sit down.
Crossing you is the same as crossing me.
I'll kill him for you today.
Oh come on.
He still got out?!
Are you sure you can handle it?
Papa! Papa!
Papal!
Kill him!
Quick!
I got a plan for people like him.
Stop! Stop!
Please watch my son! I beg you!
Thank you!
Papa papa...
Fung!
Hey! Your son has fainted!
He's got a fever.
Take him to a hospital.
Quick!
Fung!
Miss kwan, kit is causing trouble again.
Papa, it hurts!
Bear with it. You'll be fine soon.
I don't want to be here. I want to go home.
Here...
Why don't you have an apple?
Look!
Thank you!
It's fine.
Move aside.
Here. Ahh!
The boy is seriously hurt.
What kind of parents are you?
Yes, sir!
Understand, sir!
We know what happened.
It was an accident. Let's go.
Officer,
I know who did it.
I told you,
it was an acc-i-dent!
How is that possible?
They burnt his home and tried to kill him.
Why won't you investigate?!
It's a police matter. Don't lecture me!
Let's go!
Papal!
If our house is burnt
down, where will we go?
I can help you.
My brother owns gold bar.
I'll take you to meet him.
I bought you new clothes.
You're meeting the boss,
so you need to look presentable.
Julia. You're early!
Ming, where's my brother?
He's in a meeting.
That's not fair at all!
You stole all of my customers.
I want you to pay for my loss.
You should pay me. I'm losing money too.
I said it first! No you I said you...
You guys are both wrong!
We just want Harmony on bar street.
You two!
Drink what I made you
and stop fighting.
No price war either!
Drink up!
What's wrong?
Is there a problem?
No... no...
It's delicious, fu!
- Nice!
- We should go.
Yeah... bye
fu, Julia is here.
Brother.
This is my friend cheung tin chi.
He's in a bit of a bind.
I want to take them in.
What's that?
No...
Staying with you is a bad idea.
You live with Nana.
Let them live with me.
Hey kid, come here!
You're scaring him!
How can he stay with you?
I'm sorry.
We'll go
no wait.
Fu,
tin chi saved me and Nana.
You taught me that,
friends have a moral
obligation to each other.
Fine fine.
Listen carefully. These two girls
one is my sister,
one is my future wife.
They're off limits.
Don't even think about it.
I can pay rent.
Let me work at the bar.
I'll work in exchange for a place to stay.
Whatever!
Make sure you show up on time tonight.
Come on in!
Just make yourselves at home.
Don't be shy.
Nana!
Stop walking around like that!
You're practically naked!
You usually wear less than me!
When do I wear less than you?
I always dress properly.
Believe me.
Papa, papa. There's a fire!
Papal!
Fung!
It's okay.
I'm here.
It's fine...
Who's that?
Where's tso sai kit.
He's not here.
Out!
Dancing with me together, come in!
Buy me one drink.
Come.
No...
Hello.
I drink.
Let me.
Thank you!
Hey! It's cheung!
"Kiss me, honey, honey, kiss me"
"thrill me, honey, honey, thrill me"
"don't care even if I blow my top"
"but, honey honey, don't stop..."
"I'd like to play a little game with you"
"a little game especially made for two"
"if you come close then
I will show you how"
"closer, closer, now"
"kiss me, honey, honey, kiss me"
"thrill me, honey, honey, thrill me"
"don't care even if I blow my top"
"but, honey honey, don't stop..."
Are you blind?
Pick it up.
You make money from me.
I gave you an order, you follow it.
Pick it up.
Pick
up!
Sorry sorry.
He's new.
Happy happy...
Kam,
take care of him.
My friend, come on, come on.
You! Come here!
"Don't stop..."
Cheung tin chi,
who do you think you are?
Is it humiliating to pick it up?
Pride is not worth a dime here understand?
I picked it up.
There's a rule here on bar street.
Customers are always right.
Don't you ever for... get.
Allow me.
No I can manage.
I'm happy to do it.
Fung, eat your breakfast.
Why is it congee again?
It was just your first day at the bar.
And I know everything is new.
But you'll get used to it.
I mean,
you put up with so much.
How can you bear it?
Our job is to make the customers happy.
Just smile and it'll blow over.
Oh and,
please don't be angry with my brother.
He's worried you'd offend the foreigners.
Sure. It's forgotten.
Papa, does it hurt?
No way!
Who did this?
Cheung tin chi.
Stop!
This is my opium den.
I'll take care of it.
This is cheung lok business.
I made it clear to everyone.
No more trouble.
If you can't handle it,
I'll take over.
The place is burned down.
Just shut it down.
And no vengeance.
Don't compromise cheung lok's reputation.
No vengeance?
What's wrong with vengeance?
If 1 let him go,
that would be wrong!
Brothers!
We're going to kill cheung tin chi!
Take kit home.
Don't forget his medicine.
I don't need sympathy.
Follow him.
Please enjoy!
This drink is for you.
I'm working right now.
It's okay. I'm buying.
Impressive!
Who are you?
My brother burnt down your house.
This is for your house.
I hope we can put all this behind us.
I burnt down his opium den.
This is for his opium den.
Don't bother me again.
Not many people would dare to
use that tone with me.
Miss kwan!
What brings you here?
We have catching up to do.
I also came to meet your new friend.
Tin chi,
miss kwan is my benefactor.
I used to work for her.
Everyone has heard of
cheung lok, and tso ngan kwan.
Fu,
that's enough.
Miss kwan made me what I am today!
I should go.
Cheung tin chi,
you have personality.
I won't force your hand.
From now on,
if you need anything,
just come to me.
Remember.
Put it behind you.
This cheque,
covers my tab.
Miss kwan,
let me buy a round!
Impressive!
Remember we used to play
with water pistols?
Then peashooters
and now real guns.
You're such a sharpshooter.
Impressive!
What is it?
You're the heir of cheung lok.
And your sister has your back.
So what's wrong?
You look down on me now?
Why would you think that?
I'm just telling you the truth.
Every shot must have its purpose.
She's always the boss.
She's just telling me
what I can and can't do.
How can I make it big?
Because you were born too late.
Honestly.
I told you.
You should be independent.
It's not easy.
Is it that hard?
If you don't try it.
You have nothing.
If you dare to dream.
It's all possible.
You seem to be,
doing well.
What have you been up to?
Just small business.
You wouldn't dare do it.
I sell heroin.
What's there to be afraid of?
If we do this,
we can be the biggest game in town.
Wan chai district is under our control.
We can sell on bar street.
The bars are always busy.
Good.
We'll be partners.
Count me in.
Are you out of your mind?
Partners?
If your sister finds out,
she'll chop me up and feed me to the dogs.
Besides,
don't mess with chiu kam fu.
I won't man.
There's no way.
Leave my sister to me.
I'll sort it out.
As for fu,
if you can't.
I will.
Good!
We're brothers.
You got my back
and I have your back.
We're partners now.
We'll make money together!
Here's to us.
Cheers!
Hey!
This is rent for the month.
I told you I would pay.
Keep it and buy some candy for your son.
Buy it yourself.
Always so much pride.
Hey!
I heard you used to practise
orthodox wing chun.
You challenged ip man but
he refused to fight.
That's something.
I want to challenge ip man.
Why did you close your dojo?
I didn't want to teach anymore.
Didn't want to teach?
You were at the top of the game.
Let me see what you got.
Let's have a go.
I don't remember.
Quit playing.
How about...
The loser has to take the money.
Punching from mid air is
such a stupid mistake.
I like somersaults.
What's it to you?
I'm a grown man,
no one has ever slapped me before.
How dare you!
You like to fight.
I'm disciplining you on
behalf of your parents.
Asshole!
Again?
You swore.
You deserved it.
Can you fight me properly?
Don't slap me.
Why don't you use wing chun?
I don't need wing chun now.
Can't you show me some respect?
I'll have you fired!
Money's yours.
Hey! Keep it a secret!
Don't tell anyone.
Don't tell anyone you beat me.
Nothing left.
This is still intact.
The music box.
Julial
that's not how you do it.
Let me show you.
You're pretty good.
Did your father teach you?
He used to teach me wing chun.
But not anymore.
Julia,
I can teach you wing chun.
Really?
Yes.
Well then thank you shifu!
See if this is right.
Sorry!
I'm so sorry!
It's alright.
Sorry...
I'l fix it.
I only use it to hang clothes.
Let's go.
Fung, I used to check out the balcony.
What's out there?
The sunrise.
Sunrise?
More like moon rise.
When the lights come on over bar street,
that's my sunrise.
When the lights come on,
I'm able to forget all the
unhappy things in my life.
You're easy to please.
You can be so...
So simple!
Happiness should be simple.
If I can do the things I like every day,
I'll be very happy.
What do you think I like to do?
Eat?
That means he thinks you're dumb.
He's talking about you.
Papa, who are you talking about?
You, of course!
Two adults bullying a kid!?
You're not really angry.
What makes me happy.
Is being at gold bar every day,
singing and dancing.
That's how I can show my talent.
When you find the place where you belong,
win or lose,
you won't want to leave.
I don't think that's true.
Whether I come or go,
is a matter of choice.
Well it might be a choice
that you made in a fit of anger.
And when you calm down you'll realize that,
you left that day, so you
could return one day.
Dad, I finally got my steak!
Fung. It's your belated birthday party.
Eat as much as you like.
I'll take you up on that!
Brother.
Just cause he's buying, don't pig out
thanks for inviting us.
It's my pleasure.
Actually,
I should thank all of you.
I barged into your lives.
Yet you all greeted me with open arms.
And took such good care of fung.
I'm very honored to have friends like you.
Here. A toast to you!
Who said we were friends?
On bar street,
we're all family.
Here. Cheers!
Happy birthday!
This is for you.
Wow! It's black bat.
I volunteer at an orphanage.
A child there made that for me.
Mr. Davidson,
thanks for the arrangements,
and the beautiful cake.
You are very welcome.
I have other guests to attend to.
So, excuse me. Have a wonderful time.
- Thank you!
- Bye bye!
Good evening everyone and welcome.
Our humble organization,
strives to stimulate the Hong Kong economy,
but we also want to give
back to the community.
So tonight's proceeds for
our charity auction,
will go towards rebuilding homes destroyed
in the recent typhoons.
There we can show everyone
how big our hearts are
and how deep our pockets are.
And our first item up for bid is this
beautiful antique qing dynasty vase.
The bidding will start at $5,000.
$10,000!
$12,000!
$15,000!
$20,000!
$100,000!
That's a lot of money!
Anyone else?
Sold!
To this very generous lady, will you
please come and introduce yourself?
I'd like to thank the merchant association
for this opportunity.
On behalf of cheung lok company,
we extend our Sincere wishes to
the victims of the typhoon
and urge everyone here
tonight to give generously.
Cheung lok's a triad gang!
You're using dirty money for charity.
It'll be a curse for the victims.
Doing business with a gangster?
If we let her in,
we'd be condoning their evildoing.
We cannot accept money
from organized crime.
Yes, absolutely...
You... please leave.
You're not welcome here.
Yes, you're not welcome.
Get out...
Please! Everyone. Please calm down!
Miss,
I must apologize,
but a merchant association
is a collective body,
and I must respect the
wishes of all my members.
Since there is some objection
to your background,
I'm afraid we can only accept
your generosity in spirit.
I do apologize.
I haven't always made an honest living,
I admit that.
But take a good hard look at yourselves.
You are not so different, you lie,
you cheat, you exploit.
Are you willing to admit that?
I didn't think so.
Excuse us.
Where's it from?
It's...
Speak.
The guy who runs his street,
his name is fat lung.
Go
In the back!
Wow.
Whoa. Look at that!
Wow brother.
We made a killing
on chiu kam fu's turf!
Amazing!
I must hand it to you.
You've got nerve!
Chiu kam fu is nothing.
He's no tiger, just a sick kitty.
Exactly!
Take this!
Unload this!
Tso sai kit is peddling drugs.
You must tell your brother.
This will be tricky.
He's indebted to his sister.
I'm afraid there's nothing he can do.
This is the last one.
Mr. Davidson! Hi!
Here I am!
Mr. Davidson,
nice to meet you.
He is my buddy.
Kit is the boss of cheung lok,
a big, big gang in Hong Kong.
With him on board, we make money more...
You take a look!
Triple!
I only work with the best people.
There's only one steak.
Who's eating?
Boss,
don't play me!
This steak is huge.
We can... we can share.
What are you doing?
You think it's the first time
I've had a gun to my head?
Your bullets are for
target practice, asshole!
Just like you said.
Every shot must have its purpose.
This shot is worth everything.
I guess your sister is right.
You're nothing but a loser.
If you kill me, it will be your loss.
Really?
So many people could take your place.
I admire you. People like you
are destined for great things.
I would have worked with you
even if you hadn't killed him.
Sit, eat.
Cheung tin chi.
What do you think of my calligraphy?
"Martial arts is the righteous path"
you train your mind with martial arts.
But you're not calm.
You have not practised in a while.
Over the years,
I've looked after the business.
My hands, held a saber
and they were stained with blood.
It's been a while since I used a brush.
And now, that I want to straight.
I realized that doing the right thing
is even more difficult.
Taking your father's place as a woman
couldn't have been easy.
But with determination,
anything is possible.
I underestimated you by thinking
you're only a good martial artist.
I'm sure you didn't stop by today
just to have a chat
tso sai kit's dealing drugs on bar street.
What will you do about it?
I want you to stop him.
It's not that simple. Let me deal with him.
I will need some time.
Fine.
I will wait.
Let me help you.
My old drug addiction.
Left me with all these problems.
I know that it wasn't
easy to kick the habit.
Take it one day at a time.
Even though I can stand the cravings,
I'm afraid someday,
I'll be tempted by it again.
We're just like sister.
Through thick and thin.
You know that we'll manage.
You must have faith in yourself.
Waiter,
another?
Make it a double!
Hey! Excuse me!
Check please!
Thank you, boss!
Good... one more...
I can't...
I really can't.
Good... that's my girl! One more?
Hey boss! She stole from us!
Kit I didn't... I didn't steal anything!
How dare you try and steal from me.
I didn't... I didn't steal from you
I didn't steal from you.
What's your hurry?
You going to report me?
No! I wouldn't... I wouldn't dare
I wouldn't dare... I don't know anything
I don't know...
Good girl!
You deserve a nice reward don't you?
Give me a bag.
Fu will make you pay for this!
I'm tso sai kit! I'm not
scared of that fool!
Grab her!
So you mean you haven't
been here in 2 months?
Yeah, that's right!
Hey! Where's Nana?
Ok, I'll find her.
Hey! Have a drink lady! Come on!
Nana. Nana!
I didn't take the drugs.
I really...
I know.
I know, Nana.
Nana...
Anyone there?!
Please help me!
That is the wrong move.
No sis. It was the right move.
Each time you screwed up,
father made you kneel right in here
in this room all night,
to reflect.
Every time, I'd sneak in here
and played Chinese checkers with you.
To keep you company.
Remember that?
Sure I do.
Actually,
I really hate Chinese checkers.
Because they remind me,
of my mistakes and punishment.
So?
Did you ask me here
to punish me again?
Everything I do is for your own good.
You used to listen to me.
Why have we drifted apart so much?
Because I listened to you!
So everyone looked down on me.
To them,
I'm just your kid brother.
They don't even know my name
is tso sai kit.
But,
starting today,
I don't need you.
Get in here!
Sai kit,
drugs are out of your league.
You can't handle it.
Give it up!
But this path.
Is what I have chosen.
Tso sai kit!
Come out!
Kill him!
You get him!
Leave!
You promised to give me time.
It's too late.
Drugs are already killing
people on bar street.
Step aside sister!
Sai kit!
Come on!
Your kung fu is useless!
Fight my gun with your fist!
Come get me!
His arm
is a peace offering.
Miss kwan!
An arm can't make up for a life!
If you don't drop the matter.
I'll raze bar street to the ground.
We won't take his life.
But what about the drugs?
We must settle this.
Where are the drugs hidden?
There's no going back after this.
Any regrets?
I gave up martial arts to open a bar.
So I could live a quiet life.
I always remind myself,
to exercise restraint.
But after all these years,
trouble still comes knocking.
I once thought that
my martial arts could make me famous.
I even used it to make a living
as a fighter for hire.
But I really just wanted a simple life.
I thought I could put
martial arts behind me.
But deep down,
I know I never could.
Those of us who fight
never understood the true
meaning of martial arts.
You challenged ip man.
You sure know the true
meaning of martial arts.
Cheung tin chi,
I think you're pretty good.
I fought ip man. Behind closed doors.
I lost.
How'd you lose?
By just one move.
By one move? And you gave it all up?
Do you realize
that martial arts, isn't about winning?
Then why did you make
me fight you last time?
Because I needed to teach you manners.
I wanted to punch you for ages!
All of Hong Kong have heard about this now.
I've been ordered to
clamp down on narcotics.
I can't protect you anymore.
For the time being,
take your merchandise elsewhere.
Lay low for a bit.
Hong Kong is ruled by the British empire.
Can't have a Chinese hero running around.
Today is one person, tomorrow...
An entire uprising.
How will you keep order?
How will I do business?
Now, anyone who raises a fuss,
you do what I pay you for.
Cheers!
Quick! Move it!
Get in! Police check!
Turn off the music.
Men on one side, women on the other.
Over there!
You, move it!
Over there, quick!
Over there!
We received a tip.
Someone here is dealing drugs.
We need to search the bar.
Quiet!
Fai sir,
I run a legitimate business.
Is this necessary?
The gweilo's in charge.
This isn't a joke.
Just cooperate.
Sir, heroin!
Asshole!
You set me up!
He's been implicated in
the dealing of narcotics.
Arrest him.
Take him away.
He said you're dealing drugs.
And to arrest you.
Take him away!
Stay where you are.
Fu...
Don't move!
If you give us trouble!
We'll arrest everyone!
God damn police!
Tin chi...
Don't move!
Police?
Right?
You called arson an accident.
Someone was murdered in gold bar.
You did nothing.
You let the real drug dealers go free
and planted evidence to
frame an innocent man.
What kind of police is that?
I don't know anything about a set up.
We do our job
and follow orders.
You can't tell right from wrong!
Where's your conscience?
I have nothing to hide
and a clear conscience.
He's caught red-handed,
why can't we arrest him?
Stop!
I'm the owner of gold bar.
I don't need you to get involved.
Whatever happens,
I take responsibility.
Don't make trouble.
Let him go. He wouldn't sell drugs!
Don't worry.
I'll be home for breakfast.
Nothing to see. Step back!
Put him in the car.
You two, take your teams
and search the other bars.
Yes, sir!
Nothing to see. Just go back inside.
Nothing to see! Leave!
Move!
Enjoy yourself, I will wait outside.
It was you the generous - philanthropist!
Let it sit for 5 minutes,
and it will be perfect.
Ready to eat.
I prefer my fried beef and tomatoes.
Who wants your bloody steak?
But you should enjoy your last meal.
And if I want you to eat, you will eat.
Chinese don't have options.
Every person has the right to choose.
I chose to open a bar and
you chose to sell drugs.
Right?
And you choose to stick your nose
into others people's business.
You chose wrong.
And now you have to die.
My mistake was
I just found out that
you're a son of a bitch!
The steak would have been perfect by now.
And you wasted it.
The police said.
Fu tried to escape from custody
and was killed when he fell down a cliff.
I don't believe it...
Miss kwan,
the car is ready.
I have somewhere to go first.
You can't go.
Get out of my way.
Nana is dead.
My brother is dead.
But that foreigner is alive and well.
The police know everything
and yet they did nothing at all!
They won't do anything!
You don't need to do anything.
I will do it for you.
Papa,
you have to come back.
Fung,
there is something,
papa has to take care of.
But I promise,
I'll come back soon.
Papa,
I want congee and fried
breadsticks tomorrow.
Wait here.
After we leave Hong Kong,
we'll start over.
Hey!
Mr. cheung?
How can I help you?
You forgot this.
Don't make crazy accusations,
that's not mine.
What about this?
So what now, Mr. cheung?
I can fix it.
You Chinese think too highly of yourself.
Always wanting to be the hero.
Hasn't anyone told you.
That heroes die quickly?
I'm sorry!
Papa is going to be fine.
Because he's my black bat.
He'll defeat the bad guys.
Because he's the best.
I didn't come here to be a hero.
I came here to beat you.
Wing chun,
cheung tin chi.
Move! Step aside!
What's this?
Who's making a scene?
Leave!
Leave! There's nothing more to see
He has assaulted this person
and damaged his property.
Arrest him.
We're charging you for assault
and damaging property.
You're under arrest.
He's the head of a drug ring.
His car is in the back, loaded with drugs.
He's the one you should arrest,
not me.
I only see that you've
intentionally attacked him
and are trying to frame him.
He said
you not only assaulted this person,
but framed him.
We must arrest you.
Cuff him!
This is outrageous!
They were both fighting,
why only arrest one?
Why don't you arrest the drug dealer?
Did he pay you?
I don't know what you are talking about.
I'm just here to keep the peace.
You're all accused of an illegal assembly
and disrupting public order.
Go home now! There's nothing more to see.
I'll arrest you all.
You...
Beat them up!
Beat those dogs!
In the car behind the restaurant.
We found all these drugs!
We have witnesses and evidence.
He's a drug dealer!
What are you doing?
I'm being a policeman.
You covered up for him.
Arrest him!
Even you want to cover for him?
Take your hands off of me!
I'm your commanding officer.
Good, that's right...
You haven't got the authority to do this!
Let go of me!
Take him! Yes sir!
I'll speak to the commissioner.
He's getting away!
Papa,
Bullying people again?
What? You want more?
I told you my papa is the
master of wing chun.
We should learn wing chun.
Yes. Wing chun is awesome.