Dear citizens
North Korea's bombing
in Burma is...
North Korea bombed
the mausoleum of Aung San
in an attempt to assassinate
President Chun Doo-hwan
20 armed spies
came in the East Sea
1 captured, 11 committed suicide
Explosives and guns
were discovered
The couple has a 5 year-old son
in Pyongyang
They named him Revolution
to take over South Korea
Chairman Hwang of
the Supreme People's Assembly
was targeted by
well-trained spies from the North
they disguised as relatives
and approached Hwang
The Spy
Incheon Port
North Korean Foreign Minister,
Lee Yong-sung will soon arrive
During the Six-Party Talks
in Beijing last February...
I brought them last time
We can't let this through
But this is okay!
Lee Yong-sung has landed
in South Korea
On April 11th,
Minister Lee and his aid
requested asylum
to the Korean Embassy in Beijing
He arrived at Seoul Airport
today at 1 p.m.
His 34 days journey here
opens new hopes for reunification
Yes?
Let's meet in an hour
Show me the goods first
Try biting on it
This really gets it up?
Sir, the Chinese hate losing
to the Americans
This is 8 times stronger
than the original
But the wrong stuff
could give you heart attacks
Come on!
Who cares about that?
We want to get it up
big and strong
- Live it up while you can?
- Damn right!
$50,000 for all this then?
Does is say 'idiot'
on my face?
Fine. $55,000
An idiot, all right
Damn idiot!
What?
Not you
I'm talking about me
I do this when I'm mad
Don't mind me
You stupid idiot!
Stop living like that!
You idiot!
Die! You idiot!
Die!
Then $60,000?
You're on!
Where's the money?
Man...
- Come on
- Oh please!
Boss!
How was your trip?
You're back earlier than
expected
What's wrong, Ms. Ko?
Are you sick?
No, sir
I'll be right back
A friend's here
What'd you say to her
this time?
Nothing...
Is it her period?
Why you!
I told you to be good to her!
Know how hard she has it?
She pays for
her sisters' schooling
and takes care of
her sick mother
Who does that these days?
Many kids are like that
Where's the Viagra?
What Viagra?
Sell this cooking oil!
It's rotting!
But no one wants it
You good for nothing ass!
Go plant some hair, will you!
Son of a bitch!
The smell!
Wife
- Hon?
- Where are you?
Just got back
How's Ji-sung?
On the bench
That damn coach!
The game's almost over
I'll be right there!
Coach?
I'm not saying this
because Dong-su's my son
But if he keeps playing like this
I think we can win it!
No problem!
Right?
How about a toast!
- Coach?
- Sure
Go Yeok-buk!
- Go Yeok-buk!
- Go!
Stop drinking!
Great day, isn't it?
Wish I could say so
I'm sick and tired of
seeing benches
Damn this life
I'm just curious
Do you hate me or something?
Of course not
I get it
Ji-sung will play next game
Promise?
Of course!
He's our secret weapon
He is? Really?
We should save
our secret weapon
Maybe for the finals!
Right! Save him for last!
To secret weapons!
Sir? What's this?
Give it a try
It'll stay up for 8 hours
Oh!
Smoking in
a non-smoking place
Bastards!
You know?
Some folks pay to play
baseball?
- Really?
- Yes
Some people
They have no shame
Got a lot of money?
Not coming out right?
I heard of some men
getting menopause
Sit down and take your time
in there
Damn!
Come out, already!
Get on mommy's back
Carry Ji-su and go on in
I want to chat with Ji-sung
About what?
Guys talk
Ladies can go in first
Clean the bathroom
as soon as you come in
I did it last time!
Even the kitchen!
So? You're gonna skip it
this week?
Of course not
Go on in
Let's go in Ji-su
I talked with your coach today
He has a good plan
What plan?
Ji-sung
You're a secret weapon
- I am?
- Yes!
The coach is smarter than
he looks
He'll use me in the finals
as a secret weapon?
Exactly!
Let's see you swing
Shoulders back
Weight on your right foot
Eyes open wide!
Firm grasp!
And swing!
No! More impact!
Give me that
Eyes open wide!
The ball is coming!
Keep your eye on the ball!
Grasp tight!
Swing!
Not too hard. Got it?
I'll be right in after a smoke
Get the bat and go
Ji-sung!
- Go! Secret weapon!
- Go!
Mama?
Did you eat?
Did you, Mama?
Just smacked down a bowl
What's with the cough?
Just a cold
You be careful
Mama!
Jung-su! Can't hear me?
Mama! Mama!
Mama...
The moon's so bright
Real name, Lim Jung-su
Graduated from Kim Jong-il University
and sent to spy in 1989
He caught our attention
during the 2008 US beef protests
The candlelight protests? How?
He said he led it
and asked for operational funds
That fool!
He's a con-man, not a spy!
He runs a small trade shop
He goes back and forth
between China for goods
His code name is Mr. Kim
He's just working hard
to make a living
Nothing happened in China?
He wired some money
to his family in the North
Well, life is hard there
Supporting his family up North
and here
He's got it rough
If he didn't do anything
in 3 years
maybe he lost touch
with the North?
That's enough
Just arrest him
Something big is bound
to happen, sir
What if it doesn't?
You'll take responsibility?
If it doesn't...
then too bad
It's not my fault
Yes?
So bring him in now
Or you're responsible!
Understood?
Yes, sir
Son of a bitch!
I'm planting hair with this!
Report me if you can!
That son of a bitch!
If I catch you, you're dead!
Please record your message
Koo! You dare run
with my money!
You screwed the wrong guy
Know who I am! Fool!
I got special training!
I could rip you up
with my bare hands!
Bring the money
when you can
Or it'll be 3 generations
of hell for your family!
Message recorded
- Hello?
- Where are you?
What now?
Why're you cranky?
I'm not cranky!
What's up?
- They raised our rent
- What!
Again? Why's it always going up
like rockets!
How much more?
- $30,000 down payment
- What!
You said things went well
in China
Okay
I'll come home and...
Talk later!
Hey!
Stop! Stop!
Come back!
Anything happen
after he came back from China?
Koo ran off with money
Koo?
The bald bastard?
I knew it!
Sir, he's harmless
Let's drop this
No! He's our lotto ticket!
Trust me!
Just you wait
Something big will go down soon
About to lose hideout
due to soaring rent
Urgent request for $30,000
to secure hideout
I'm not lying
Don't trust your husband?
It's no time to be drunk!
I didn't drink!
Come home, now!
Okay! Okay!
Late again?
- Drinking again?
- No, kid
Give me my smokes
You should quit
It's bad for you
Whatever!
Do I smell like beer?
Say, 'Ah'
Ice cream and chocolate
work best to cover that
Really?
$2.50, please
Give me money!
Hurry!
Move!
That bastard!
I don't believe this
What's with today?
Damn it!
Who are you!
I didn't get my change...
I bought ice cream and...
Stop!
Hold on
Stay back!
Where's my 50 cents?
I'll kill you!
Hold on
Think I'll stab you with this?
Did I get it or not?
I can't remember
Hold on
Look, I got it!
You nuts?
Fuck you!
Shit!
Damn, I pulled a muscle
You okay?
Just one favor
You don't know me
Some stranger helped you
then left. Got it?
Yes
Call the cops
You don't know me! Okay?
Or I'll be mad!
Okay
Am I fired?
It kills me to do this
I'll give you a severance
I'm sorry
That guy is our lotto ticket!
I can't go on any longer
Mom is bed-ridden
and tuition keeps going up
I should just drink poison
and die
Don't say stuff like that!
If you want, I'll go quietly
Damn it!
It'll be rough
you okay with that?
My whole life was rough
Peonies Bloomed!
- What the fuck!
- Pardon?
I wasn't talking to you
I know you had it rough
Of course...
Well, then
Get back to work
- Go on
- Yes, sir
Peonies Bloomed!
The press conference for
Minister Lee's asylum will begin
I came to stop a war
Though the people are starving,
North Korea is preparing for war
I'll join our brother country
to try and stop it
That's why I came here
Instead of the money I asked,
damn peonies bloomed?
Today 4:00 p.m.
General Yi, Gwanhwamun
They'll refuse the talks
The Six-Party Talks is...
North Korea's scheme
to buy time
Buy time for what?
How many nuclear weapons
does North Korea have?
That concludes
the press conference
Excuse me
Can you take a picture for me?
Are you from China?
No, Taiwan
Thank you
October, 2001
The guest has arrived
He's here
Kwon: Kim Jong-Il’s nephew
escaped North 10 years ago
Currently a researcher
at National Defense
His wife is with him
We can't do it
Chief!
Not the woman!
Dear?
What is it?
Damn traitor!
Dug up all that water
just to make this?
They never leave things be
- You gained weight
- What? I guess
Looks way better than
being gaunt
- Mr. Kim?
- Yes
They want his head
Lee Yong-Sung
Gather up the gang
and rent an office
Your son's name is
Ji-sung, right?
He needs to relax his shoulders
Tell him to swing smoothly
I'm off
Get an office with this?
What a joke!
When did that guy come over?
Just my damn luck!
Excuse me
Know where a famous restaurant
called Gooksu is around here?
It's across the street
to the right
Welcome!
Where have you been?
- Mrs. Wang
- Yes?
- How've you been?
- Good
Why didn't you come by?
Found a new favorite place?
I wouldn't do that to you
I went to Europe
Really? Where?
Counselor Yoon
Spy for 40 years
We'll catch up later
- Reservation under Mr. Kim?
- Yes
So many years have passed
The good old days
Back then
we had conviction and pride
being spies
Right
Willing to give our lives
for reunification
You too, right?
That's history
Now, I'm busy making a living
Do they send money down
these days?
Up to 3 years ago,
they sent a little
Now, things aren't the greatest
up there
Nothing for us to do now
All the info is on the internet
Right...
They bad-mouth their President
more than Kim Jong-il
President Park's time was best
Indeed it was
Those were the days
The peonies bloomed
Lovely flowers
Peonies bloomed
What?
Who came down?
It's Chief Choi
We're in for a bloody massacre
This is a steal deal!
They're redeveloping the area
Big high-rises will go up
I'll call right back
It's $100 short
For what?
0.3% realtor's fee
Want a copy of
real estate law?
Who takes that these days?
That's why you got no customers
Son! How are you?
Mommy will call right back
Hey!
Wait!
Pay up the $100!
What are you a thief?
Why you!
Your rumors are true!
That you'd do anything
for money!
Want a piece of me?
Fine, bitch!
Your hubby came
with money, too!
You little bitch!
Ow! That hurts!
- Pay the $100
- Okay! I'll pay!
Ms. Kang
spy for 15 years
Crazy bitch!
Closed
What is it?
The peonies bloomed
So what?
Peonies bloomed!
I can't!
I'm busy!
I am too!
I'm seriously busy
Raising my kid and making money
This is insane!
No husband?
Help me out just once?
Please?
You help me!
I'm cash-strapped, too
Think I want to do this?
Forget it!
Chief Choi came down
Shit! Just say I died!
Shit
We all have it hard
Think she can get away
from Choi saying she's dead?
She scared me
She was so pretty back then
Must be hard being
a single mom
It's hard for me, too
Wife wants money for rent
Mom wants money
for my sister's wedding
Why was I born a man?
She's getting married?
Congratulations
No need
It just costs me money
Who's next?
Mr. Woo
- Mr. Woo?
- Yes
The revolutionist?
What's he up to?
With American farm products
our cows will all die!
Stop killing our cows!
Incompetent government!
- Go away!
Come on, Chang-sik!
Stop it!
Think you're James Bond?
Get that away, now!
Put it away!
Go away! FTA
Go way! FTA!
Stop killing farmers!
Charge!
We can't raise cows like this!
Where's the democracy!
Mr. Woo
spy for 13 years
Said you'd burn
for reunification
I did?
Said you'd free our country
from Americans!
When?
Shouldn't have neglected me
They don't even get rid of
cows like that
Why'd you come
after ditching me?
Don't ask me
Go spill your heart out
to Chief Choi
Who cares!
Dying is just the same
Then, who'll raise the cows?
How much is a cow?
The feed costs $3,000
But a cow sells for $500!
Cut it out!
Chief Choi is here!
You know him!
Is Ms. Kang coming?
Of course she is!
What do you think of FTA?
Everyone's got it so rough
Why the hell did Lee
come down for!
Was there something between
Woo and Kang?
You didn't know?
They were a couple
Really? Did they do it?
Do what?
- Did they do it or not?
- I don't know!
- Why not do it?
- Ask them yourself!
It's me! Woo
Remember me?
How's it been?
No. No
What were you up to!
Did you forget about me?
Did you!
Damn it!
Long time no see
No. No
It's been long
Been a long time!
It's been a long time!
How have you been?
Yes! Okay!
It's been a while
Greet each other, will you?
You two go way back
You know? Like this?
Been okay?
What's with your accent?
What's with your body?
It happens
when women have babies
It's been so long
Good to see you
How've you been?
You all look well
This is all I could get
for the money
We're not having a party
This will do
It's great
If I gave you much money,
I could pick faults
But since I couldn't,
I have no right to say anything
I heard how you comrades
were living
You've worked hard
to survive here
Our country has never forgotten
all your hard work
Please keep doing your best
Our mission is to kill
Lee Yong-sung
You know how things run here
Our expertise is killing
So, you set things up
May l?
I'm quite old now
I'd like to go back home
after this mission
Is that possible?
You'll go back with us
Thank you!
Woo has a question
I do?
About the pay?
- Damn bastards!
- How much do you want?
It's okay. Tell me
How much do you want?
Long live the Democratic People's
Republic of Korea!
Long live General Kim Jong-il!
That's good
There's never been a more
vicious dictator!
He claims communism
but we all know very well!
It's Kim Jong-il, the fat pig's
dictatorship!
Destroy him!
- Congratulations
- For what?
Heard you got married
and have a kid
Don't mind my business
and get to work
How could you do that to me?
Why'd you disappear?
Shit!
Long time no see
Senator Park!
How've you been?
Did you go home safely then?
You were really drunk
Do I know you?
Chairman Choi!
Pastor! Nice bumping into you
How was your trip
to Washington?
Great. I got
Senator Robert Palmer's promise
So, the States will help?
Professor Hwang?
Who are you?
I'm a reporter
from Seoul Daily
May I interview you?
I see
Then, he is only staying
in his hideout?
Because they'll try
and kill him
When he is so sick
Damn commies!
Is he sick?
I heard he has heart trouble
But
You didn't receive as much
attention as Minister Lee
Why do you think that is?
I came solely for
a better future for my country
He had a different motive
What's that?
Money?
What money?
He got paid for coming over
Obviously, he needs to make
a living
Think he'd come for free?
Must've made a deal
How much did he get?
$10 million U.S.
$10 million?
That much?
Ms. Kang?
Right
Lee has heart trouble
He received monthly checkups
in the North
But he can't go to
a hospital here
He can't walk around in public
Knowing he could get killed
So, a doctor visits him
regularly?
Our first plan is to follow
the doctor and find the hideout
Get your guns
Grease them up ahead of time
You didn't bring any?
We came by plane
Sorry, sir
Son
Must be hard
raising him alone
It's okay, sir
Is that good?
Let me try it
I've never tasted coffee
Bitter, but nice
A successful son drinking coffee...
Your mother must be proud
We have one week
to kill Lee. Understood?
Yes, sir
You brushed your teeth?
Such a big boy, now
Mommy will come
this Saturday
Must be nice
Coming by plane
When we came by subs, right?
I swam over
What happened to
Kang's husband?
She got divorced
You should know
You set them up
You did?
Damn fool still lost in love?
Snap out of it
What?
He's lost in love, alright
I am not!
I'm a Casanova!
Yeah, whatever
Wash up, will you?
- You smell like shit
- Quiet
Where'd you put your gun?
I buried it in the mountains
Mt. Gwangmyeong
Damn it!
- Mister?
- Yeah?
Where'd the mountain go?
Gone to build apartments
Shit! That's why
this country sucks!
Damn it!
Our guest is here
I'm sorry
Honey?
You left this at home
See you later
Let's start with a blood test
What's going on?
Doctor!
Are you okay?
I'm so sorry
What's the matter with him?
My father insists
he can't get a blood test
Why?
Because he's
a Jehovah's Witness
I'm sorry
Have a good day
Go straight,then turn right
Where would all that money be?
Think he used it all?
How can that old man
use it all?
Unless he had a family
Sure he brought
the money here?
You said Professor Hwang
said that!
But it's not like he saw him
get the money
I searched through the internet
He got the money for sure!
Stupid? You believe that?
Idiot! Remember
the beef protests?
Mad Cow disease was
all over the Net
Internet is the Alpha
and Omega now
It's all made-up
The beef is cheap and good!
Hey! Go that way!
Use your head, will you!
You little twerp!
How dare you raise your voice!
You country moron!
Damn woman!
Gone mad after eating mad cows?
Crazy bitches deserve
a spanking!
Go ahead! Hit me!
You disrespectful little twerp!
I'm older!
Talk with respect!
Fine then!
Must be nice being old!
With wrinkles and sagging tits!
Who says!
They're as firm as rock!
Cut it out!
Focus on the money!
They did it, alright!
This is it?
Nice house
How much is a place like this?
This is why
we have nothing to do
In the past we went up
mountains to take pics
We climbed a lot
Here
496-24 Pyeongchang-dong
See how many surveillance cams
and infrared detectors there are
21 surveillance cams
and 1 1 detectors
Can we see inside?
No technology for that yet
Unless we actually go inside
Then, let's go in
Thank you for calling
How may I help you?
Our technician will visit
your house soon
- Your address, please
- Hello
Your ID, please
Come in
Now, let's go in
4 surveillance cams here
and 3 in the kitchen
The front door is the only way
in and out
There are 6 guards on watch
24 hours on the first floor
They are carrying Beretta 93 guns
at all times
That's the study
Mostly books on South Korean
politics and economy
Must be reading up
to settle down
But reality is far from books
Could wonder why
he came to live here
28 stairs to the second floor
The wooden stairs creak,
so be careful
The upstairs guards' room
is used for sleeping
So, the guards take turn
on shifts
Thus, there are always 1 2 agents
on guard here
Is there internet in there?
No. That's everything
Must be the terminal board
That must be Lee's bedroom
where the doctor comes out
Now, here's the plan
It'll be hard to sneak in
with the 24 hour watch
There are power lines
all around the neighborhood
Thus, the electric pole!
We cut the electricity
and sneak in
But we only have 3 minutes
The independent power generator
will kick in after 3 minutes
We go upstairs to Lee's room,
kill him, then get out in 3 minutes
It's a race against time
Every Thursday at 3:00 a.m.
the garbage truck comes
So, we disguise as such
and go up to the house
32 to seconds to go over the fence
and get to the door
17 seconds from the door
to the stairs
28 stairs at 0.5 seconds each
That's 14 seconds
From up the stairs
to the room, 1 2 seconds
9 seconds to go into
Lee's room and kill him
84 seconds to go in
for the kill
84 seconds to come out
Thus
It'll take 2 minutes 48 seconds
to go in and come out
Kang get a garbage truck
and Woo go up the pole
Why me?
I can go up in 8 seconds
The counselor and I will guide
Just come out
within 3 minutes, Chief
Vanish into the darkness
before the generator kicks in
Got your guns?
What?
Well...
A cow stepped on mine
It's broken
I have a gun,
but I lost the bullets
I buried it in the mountains,
but the mountain's gone
Damn too many apartments
these days
I'm sorry
I left it somewhere
Are you okay?
Counselor!
You smiled?
Comrade! Wanna die!
Son of a bitch!
'Sorry' is that easy to say?
Are you okay?
Thank you...
If a meal is set
we can't flip the table
because there's no spoon
Thank you
It's for our country
Don't kill him
Let's all live! So you can
make it back to your families!
Right, Mr. Kim?
Yes...
I'll get it
Enough with the money!
I'll sell my organs
if I have to!
That damn bastard!
Hitting you like that
I deserved it
Thanks
Saw the safe
under the desk?
People don't put
black money in banks
The $10 million is
definitely in that safe
Get killed by yourself!
Think of the cows!
What's $1 0 million
divided by 4?
$2.5 million
We hit the jackpot!
$2.5 million each!
Think about it
Our lives are at stake anyway
Let's get paid
Who needs a medal later?
Kang? What do you say?
Think of your son
Let's go!
What about you?
Think of the cows
Let's go!
Now you're talking
Counselor Yoon?
Me?
I have some money saved up
But if you guys want it,
I think it'll be fun
I knew you'd pull through!
Now
If Choi's got 3 minutes,
we do it in 2 minutes 20 seconds
Get everything ready
while I go to Busan with Choi
We go straight for the money
A toast
- To success!
- Success!
Brought the money?
When is the meeting?
3 hours from now
The sea is nice
- It's the same
- Okay!
48 seconds to get to the safe
Minus 64 seconds to get out
Then, we have 44 seconds
to open the safe
Width, 49
Height, 57
Length, 51
How much?
$1 0 million!
That's not right!
Paint it evenly!
- This is all wrong!
- I can do this!
You don't get it!
Stop it! I'll do it!
- Why you!
- Fool!
It's been a while, Ms. Ma
How's business?
Getting by in the shitty economy
like everyone else
Still dealing Viagra?
What are you talking about?
I don't deal with that stuff
What the hell?
Last time, you asked me to...
Cut the nonsense
and show us the goods
They want to see the goods
Tell them to show the money first
The gentlemen want
to see the money
Who'd pay without seeing the goods?
Don't trust us?
Think we'd just take the cash and run?
There's an old Russian saying
Befriend a bear
but always keep an ax at hand
Did you live in Russia?
In Moscow for a bit
Do you like?
It's the best
Let's see the money
Please...don't...
Damn it!
Yeah?
What? Busan?
Why'd he go?
Probably to catch Koo
Anything else?
Nothing
Shit
Kim's just a con-man!
What?
Crazy son of a...
Eat up
Have some more meat
I brought your favorite
egg and ham
And fried rice
Try this first
Is it good?
Yes! Have some, Mom
How's residence?
Anyone bothering you?
Don't worry
Everyone's great here
I'm sorry Jun-sang
About what?
Everything
You have to go early again?
When this job is over
let's live together
Really?
You don't have to work?
I made a lot of money
Mommy's rich
Then, you can get married!
Silly!
Let's eat, Son
Lee Yong-Sung's Hideout
Ready?
Where's Lee?
Got it?
I'll ask one last time
Where's Lee Yong-sung!
What's this?
What?
What!
- Run!
- Hurry!
- What's wrong!
- Damn it!
It won't start!
Bring the car around!
Where's Counselor Yoon?
Let's go
Hurry up!
What did you do!
Wanna die!
How can this happen!
Where's Lee?
In his room in the basement
Where's the surveillance?
This way, sir
What's that?
They were standing by
6 people
- The old man died?
- Yes
But we didn't kill him
They killed him, sir
This was in his pocket
- Anything else?
- No, sir
Comrade Ahn Byung-jik
Comrade Baek Yeo-jin
Comrade Lim Jung-su
With fattened bellies
don't you get
what's going on?
Step forward
if you don't want in
It was a damn bathroom
You killed comrade Yoon!
Go to his house
and burn up all the evidence
Did they do it?
Do what?
I have some money
But if you guys want it,
I think it'll be fun
I'm quite old now
I'd like to go back home
after this mission
Joo Eun-hae
Can you live without me?
What?
Can you raise the kids
without me?
Are you drunk again?
So what if I am!
Why'd you ditch me?
Then, why didn't you
live well!
Why'd you ditch me
if you can't!
Shit!
So what?
Think it would've
worked out with us?
Why not?
No way in hell
Both parents as spies?
There's no future for us
Still don't get it?
Shit
I'm sorry
So sorry!
Damn loser
Stop it, hon
What'd you just say?
- What?
- Stop it!
- Want a piece of me!
Today's your funeral!
Let go!
Know who the hell I am!
Who cares!
Know who I am?
Who the hell are you!
Bastard! I'm a spy!
I don't believe this
Tattoo it on your forehead
'I'm a spy!'
You'll get yourself killed!
Stand up straight!
Stay up!
Damn fucking life!
That bastard!
I'll kill him
Who? Chief Choi?
That bastard's
out of your league!
If you're a Terrier
he's a Doberman!
Shit
How will you do it?
How will you kill him?
I can't die
You get me?
So focus and kill Lee
if you don't want to die like Yoon
Shit!
When's the last time he came?
He ate a good meal
and gave me a big tip
I'm a little busy
When did he come last?
Wait. Hold on
It was last Wednesday
He came with someone?
He's heading out
An attempted assassination
on Minster Lee took place
We're meeting at the office
in an hour
We must kill him
Keep a distance
Yes, sir
Agent Sang don't lose them
Squad 2, take position
Yes, sir
Being Followed
Walk past
He's going into a building
What happened?
We got him
Mr. Kim
It's so hot
What are you doing here?
I'm in a rush
Catch you later
Lim Jung-su!
Wait
Let's talk
Dong-su loves playing
with Ji-sung
So kind like his mother
who died
How long did you keep watch?
For 3 years
Ms. Ko spotted you
during the beef protests
She's our agent
But her mother's sick
She's a professor of psychology
Pays for her sisters' schooling...
She's an only child
Grew up in a rich family
Her family is loaded!
Now what?
Not like we'll get reunified
by sending you to prison
Right?
What do you want?
When's the next hit on Lee?
You want me to be a rat?
Think of your family
What did they do?
Just trusted
and depended on you
Our country is like that
Get branded as a commie once
and it's forever
For life
You get me?
You'll catch a cold, Sweetie
Sleeping with the bat
I'll do it
But keep your promise
Good decision
I'll get you off
no matter what
I checked
He's agent Han Jung-wook
of National intelligence
We'll be keeping watch
so just act natural
What's up?
Meeting in a place like this
I just came as Choi said
Where's Kang?
Are you sick?
Just indigestion
Get ready
Where's Chief Choi?
Contact point's been changed
All agents move out
Car 1, stay close
Car 2, keep a distance
Car 3, report location
Standing by at point
They turned right
towards Sung-san
Car 1, pull out
Standby on the other side
Went down an alley
Car 2, pull out
Take your positions!
Ready, sir
At 4:00pm today
We're going in to kill Lee
We don't know where he is
How?
Mr. Kim
Tell Han Jung-wook yourself
What? Who do you mean?
Who's that?
Agent Han Jung-wook
of National intelligence!
Don't know?
Huh!
Show him!
What did you talk about
yesterday?
So friendly?
Tell Han we're going in!
If you want to save your son,
you'd better hurry
If Lee's not dead
by the end of the game
Your son will die!
Got that!
You son of bitch!
Call Han now
This is the final game between
Seok and Yeok-buk elementary schools
We will be broadcasting live
Welcome to an exciting matchup
What happened?
Got a tip saying
our location's been exposed
They suspect you?
No
It came from the North
Then, there's a leak
on our end?
There's always a rat somewhere
Has the date been set?
We attack the hideout today
What time?
4:00pm
- How many?
- Got a lighter?
If you pull anything,
it's over for you and your family
I don't care what happens to me
But...
If something happens
to my family
I'll blow up
both countries!
Pull out when you can
I'll tell the agents
in advance
See you later
- It's a hit!
- Looking good!
Going! Going! Gone!
Homerun!
- What a player!
- Yeok-buk Elementary
ties the game 3 to 3
What a close match!
Way to go!
We cancelled
the press conference
We'll escort you to Busan
How long do I have to be
on the run?
Let's go, sir
He is going in a van
A van with plate number 2249
Let's go
30 minutes to the attack
- Be right back
- Hurry Mom
We attack the hideout today
Shit!
Seok Elementary is up to bat
That's it!
The ball count is in his favor
Run!
Get Lee out of there!
Freeze! Or you're dead!
At this rate, we'll all die!
So you betrayed us
to make it alone?
I have to protect my family!
Would you let Jun-sang
live life as a spy's son?
What would you do?
Yeo-jin! Wake up!
Yeo-jin!
Get Lee out of there!
Cover his right!
Hurry! Go!
Protect him!
Run!
Hurry! Run!
Let's not meet again
Keep running!
Go! Go!
Run!
Out of the way!
Drive!
Hurry!
Mister! Wait!
Hey!
Answer the damn phone!
Go right!
What are you doing?
It's over!
It's not over!
Call and cancel your order!
Don't just think of your kid!
Think of our home country!
The hell with all that!
What did you ever do for us!
You and me!
We live and die
upon command!
I was just following orders!
Cut the crap
and make the call!
For our country!
1 out, bottom of the 6th
Here's the pitch!
He's tensed
He needs to believe in himself!
Yeok-buk Elementary is losing
4 to 3 in their last at bat
Hello?
Why didn't you pick up!
Where's Ji-sung?
What?
I can't hear you!
Where's Ji-sung!
Where else? On the bench!
What's with him?
- Strike out!
- Han Dong-su...
- Time!
- I don't understand
I'm the secret weapon
Ji-sung
Get ready to bat
Yes!
Here's the pinch hitter
It's Kim Ji-sung
Ji-sung! It's your brother!
Go secret weapon!
He's a reserve player
Go Ji-sung!
He's a backup player
Can Kim Ji-sung come out on top?
Strike!
Go Ji-sung!
- What a tense moment
- Sure is
One homerun could
turn the game around
Here's the pitch!
Shoulders back
Weight on your right foot
Eyes open wide
The ball is coming!
Keep your eye on the ball!
Grasp the bat tightly!
He's hit!
- Kim Ji-sung is down
- Ji-sung!
I hope it's not a serious injury
Ji-sung! Move!
It's dangerous!
It's daddy!
That's not right
- Is he the father?
- Not sure
Ji-sung!
He looks drunk!
Kim Ji-sung is getting up!
He's running to the mound!
- Stop it!
- This is unbelievable!
All the players are out
on the field!
Ji-sung! Run!
How many years do I get?
Well, there is one way
Instead of going to prison,
how about working for us?
You're asking me to be
a spy for you?
It's the only way you have
for our country
and your family
There was a second attempt
to assassinate Lee Yong-sung
The assassins from North Korea
were all found dead at the scene
Next news
An explosion at a baseball field...
Hello?
Son! How are you?
Mama! I'm fine
Did you eat?
I made chicken soup today
Thinking of you,
I can't bear to eat it
You used to love
my chicken soup
Feels like just yesterday
you'd slurp up a bowl
Did you eat?
Son? Is something wrong?
Nothing's wrong
How are you Mama?
Same old as usual
By chance
did you wire the money?
I'll send it soon
Don't worry
Don't worry about it
Who needs a big wedding anyway?
Damn girl doesn't get
how hard it is for her brother
Did you go see a doctor?
Don't worry. I'm fine
Why don't you go!
Listen to me
and go to the hospital!
Fool!
Why're you yelling!
How dare you yell at Mama!
Come on, Mama!
If you don't want to die,
go see a doctor now!
You fool!
Then, send the money so I can
go to the hospital!
Why always me!
That's it!
Yes! Dong-su!
How're the peonies?
They don't bloom that easily
Sure they didn't?
First time they bloomed
in 1 0 years
Got any money, pal?
You know I saved Dong-su
Get it straight
Your son saved him, not you!
Same difference, man!
Lend me $30 grand?
I'll pay you in 3 months
Yeah?
When?
Okay. Be right there
Shit!
Lee died
Really? How?
Heart attack
I heard he had a bad heart
Too bad
So, they'll announce it soon?
- I guess
- When?
Probably tomorrow
Why?
Just wondering
So cold!
Gotta go
Call if the peonies bloom
In this cold?
- Call me!
- I will!
Take care
Enough homeruns, Son!
Bye!
Ji-sung!
Secret weapon!
Relax your shoulders!
Won over Lee's doctor
Changed Heart Medicine
to Viagra and Lee died
Request Overdue
Operational Fund
Watch it!
Peonies Bloomed!
Damn! Blooming in the winter!
Here's your steak
Wait
What's the beef's ID?
We only use Grade A
American beef
We're leaving
Come on!
It's embarrassing
You still don't get it?
What if Jun-sang goes mad
by eating mad cow?
Please!
I'm warning you
They did it, alright!
Mom? Do you have to go again?
I'll pay you $30,000
Does it say, 'idiot'
on my face?
Come here you!
Where's my money, fool!
I planted hair with it
You son of a bitch!
Let go! Let go!
Cut! That's a wrap!