"Give me your
Press badge! "
"No way.
You're not my dad! "
"Then I shall take it
by force! "
"Oh...
he's my brother!"
"So shall make out
with her. "
So your name is Dan
Yes Dan Quinn.
Like on the resume.
Dan Quinn, born in 1990.
Didn't think that was possible.
Yes, 1990.
People are born every year.
What do you hope to get out
from being in the Mailroom, Dan?
I guess I hope to get out
of 'being' in the Mailroom.
You got 'Saz'.
I like it.
Guess what?
You're hired.
I'm Lemuel Gulliver.
Welcome to the team!
I was hired yesterday
by the HR.
What?
-"Doggie wants a bone".
Floor 30. This is the Editor's floor.
-We're at the epicenter, my friend.
Feel it! Feel it!
-Ok.
Oh, we've got a little
something for you.
Oh, damn it! Sorry about that!
Listen, I will try clean that. Sorry!
Sorry about that.
'Bye.
Just wait a minute.
-Huh?
One second.
It's your mail, sir.
Hey, you're Herald Jones, right?
-Yes.
I love your piece on
"the failures and dreams
of the markets".
Thanks very much.
Look forward to seeing
you around.
And you've been
an inspiration to all
the readers.
Dan, what are you doing?
You CAN'T talk to those guys!
Why not?
-Because, okay...
...this is your first day.
We're the Mailroom guys.
Mailroom guys are meant
to be seen and not heard.
And ideally,
not even seen!
We are not at their level.
We are little people.
You know what it is?
I think you're just scared
talk to them.
I'm not! Listen,
I'm just respectful of
their workspace.
I talk with these people
all the time...
Thanks, I'll let you
know once I made a decision,
Nigel.
Thanks you.
-Thank you.
Good day, fellas!
-Good day mate!
Gulliver!
Got any mail for me?
Yeah .. No. Maybe.
Let me check.
Hi, I'm Dan...
from the Mailroom.
-Darcy.
I will do whatever it takes
to "not" be from the Mailroom.
Doesn't really need to
bother her right now,
she's busy.
You're not really bothering me.
I love every reason to procrastinate.
Yes, me too.
You're not bugging me.
Right, oh, wow...
I'll see you guys later.
-Ok, good to see you!
Let's go!
So, how long did you have
that debilitating crush on the
'travel letter'?
Crush on Darcy?
No way, dude.
Ok, first of all,
you're a terrible liar.
Second of all,
Why didn't you just
ask her out?
Oh, you don't think that
I'm gonna ask her out?
-No.
Dude, I'm gonna ask her out
"whenever" or "wherever"...
... no problem, It just
take me 5 seconds.
"Will you go out with me?"
"Yes"... done!
I'm not going out with
Darcy Silverman.
We're "boyfriend, girlfriend"
"You know Gulliver and Darcy?"
"Yes, they're the cutest
couple ever!"
-Ok, so...
...really do it!
The next time I see her,
I will!
Hold on!
"Hi, again.
"Oh, hi, Darcy!
I just remembered...
I get claustrophobia
in elevators.
How is your day going?
-Really good.
It's going really good.
What are you doing this weekend?
-So much... that I've just got to do a...
...bunch of stuff. -Cool.
-Yeah, it's cool!
Have a good one!
-You too!
Wait! I forgot something.
-Yeah, me too.
Gul.
Yeah?
-Yeaaah!
You chickened out,
didn't you?
Listen... I just... you know....
I didn't chicken out.
You're being respectful
of her workspace.
-Exactly.
Dude, speaking of which,
after work, do you want to go
for a couple of brews...
...shoot some pools,
maybe a little man date,
huh?
I don't think so. Especially
if it's called a 'man date',
sir...
I got you!
You want a 'rain cheque'.
You want to wake up all 'bright-eyed'
and 'bushy-tailed' for the boss.
You are not my boss anymore.
-What're you talkin' about?
I just got promoted.
It's impossible!
You just got here.
Yeah, they promoted me
to the 'head' of the Mailroom.
So, I'm your boss now.
Look, Gulliver,
the reason you didn't
ask her out...
...and you never will,
is the same reason you're
not going to leave the Mailroom.
You've been here like
ten years, man.
You know, you ...
You peaked.
When you talk the big game,
and that could be fun
...sometimes.
And you're pretty funny
around the office...
...but that's all you are.
just 'talk'.
So, you might as well face it.
You're never really going to get any
bigger than this.
These talks is...
the worst part of being a boss.
Anyway, be in tomorrow at 7am.
We're gonna sort of change
things up and...
...let's start with playing the guitar
during working hours.
Good night, Darcy!
See ya!
Gulliver?
Hi.
Can I help you?
-Yeah, I. ..
Well, I wanted to see
if ...
you wanted to...
You seem a little nervous.
Are you alright?
I'm fine. I'm just...
I've got so much going on...
I wanted to pick this up,
and then I was on my way.
You want to apply for a
'travel writing summit'?
Yup, exactly.
I had no idea you wrote,
or travel.
I do, I travel a lot.
I go to New Zealand...
...been to Mexico,
"me-hee-kaw" as they called it,
the locals.
Africa, the Congo...
...which I know is in Africa
because I 'travel' and 'write'.
So, this is kind of like
what I want to do.
Why don't you bring in a
writing sample tomorrow morning
and I'll see what I can do.
Perfect.
Okay.
Hey, Gulliver!
Nice job
putting yourself up for it.
Yeah, cool. Okay, bye-bye.
-Bye-bye!
Gulliver's Travels
Jesus! I meant to ask
her out...
Now she's expecting a writing sample?
What was I thinking?!!!
I saw some things
in different lands
I got to write this thing!
No, I've got nothing.
Oaxaca, MEXICO
Wow! I'm so impressed, Gulliver.
I had no idea that you're such
a good writer.
Well, I tried to
keep it a secret...
I don't like to brag
about my more literarian side.
These samples are terrific,
and you exhibit such variety.
I mean, this one about Oaxaca
feels really classic.
Like it's straight out
of 'Frommer's'...
...where a description of Barcelona
is all sassy!
It's like I'm reading
'Time Out'!
I think I've the perfect fluff piece
to start you off with!
There's a guy down in Bermuda
who claims he has the secret
to the Bermuda Triangle.
He's either crazy or
he's trying to build...
But I figure it could be
a fun way in...
...to explore Bermuda
and the small islands
around it, you know.
You have boat experience,
don't you?
I'm... I'm a...
I'm a 'boat' man.
Okay, good,
'cos...
I've to be honest with you...
It's hard for me to find
someone to do this.
You have to be at sea
for 3 weeks, completely
off the grid.
That's okay with you,
right?
Good, 'cos I thought I was going
to have to do it and...
...I do get 'super' sea sick.
Crazy!.
-Yeah.
What do you say?
Not a big story...
...but it's a start.
Okay, so the
Bermuda Triangle, huh?.
And everything I need to know is in here?
-It is. Your contact has been arranged.
And there's a boat
waiting for you.
Yeah!
Oh, hey!
That's me!
Precious cargo!.
No! No! Hoo... Ok!
That was close.
All the chickens get off
the road, man!.
I don't know about this, Hank.
I mean, are you sure this is safe?
All this
Bermuda Triangle talk...
...is just to sell
T-shirts to tourists.
It's a good story
to pick up some girls.
This is your boat.
"KnotferSail"
They really went 'Pun-tastic'
on that boat.
Well, the Dock Master's
really into pun, man. He believes it
keeps the pirates away.
"Ship Happens."
This is 'you'.
And that's your 'destination'.
Just follow that 'dot'
and you'll find yourself
in the 'Triangle'.
In the Bermuda Triangle?
-Yeah!
And then to come home, you said,
I turn this knob and follow
the 'dot' back home?
Yes!
-Easy!
Done!
-Done!
All right.
-I got it.
Fine, fine!
Well ..
It's not moving.
Okay.
Where is the clutch?
And as you go out,
to the ocean water...
...towards the Bermuda Triangle,
there're reflections everywhere.
I should have brought
sunglasses.
I'm as hungry
as a horse.
I could eat a thousand
cheeseburgers.
Okay, 'quitting' time.
Yeah!
How to build
your own robot.
That's going to happen!
Darcy.
Cheeseburger.
Safety! Okay.
Rubber ducky. No!
Floaties!
For the legs,
for the arms...
...for the head!
I am safe!
911! Gotcha!
Oh, no!
I'm paralyzed
from the neck down.
What is that
crawling on me?
No, no, not fire ants!
Please don't be... fire ants.
I am General Edward Edwardian,
Commander of Lilliput.
All hail, Liliput!
All hail Liliput!
"You are herewith charged
with aiding our sworn enemy,
the Blefuscu!"
"You are our prisoner
and shall be presented
to our Royal Highness...
...King Theodore!
What say you, Beast?!!
You are not real!
Where am I?
I'm dreaming.
I'm going to close my eyes...
...and then I'm going to open them
and I'll be home in bed.
Okay! Okay!.
My spear.
Bring the Beast down!
Alright, boys!
Release the hookers!
Pull! Pull!
Pull!
-That's not cool!
Hey! That's my pants.
That's not funny!
Unlucky!
Pull!
Lift!
Rest!
This Giant is hereby declared to
be brought to His Majesty, King Theodore!
All hail King Theodore!
I wanted a bracelet...
...not a great,
big hairy Beast!
Oh, dear...
are these strings
really necessary?
They are...
My innocent, naive,
little 'Bunny tail'.
To prevent the giant Beast
from running rampant and
killing us all!
What is this thing?
-A Blefuscian spy.
I am not a 'Blefuscian'.
I don't even know what that is.
Someone please,
just tell me where I am?
You're in Lilliput!
-Liliput?
The grandest and greatest
land in all the world!
All hail Lilliput!
This is insane!
Okay, enough!
Come out with
the funny cameras!
Mealtime, Beast!
Hay?
I can't eat hay!
Eat up!
You've a busy day ahead
of you, Beast!
Enough with
the 'Beast' thing!
I may be a giant
but I have feelings!!!
I think that you will find
that the hay is...
...a bit more digestible if
mixed with some sewer water.
I am sorry my countrymen
called you a 'Beast'.
I do not think of you as a 'Beast'.
As a matter of fact...
...before you arrived, I was
the tallest man in the Lilliput.
So, I know how you feel.
-Thanks, man.
I can't reach you for a
handshake. I am Gulliver.
Horatio.
You guys are so tiny.
Are you the only prisoner
in the whole dungeon?
Yes, I've been placed in
this prison by the great and glorious
general Edward Edwardian...
...for sending an illicit
letter to his betrothed...
...Princess Mary.
That's it? He put you in prison
for hitting on his lady?
Dude, that is harsh!
No, no, no, you must understand
that I am of a lowly station.
To legally court
a woman of her stature...
...one must commit a
valued action...
...which is virtually impossible
as a commoner.
Come on, don't be so hard on yourself.
You seem like a cool guy.
You can do something valiant!
Gen. Edward has led
countless crusades...
and is known far and wide
for his bravery.
I'm no Gen. Edward.
Well ..
No offense, but this Edward guy,
seems like kind of a lame-ass.
A lame what?
It's my impression that 'lame-ass'...
...is a negative expression
from whence you came.
If this is the case,
you should be thrown
into stocks!
No, no!
"Lame-ass" means,
'great, brave...
...courageous, heart of
a lion' man.
Is this the honorable truth?
Yes, this is the honorable truth.
Then, I'm not just
a 'lame-ass'.
No.
I'm a big 'lame-ass'!
-The biggest!
I, General Edward Edwardian,
I'm the biggest 'lame-ass'
in all of the land!
Heart of the lion!
So, listen...
now you know that
we're cool...
What do say if you
loosen up these
shackles a bit?
No. It's time for your life
of hard labor to begin.
Left
Right
Their Defense System
is operational.
We must move in
stealthily.
Left
Did I tell you to stop
fanning, peasant?!!
-Sorry.
They would be too busy with the fire
to protect their Princess.
Fire!
Fire is 2 bells. There was 3.
It is an attack!
There were more than 2 bells and
a pause, then a third bell.
So, there is an attack
and a fire?
The Blefuscians!
-The Princess!
To the Castle, Beast!
Left, right!
Faster, Beast!
Oh, no! The Blefuscians!
Do not kidnap me!
Please do not kidnap me!
Why is she standing there?
First, she's going to get
kidnapped and...
-You speak not of the Princess!
Down!
I shall save you,
my Princess!
'My Princess'.
Dude, I can help!
We do not need your help,
Beast.
You just stay here!
Nobody save
the Princess!
He'll never get
to her in time!
Please, you must
save the Princess!
Yeah, but you heard that
angry little dingleberry,
he said I shouldn't!
I beg of you!
It's too late.
-You're kidnapped!
I am kidnapped!
-Not on my watch!
Hop on, Princess.
Let's get you out of here.
Fear not, darling!
I am here to save you!
Where did she go?
Oh... She has been
kidnapped.
Here you go, Princess.
-Thank you so much!
Are you okay?
-Yes.
Thank God.
The Blefuscians have retreated.
-We ought to have a victory feast!
Terrific!
The fire has raised out of control.
-My father is trapped!
You guys got to invest
in a more efficient warning system!
Your Highness!
Out of the way!
I've gotta put out the fire!
Out of the way...
Coming through!
The Beast!
Yeoow! I've gotta say
that was hot!!!
Princess, no!
Princess... no... you mustn't!
-Father! He's burning!
You have served me
with great honor!
We need access to a great
deal of water!
-Do something!
I do not want to do this.
You have a plan?!
-I have a plan but you're
not going to like it.
Don't look.
Seize Beast!
It's working!
Yes it is working!
Out of the way!
How dare you evacuate yourself
on our great and glorious...
Oh no... Oh no.
Sorry about that smell.
I have been drinking sewer water.
-This is ground for execution!
I know that was pretty gross.
Let me pull up my trousers.
Father! Father!
You look glorious!
Thank you my dear.
Our Savior, the Beast!
Beast! Beast! Beast!
Hey, guys...
It was nothing, really.
I saw a fire, I had some water
and released flood on 'I-O-2'
(Instant-On Input-Output).
Is that translated?
You got the joke here?
'Flood on I-O-2'?
Ok, Thanks to you guys.
The King requests the honor
of your company at the banquet
this evening...
Do you accept?
-Yeah, on one condition.
You free my friend Horatio,
and allow me to bring him
as my 'Plus One'.
He was jailed for 'unlawful'
courting. He must return...
That's my condish!
One moment,
if you will.
Why are you doing
this for me?
Because you are my buddy.
I'm not going to this thing
without you.
I'm not going to know
anybody there.
You have to come!
Shhh...
Play it cool.
The King requests the honor
of your...
...and Horatio's company
at the Royal banquet
this evening.
Do you accept?
-Yes indeed.
I can make it.
-Oh, God...
My God!
I'm forever indebted to you.
It's not necessary.
Instead, let's just do this.
What is that?
-You pound it...
with your fist.
Come on,
don't let me hangin'.
Yeah!
Now, let's go P-A-R-T-Y...
Yeaaaah!
Will not somebody ...
I'll eat everything.
So, since you are not from Blefuscia,
where are you from?
Beast?
Once again, totally cool
to be just called Gulliver.
Some people believe that
you've come from the island
that we dare not go.
Is there any truth
to this rumor?
No. Where is
"The island that we
dare not go"?
There, beyond the fog bank.
Nuh, I didn't come from the fog bank.
I'm from the island of Manhattan.
Between the islands of
Staten and Long.
This island of Manhattan?
What sort of 'Kingdom' is it?
I'm not from a 'Kingdom'.
I'm actually from a democracy.
You see, we elect
a president
every 4 years.
You're so honorable
and courageous.
Were you the President?
-Of course he was, Mother!
Look at him.
He's the most powerful
gentleman in all the land.
So sorry mother
embarrassed you.
No, no, it's a common mistake
to not think I was President.
Are you a victorious President?
Oh, yeah, pretty victorious
Noble as well?
Yeah, I was eh...
... Super noble.
I was actually known
as 'President the Awesome'.
'President the Awesome'.
Pretty unlikely title.
When do you return home,
noble and awesome Gulliver?
Pretty soon,
I suppose, yes?
I should imagine they're
falling apart without you.
Their 'greatest' hero.
Well, without my boat...
looks like I'm stuck here.
Don't worry, my army
will find your boat.
At the meantime, I'm sure
we could find you a
suitable accommodation.
You mean...
some hay to sleep on?
Anything.
-Anything?
We have the finest builders
in all the land. We can build you
anything.
Seriously,
We are ridiculously
good builders.
And we are your servants,
Awesome Gulliver.
I don't want to
take advantage,
but...
Day 7 of my stay here
in Lliliput.
At first, me and the
little guys get off on
the wrong foot
but it turns out that
they are a pretty solid
group of dudes.
They are building me a
temporary place to live.
They threw me an
awesome party just to
release in myself.
And the King sent out
a search party to
find my boat.
At the meantime,
I'm 'worthing' it.
Hmmm, That is a good
cup of joe.
Good morning.
Good morning, Gulliver.
Top of the morning
to you, fellas.
Gulliver
Your media room is ready.
Obi-Wan did I tell you
what happened to your father?
You told me enough.
You told me you killed him!
No, Gulliver!
I am your father!
No way.
This is an impossibility!
-Yet somehow it seems
completely inevitable.
Gulliver, you truly have lived
a thousand lives.
King Theodore, it's time to perform
our bi-weekly military exercise!
Just one moment.
We're watching the stories
of Gulliver's life.
Sir, we've not missed
a military exercise
over 300 years.
Dude!
-Get out of the way!
We can not see the screen.
The Titanic is sinking!
But it was made
to be unsinkable.
"I love you, Gulliver.
-No, no, don't do that."
"You're going to make lots
of babies and die on a warm bed
at a very old age."
"God."
"I'm the king of the world!"
Wait.
I'm sorry.
You mean to say that
you actually died in the
ship wreck?
Yes. I died.
-That's what you're telling us?
You actually died?
-Yeah, but I was resuscitated.
It's preposterous!
-But then, I survived!
That's ridiculous!
Well, you have to see the scene...
-Well, okay now. It's silly!
Silly, silly stories!
Let me get this straight.
After you were brought
back to life as an avatar.
That's when you met your Princess
Darcy Silverman, Manhattan.
Yeah, I can't wait to get
back to her.
I noticed you had a little
eye-contact with the Princess.
How's it going?
-Good, yeah, I think if things
go well...
...within 2 to 4 years
she may then speak to me.
Wow... wo... wo...
Hold your horses.
-Thank God.
You can't woo a lady
by hoping that 'then'
she'll speak to you.
To land a Princess, you got to
employ some 'grey day cortash'.
Could you teach me?
This... this 'Cortage'
that you speak.
Yeah, I can teach you
some of my moves.
Yes! Thank you.
-If you beat me back home!
On your mark, get set, go!
-I'm not ready to race you!
Princess! Oh, Princess!
Wherefore art thou, Princess?
Hello, who calls?
It's I, Horatio!
Why are you so far away?
I don't want to invoke the ire
of thy father.
But I must be honest.
"And tell ye ...
-And tell ye ...
Tell me what, Horatio?
"You don't have to be rich
to be my girl."
"Say it!"
You don't have to be rich
to be my girl.
"You don't have to be cool
to rule my world."
Horatio, these 'passion' words
can get us into trouble.
"There is no particular sign that
I'm more compatible with."
There is no particular sign...
...that I'm more compatible with.
"I just want your extra time
and your....
...kiss."
...kiss.
Oh, what beauty emanates
from your lips!
"I think I'm gonna
dance now."
I think I better
dance now!
D-dance now!
Feel it.
Put the mustard on, baby.
Yes, feel, move the hips.
I don't think it is
working.
You are not
dancing good.
Shake.
I've never been wooed
with such unique passion.
It's working.
Did I tell you? Yes!
I hear someone coming.
'Til tomorrow.
It worked!
Let's go!
To whom were you speaking,
my Darling?
No one.
Me ... I...
...was speaking to me, myself.
What are you doing
In my chambers?
I have come to court you.
As I always do
at this time of the day.
Or have you already forgotten who is
your one true, eternal love?
No, of course, I remember.
Remember what?
That... that you are my
one, true eternal love.
It's just that I was talking
with the Giant and lost
track of time.
I trust not this Beast.
He seems trustworthy to me.
He is very nice.
You've done sewing?
-Sewing, yes...
...embroidery. It's my
Grandmother's doily.
I captured a hawk today.
-Did you?
He laid on the field, I came behind
him and catch him with my bare hand.
This is impressive also.
Oh... fun!
Fun courtship,
you and I have.
It is over, now.
Must go!
Those villagers
shan't pillage themselves.
We must alert General
Edwards of this at once!
We found it.
I hear you
Ring-A-Ling-A-Ding-Dong.
How is it going?
-Hello, Beast.
I come bearing the most
terrific news!
Yeah, really?
-We have discovered
your ship!
The "KnotferSail".
Clever name!
You did it.
You found my boat!
I'm actually going home.
Hey, you guys can
fix this thing, right?
Of course you can,
you incredibly awesome builders!
Yes!
Darcy is about to read
the best article ever.
Talking 'Pulitzer', huh?
Slide to unlock.
What're you guys doing?
It's that my phone?
Yeah, it's A-lookin'.
No signal but I have
12 messages,
Mr. Popularity.
Hey, Gulliver it's me.
It's Darcy.
You know I just realized
why I felt your writing came
straight out of Frommer's...
because it does!
Call me as soon as
you get this.
Sergeant,
what is he doing?
He's checking his 'voicemail',
General Edward.
Very good.
What is 'voicemail'?
Hey, Lemuel, it's Darcy.
I've totally forgiven you.
Wait, no I haven't!
'Coz now I have get seasick
on a boat...
...to cover your butt.
Thanks for this.
And If you can't tell,
then thanks for sarcastic.
Darcy again.
I can't believe you
lied to me.
I trusted you.
Wherever you're hiding.
Stay there. I never want to hear
from you again!
Mr. Beast, I've instructed
our builders to work
day and night...
...to ensure that you are
sea-worthy by week's end.
Isn't that the most
fantastic news you've ever
received in your life?
Great...
I can't tell you
how happy I am...
...for you.
Why do you look so forlorn,
noble protector?
Me? Forlorn, no way.
You do look quite
forlorn.
Just for the record, what does
'forlorn' means again? Is it like sad?
Basically, just a bit
more dramatic sounding.
Oh, well, in that case, I guess
I'm a little 'forlorn'.
Oh, Gulliver, you miss
your Princess.
Well...
The truth is we are not
super close.
Oh, Gulliver ...
She's kind of mad at me
right now.
I am forlorn as well.
I don't know what to do.
I think I'm in love
with Horatio.
But that's great.
Don't be forlorn about that.
Most people spend their
whole lives looking for that
and they don't find it.
Go for it!
Follow your heart!
-But my heart is promised
to General Edward.
And I can not break
that vow. He will lose honor...
...and respect, and he'll
die of heartbreak.
Okay, look, he's just
being melodramatic.
Is he?
-Yeah.
Gulliver, I will miss you so much.
-I'm going to miss you too.
Maybe I should stay.
Don't you miss your subjects?
And the White House?
And the Millennium Falcon?
Yeah, but vice president can
run things without me for a while.
You think the king would mind
If I stuck around for a bit?
Of course not, Gulliver.
You've made everyone
here so happy.
I can't imagine anyone
in Lilliput not wanting you
to stay...
...as long as possible.
Noble and valiant King Theodore
I trusteth not this Beast Gulliver
who liveth in our midst.
He can now leaveth,
but he chooses to stay.
And furthermore, I do not
believeth who he saith
he isth.
I mosteth humbly
disagreeth.
And whyeth must we always
go on with these 'Fs'?
Because we speak
officiallyeth?
Forget it, from now on,
even when speaking officially...
...we must get rid of these 'Fs'.
Official speaking is an
illustrious Lilliputian tradition!
Woh....'Inside-castle-voice'
please.
Forgive meeth.
Forgive me.
You know I think this job's
beginning to stress you out.
Maybe a little 'Time-off'
will be the thing.
Who else could
run your army?
Our new General,
Gulliver!
I won't let you down, King.
And I look forward to
working with you,
Vice-General Edward.
Vice General?
Vice.
I've never been a "Vice"
of anything.
I can't be expected to take orders
from that gigantic fool!
I rather take orders from
a woman. You are relieved.
Thank you
Vice-General Edward.
Alright, Gulliver,
protect against this!
They have turned off
their defence system.
Alert the king!
And prepare the Armada.
Oh, no. Our defence system
has failed.
We shall never reach
our ships on time.
Careful now.
Mind yourselves.
Oh what a mess.
They are defenseless.
Ceasefire
and ready the troops!
Gulliver!
The Blefuscians attacked.
Are you sure?
-Yes!
Please! We need you.
You are our General.
Good Lord!
It's the entire Blefuscian Armada!
-I know.
Finally!
Our General has arrived.
What's going on?
I heard the bells.
As our 'mighty' General,
you must lead the army...
...to save Lilliput and vanquish
the entire Blefuscian Armada.
You want me to
vanquish all of them?
Yes, please.
Everyone last one of them.
Yeah, fine.
-Thank you, fair Gulliver!
Okay. Here we go.
Time to vanquish.
It's cold.
No problem.
You're going down.
Why have we stop?
-It's him!
Hey, dudes.
I am Gulliver.
I come in peace.
Listen, They want me
to vanquish you guys.
I don't want to vanquish anybody
and you don't want to be vanquished.
Let's just pretend,
okay?
I'll go crazy,
you act all scared,
and...
Just follow my lead, alright?
Sell it!
Turn the ships!
Sound the alarm!
This truly is
the battle of the ages!
-It truly is!
I'll just tell them you're
too swift or whatever ...
How come you all turned around?
Fire!
Oh no!
That looks painful!
I am invincible.
Yes! Go on, Gulliver!
Well done!
Excellent!
Well done,
you big fat pig.
Pound it.
Well done, Gulliver!
This is glorious!
Goal!
Alright!
Yeah! Guys, this is what
I'm talking about!
Look at that! The Billboards
and the lights.
Home sweet home.
What can I say?
Okay, can you guys send over
a division to my left shoulder, please?
North 2 clicks.
One click.
Oh, yeah!
That's the spot!
A little off the top.
Don't go crazy.
And don't shave off my sideburns.
I need those monkey chaffs.
Can I double the bet with you because
I was playing and singing.
You did good though.
Let's try again from the top!
One second, please. Pause game.
-Pause game.
I was just thinking.
You are the General of Lilliput now.
Shouldn't you be training the army?
What if Blefuscian should
attack again?
Oh, man, no one's going to attack.
Not while I'm around.
I'm one-man wrecking crew.
If you want to worry
about something...
You should worry about how you haven't
made a move on the Princess yet.
You're in danger of falling
in the 'Friendship Lagoon'.
What?
Yeah, 'Friendship Lagoon'.
It blows. You'll gonna be like:
"Oh yeah, We're friends,
that's great, I'm cool with that."
And you won't be cool with that!
And it kills you inside!
No, never.
Yeah, man!
You got to 'man-up' and
be direct.
Next time you see her
Just tell her: "What's up?".
"Hey, what's up sexy? I hope it's not
too forward but I find you incredibly sexy. "
"I never told you before,
but I'm really into you."
"But I'm also into a lot of things.
So don't get too excited."
"There're a lot of things going on.
I like you to be one of them."
See the way I mixed it up?
I want you, but not that much.
You try it!
Okay, show which face?
Dude, you know,
if the face comes to you
but make it look natural.
Don't make it a forced face.
I just have, you know, one of those
faces that just happen naturally.
My hands are sweating.
-Go!
Well, hello,
fine maiden with the wide...
...child-bearing hips.
Yikes, you don't want to talk about
"wide child-bearing hips."
It's a good instinct. You're getting there.
But this time more smooth and sexy.
No "big hips"?
--No "big hips".
I've got it.
Well, hello there, slim.
I ought to call you Portamus
because you've
got no hip.
Do we have to be
here for this?
Take five.
Save game.
Forget about the hips.
Here's what you've got to do.
What are you doing
In my chambers?
I have come to court you.
as I always do at this time
of the day.
This is not the time of day
for courting. You cannot
just barge in.
I can court you
when I wish to court you.
I'm not in the mood to be courted.
I have a headache.
It's your womanly duty.
Section 4.2 of the
Official Courting Doctrine.
Edward!
I'm unsure about
things between us.
It be not you.
It be me but I'm
very unsure.
That maketh no sense.
We ought to be married.
You are to be my bride.
We are not in love.
We're not in love.
Who do you love about me?
Name one thing.
Inappropriate, Edward.
Reach for it.
-One second!
Okay. Take your time.
I find you...
absolutely...
satisfactory.
Edward, that's not enough
to say that someone is average,
or adequate or moderate.
I want to be loved
for who I am!
There's an awful lot
going on up here.
Is there?
-Now you're being cruel.
And frankly, melodramatic.
And acting like a complete baby!
You are acting like a little Princess!
-I am a Princess!
Maybe I should
act like a Princess.
Gulliver was so right about you!
-Why don't we all just listen
to the Beast!
Don't call him that!
-He's a big ugly Beast
And you should know better!
-Get out!
You can't break our engagement!
It's a fate worse than death.
Get out!
You'll be sorry you ever crossed
General Edward!
Get your Gulliver T-shirt!
You sir!
What do you want?
This Beast has transformed Lilliput...
...into his own sordid and
rotten little kingdom!
And he will do the same to your land
if we do not stop him.
To save Lilliput,
I must first destroy it.
How do you suggest we complete
such a dangerous task?
Alright! Welcome to the first
ever Lilipaloosa!
Let's get this party started
with a little gem I wrote!
Right?
So what are you
up to tomorrow?
-Tomorrow?
Yes.
-I'm just hanging,
you know.
Would you care to attend
the Ball of the Moonlight with me?
Oh, the Ball!
The Ball's tomorrow!
Right. Maybe.
Why are you acting
like this?
Acting like what?
-Why are you being
so strange?
I am a gentleman merchant about town,
and I have got to keep my options open.
Do you?
That's what I've been told.
-Well, I'm not an 'option'.
I'm a lady.
-I know you are. And I love ladies.
I'm sorry...
Five bells.
What does five bells mean?
-There've never been 5 bells!
Don't worry about it.
'Coz this guy throws down no matter
how many bells they're ringin'.
Don't freak, little peeps.
This one's on me.
You gotta be kidding me.
This is 5 bells?
Ha... it's cute!
Edward, you traitor! How dare
you forsake your lilliputian
brothers?
I only forsoken
for I was forsoken!
'Forsoking' ends now.
I challenge you to a duel!
Cool. Whatever.
Do you accept?
-Oh... Yeah!
Yeah, I accept your duel.
Good.
-Make a move.
Wow! You are hard.
Okay, just stretching up.
It is a good thing to do
before the duel.
You brought this
on yourself, Beast.
Do you surrender,
Beast?
Sure, yeah,
whatever!
No, no, no...Say it properly,
Say it, you surrender!
Say it! Say it!
Say!
I surrender!
You win.
Release my butt.
You can not surrender.
You are our most glorious
protector!
You are 'President
The Awesome'!
You and Captain Sparrow defeated
The Joker and Magneto.
And you and Jack Bauer had
only 24 hours to do it.
I didn't do any
of that stuff.
I'm just the guy
from the mailroom.
But you gave us your word!
-I'm sorry.
I lied.
I knew it!
I hereby banish this Beast
to the island where we
dare not go!
Never to return
to Lilliput again!
Take your positions!
Please Gulliver!
Hey, is this 'Island that
we dare not go' really
as bad as they say?
It's delightful!
Okay, no little people anywhere.
It's a good sign.
Hello! Is anybody here?!
No way!
Raise the flag!
Can I not walk alone
in my own garden?
Go away!
Princess.
I've secured a boat.
We can leave tonight.
No, Horatio.
But Edward's going to
force you to marry him.
I don't have any choice.
Please, please...
Yes, of course you have a choice.
You made that choice for me.
-You don't understand.
Gulliver told me...
-Everything Gulliver said
was a lie.
Including you.
Oh, I'm paralysed from the waist down.
What's that crawling on me?
Not fire ants. Oh please
don't be fire ants.
Am General Edward Edwardian.
Commander of the new Blefuscia.
All hail Blefuscia!
-I must warn Gulliver!
State your name,
She-Beast.
Darcy Silverman.
-Of Manhattan?
Ahhhhhh...!
Noooo......!
I'm not doing this.
You got me in the diapers and dress.
I'm not doing tea-time with you.
Go find another doll!
Tea-time...
time for tea!
Okay, we're kissing.
Ohhh....
Gentle-r!
Just hold hands, will you?
What's up?
What kind of toy are you?
Top Gun, G.I Joe?
Cool detail.
Gulliver! Gulliver!
Down here!
What are you doing here?
Gulliver, you must
return to Lilliput at once!
Forget it, man, it's a No-Go.
-No! you don't understand! Edward ...
Doesn't matter.
I may be a hundred feet tall, but
I'm not half the size of...
...one of you little guys.
-You've got to listen to me,
this is important!
No. This is where I belong.
As a giant girl's
babydoll.
Hey! Stop feeling sorry
for yourself and listen!
Blefucian has taken
over Lilliput and Edward,...
...has captured
Darcy Silverman
of Manhattan.
What?
She's... Darcy's here?
-Yeah!
Oh no! She said she was going
to do the assignment herself.
She's here because of me.
-It's all because of you.
How could you lie to us?
I was afraid to tell
you guys the truth.
Because it was just so great
being a Big shot for the
first time in my life.
I didn't want it to end.
Snap out of it, man.
You think of yourself as this
small little thing.
But that's not how
I see you.
Think about what've done already.
You saved the Princess,...
You single-handedly defeated
the entire Blefuscian Armada.
Didn't you?
Come on,
I'm your best friend.
I wouldn't lie to you.
You can do this.
So take off that dress
and let's get out of here!
Am I really your
best friend?
You're kind of my only friend.
-It's great, man. You too for me.
Let's go save Lilliput.
-Yeah, let's go do this.
Take me with you!
One second. There we go.
-I gotcha.
Okay, officer...
I'm just going to borrow this
parachute, if it's okay with you.
You don't need it anymore.
This is insane!
Oh, I'll let you.
-Thanks, Horatio.
-Good luck!
I got this.
Darcy! Darce!
Gulliver!
-Hey! I'm coming over there.
Are you okay?
I can't believe you're here.
I mean, of all the places,
right?
What's up?
-What's up? What's up?
What isn't up? Can you talk
about the inverted whirlpool.
Crazy...
And why does everybody
calling me a "Princess"?
They don't.
I think you misheard.
I see you've returned
for your "Princess".
Now, you heard it right there.
He just called me your "Princess"?
That's because everybody is
a Princess here. I forgot to tell you,
It's just this sort of a thing.
If you wish to speak to
your one true love
more privately...
...we should cover
our ears.
"One true love"?
I told them
I was your "one true love"?
Is it now a good or bad time
to tell you about...
...the crush I've had on you
for the last 5 years?
Really?
Yeah. I totally have
a crush on you.
That's why you're always wheel in
the mail cart around and none
of the mail is for me?
Yeah. Hmm...Yeah.
I told everyboby that you're
my 'girlfriend'. It's really embarrassing.
I think it's kinda sweet.
Gulliver, we've gotta focus.
We've got a book to the podium.
We're gonna get the hell out of here.
We are surrounded by
little people?
-Darcy, listen to me.
I would love to book with you,
over to the boat right now.
but I can't.
These little people have grown
very large in my heart.
They depended on me
and I let them down.
I have to do this first.
King...
If it's alright with you,
I would like to be your
glorious protector again.
I don't know. How are we to believe
anything you say, Gulliver?
Because my word
is my bond...
...this time, for real.
I promise.
-Gulliver.
You work in the mailroom
-Not today...
I don't!
Hey, Edward!
If I win, Lilliput returns
to her former glory.
And if you lose.
This is what becomes of Lilliput!
Oh, I've made a
slight improvement.
Shocking, isn't it?!
Hey, hey that's not fair.
He's cheating!
I've got to do
something!
Now, do what you do best, Beast,
and run off!
No way.
Not today.
I've always liked you, Gulliver.
I've always thought we had
a real 'spark'.
Hang on, Gulliver!
I'm on my way!
Gulliver, no!
I'll sizzle ya bit by bit!
It is hot!
Go, Gulliver!
-Yes, Gulliver, go!
Take it!
Now that's a Wedgie!
Yeah, Gulliver!
Did you see that?!
I want you to get back
to the second grade.
I'm so, so sorry.
I hope you can forgive me
for the way I behaved.
You are not an "option".
You're the most beautiful lady
of all the land.
And you're also super cool.
And a stone-cold fox.
Horatio!
Do you realize what
you've done?
You have committed a
'Knight of Valiance'.
I hereby give you
my permission.
Yeah!
Nobody move.
Halt! Stop!
I've kidnapped the Princess.
You've been kidnapped, congratulations.
Enough with the
kidnappings!
Boosh!
Yes!
Listen! I played your eyes all that stuff
because I thought you'll never want to go out
with the dude in the mailroom.
I'm sorry.
That will never happen again.
So...
Prepare for war!
-No! You prepare for war.
I have to do one more
thing real quick.
Kings! Kings!
C'mon guys!
What's it with you and the...
executions... and the gallows...
and the stocks... and the war?!
Seriously, war?
Why do war?
What is it good for?
Absolutely not...
...War!
What is good for?
Absolutely not...
Say it again now...
War!
Good God, y'all...
What is it good for?
For absolutely nil!
War is the enemy
to all mankind
The problems of the world,
blows my mind
Life is much too short and precious
to spend fighting war these days
The Lord gives me life,
He can always take it away!
Good God, y'all!
What is it good for?
Absolutely nothing
Say it again!
War!
What is it good for?
Absolutely nothing!
Listen to me
Peace, love and understanding
Is there no place
for them today?
They say we must fight
to keep our freedom
But the Lord knows there's got to
be a better way
War
Good God, y'all!
What is it good for?!
Say it!
War!
What is it good for?!
Stand up and
Shout it!
Bravo! Lilliput is free.
Gonna miss
Your big friend?
A little.
"Yeah?
A lot...
-Oh, dear.
How was Papua
New Guinea?!
It was hot, sticky ...
...and the most mind-boggling
place I have ever seen.
The most mind-boggling place
you've ever seen? -Okay, the second
most mind-boggling place.
Oops, sorry.
-Danny!
Here are your morning mails,
Gulliver.
Thank you.
Who's your friend?
I'm Mark, just the new guy
in the Mailroom.
Oh, just the Mailroom?
Mailroom's 'Whozat',
right, Dan?
Yeah, I don't know why he
would say that 'coz there's where all
the great start, y'know.
Remember, there's no small
jobs. Just small people.
Teeny, tiny,
teeny little people.
Haven't I told you that? No small
jobs, tiny, tiny people.
Can I take you for lunch?
Of course you can.
My fair 'Princess'.
DARCY SILVERMAN:
Gulliver's Travels
"A voyage to Lilliput"
"A voyage to Brobdingnag"
(THE JOURNEY CONTINUES...)
ThE EnD
Movie & Captions Conformed By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
'' Hope You've Liked & Enjoyed The Movie !!! ''