Makoto77.
- Hey kid!
- What?
I found something.
You should see this.
Jumanji.
Board game. Who
plays a board game?
Okay, okay, gate 1, uppercut.
Perfect, you lose. Attack,
attack, counterattack, and slam.
- Okay, all right.
- YOU KNOW.
Strange house in 20 minutes.
Benjamin Franklin, and his
exceptional nationalism.
Burning the spirit of
Westward expansion.
- Spencer, I'm coming.
- Ah!
Mom, what did we say about
knocking on the door?
I'm late for work, are you going straight
to your dad's house after school?
- Yes, maybe.
- Do not forget your equipment.
And please, remember it's a
horrible place, be careful.
I love you more than life itself.
See you Sunday night.
Okay.
- Bye, mom.
- Eat something before you go.
I can not, I'm going
to Spencer's house.
- Spencer Gilbert?
- Yes, Spencer Gilbert.
He, he taught me, helps
me get good grades.
I'm glad to hear that,
Spencer Gilbert.
Will your score be good?
Yes mother, that's why
I'm asking for help.
I want you to get
out of his team.
I will not get out of his team.
That .. That'll be fine. OK?
Sweet, right?
Yes.
Bethanywalker: Just getting out of bed.
Uh, good morning.
- Yo.
- Hey Fridge.
Why are you wearing raincoats?
- What do you mean?
- I mean, it's not raining.
Oh, well, I mean, it could rain.
- God.
- What the fuck, man?
Do you mind, can we finish this?
This is very uncomfortable.
Here it is.
- Have you checked everything?
- Yes, I checked it.
And I already gave the
prefix and the suffix ..
And something in the middle.
Listen, man, I'll do it
myself if I have time.
Yes, no big deal.
Hey, I thought, so, I mean, it's nice to
help you and do your homework, but ..
I do not know what your activities
are this weekend, but I think ..
This weekend, yeah, uh ..
- Hey Fridge.
- Hey.
You need a ride?
- I'll come with him.
- No, that's better for me.
I also have my own schedule. See
you later, " Refrigerator ".
- Sorry. Sorry.
- Hello, guys.
Forget .. He's not your best
friend during your childhood.
What did you say?
Uh, nothing, sir.
- Uh, that guy is so weird.
- Poor guy.
What happened to
them was terrible.
- I'm talking about his son.
- What are you doing here?
I was talking to
my friend first.
- You should be more careful, you hear?
- Yes, Mr. Rick.
- I understand.
- This world swallows kids like you.
It took me two hours to
create another content.
Because I do not like it.
Did you see it?
Yes, of course. I do not
know who it is from.
Thanks, and it's not always like that,
but it's enough to stay relevant.
- But that's funny.
- Is there a strange person behind you?
- Hi.
Bethany, did you call
during the exam?
Yes, but I have
finished my exam.
Oh, okay. Do you realize that the
other students have not finished yet?
- So?
- Oh, sorry.
Let me repeat. You're more weird than
the other people in his world, right?
Listen, um, you know, now
I have affairs, and ..
Believe me, I know how
hard it is to be you,
I'm having a crisis, and, Lucinda,
I mean, she made me a woman
and it feels like maybe
you should do it too.
- Just close the phone.
- Okay, no problem.
- Bethany. Close it now.
- 2 more minutes and I'm done.
And that's the tension.
Okay, stretch her hand. Come on!
- Bethany, you're late.
- Sorry!
I heard she split with him.
Maybe this is your chance, man.
Okay, we'll practice a catch, so
find your partner and grab a ball.
Let's move!
Hey, Martha. Martha. You can
not play capture alone.
Find pair. Come on. Hurry.
No, I'm fine.
Okay.
You must participate,
like everything else.
Otherwise why are you here?
That's a requirement.
- Martha ..
- This is useless.
The gym class will not take
me to Princeton, and I'm not
obsessed with throwing balls
and jumps, and oh, goals!
Okay, there's a lot
wrong with that, but ..
It's physical activity, good for you,
with other people, also good for you.
And if you try it,
maybe you like it.
Have fun. That's what we're
doing here, having fun?
It's a school, we should
learn something important.
- Okay.
- We do not have much time in this life.
And I do not want to spend it
by being a sports teacher.
- That sounds wrong ..
- Yes, of course.
That's a hold.
- That's very hard.
- Cool.
Spencer Gilbert.
Sit down, Spencer.
Mrs. Mathers.
And with its exceptional
sense of nationalism,
which fueled the spirit
of Westward expansion.
Does that sound familiar, Mr.
Gilbert?
No.
That's the last sentence of Anthony's
assignment on Westward expansion.
And by chance, it's the
last sentence of your
assignment about Westwood's
expansion from last year.
That's interesting.
- Really?
- I think so.
I mean, how likely is it?
Very small.
Yes, you also use
the same metaphor.
Deployment on your assignment
about the Boston Tea Party.
Gettysburg Battle and
women's suffrage.
- In this room is very hot.
- Anthony.
I know you really need to pass in my
class, but this is not the way you do it.
- I will not tolerate cheats.
- Cheating?
- I'm not, I'm not cheating.
- It's my fault.
I made him do it.
You made him tell
you to do his work?
Yes.
Hm-hm.
- Listen, I'm sorry. Okay?
- No, that's not okay.
What the hell, dude, you
can not betray his team.
Yes, but you will
get me removed.
Not only are you
having trouble here.
- Having trouble?
- Yes.
The most dangerous thing
I've ever done in my life.
And now look at me. I
accept the consequences.
Well, this is a fun group.
Welcome to containment.
- Yes, Spencer?
- I just want to apologize.
- Thanks.
- Principal Bentley, all I do ..
Bethany, please, you are here for
a reason, you know what it is.
This is what you
have to think about.
Who are you at this time?
And, you want to be what.
You have one life, you decide
how you guys will live it.
Fortunately, there is no better place
to mirror than the quarantine place.
Everything stands up, come on.
We will convert this to
a new computer center.
But before we do, it
should be cleared.
All of these old magazines
will be sent to recycling.
But it must be set up
before it is sent.
It seems that all the
stappler must be separated.
Whatever you do not finish
today, you finish tomorrow.
- But tomorrow is Saturday.
- Because I do not want ..
Yes, I do not think
it will work.
- That's fair.
- Shut up.
So I guess you can start.
Select your equipment.
Why is there a
bowling ball here?
Really? No signal? Okay,
can this day be any worse?
Are you going to help
or you're too pretty?
I'm too pretty.
Hey. Yesterday I watched
you with his coach.
I mean I'm not paying attention
to you, not in a strange way.
I just, I'm in the
same class as you.
But I think you said the smart thing
about why the gym lesson sucks, and ..
About other subjects.
Thanks.
Yes.
Yo, what is this?
- I do not know.
- Is this some kind of old Nintendo?
I do not think so.
I do not recognize it.
A game for those looking for ..
A way to leave their world.
WELCOME TO JUMANJl
Jumanji.
Friends, staples.
- Jumanji, what does it mean?
- I do not know, never heard of it.
SELECT CHARACTER
Ah, which one do I choose?
I do not know, I do not
think it matters much.
Jefferson " Seaplane" McDonough.
Pilots and bastards.
- This does not work.
- Okay, try something else.
- Franklin " Moose " Finbar.
- Hm ..
This looks cool.
And he's an animal
expert, that's cool.
- You select.
- Okay.
Doctor Smolder Bravestone.
- Bethany, do you want to come?
- All right.
I will choose Shelly Oberon.
The sexy genius.
- Put your staples, come on. Your turn.
- Uh, no thanks.
Wait, just a minute?
This will be fun.
He does not like to have fun.
Okay.
This is probably the dumbest
thing I've ever done.
I highly doubt that.
Welcome to Jumanji.
What's happening?
I think it is shorting.
Unplug the cord!
- What's happening? What's in your hands?
- What's wrong with you?
I do not know.
Oh no, oh my God!
What the hell, dude?
Oh no, oh no!
Come!
Guys! This does not
sound like my voice.
Where's my hair?
What the hell?
Oh my God!
It's stupid.
- Who are you?
Who is it?
Who are you?
Good. What the fuck ..
- God! Oh, my God!
- Get out of me!
What's done? What's
wrong with my voice?
- Get out of me. Watch out!
- Where am I?
Move!
Oh ..
What happened ..
Happened to me? What is this?
What's on my back?
- What's this?
- Oh, my God.
Fridge?
I'm Fridge, who are you?
I'm Spencer.
What? Who are you?
What's going on?
- I think we are in the game.
- Excuse me?
- You are talking about ..
- Somehow ..
I do not know how .. I think we
like being sucked into the game.
And we become the
avatar we choose.
So here I am, Spencer. But I look and
sound like Doctor Smolder Bravesound.
You told me you were Spencer?
Yes, yes. Yes. That's right.
Fridge, I'm Spencer.
Which .. Which you are Mush Spinbar.
Written on your mantle.
And ..
- Marta? You are a Ruby Warrenhouse.
- Yes.
Bethany. You are
Professor Sally Oberoun.
It's just that Shally must
be short for Sheldon.
- What are you talking about?
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God. He's right.
- And you .. And you Spencer? You?
- Yes. Guys, I'm telling you.
I'm Spencer. I'm Spencer...
- Yes, it's Spencer.
- Wow.
So, that means I ..
Wait.
No!
I'm a Norwegian.
Ah, I have a tattoo. My mom always said
she would kill me if I had a tattoo.
I also have a tattoo.
Sometimes.
Wait a minute,
where is my phone?
Why am I wearing this
outfit in the Jungle?
I'm a bit short with my
leather tops, what's this?
I look like a walking park.
Where's my phone?
- Who cares?
- We are in someone else's body.
That does not seem the most
important at the moment.
Oh, really? You do not think
this is not a good time to call?
Or send a message to anyone? Or
change your status in the game?
What I'm saying is that I do
not have my Clentine, either?
And I'm almost allergic
to everything.
Oh, no. You have
allergies, Spencer?
Oh, I do not have a
tattoo on my body.
You guys are really
not possible.
It's possible that
we're all in a coma.
Together? We're all
in a coma, together?
You heard, that's the only
best explanation .. Like ..
Oh my God!
Oh, my God. You better
go down save him.
I will not go in there.
You go in there.
Oh, No, I'm wearing a backpack.
You do not go into the water with
a backpack, everyone knows that.
Ouch!
- What?
- Bethany.
Are you okay?
That's very stressful.
I can not seem to get
away from this place.
- What just happened to you?
- I've just been fed by a rhinoceros.
And then I fell from a
thousand feet from the sky.
- Yes, it looks like that.
- It was a hippo.
Near the river, hippos fast and
provide 800 Newt pressure.
How do I know this?
- You are a wildlife expert.
- What?
- I'm still a fat guy, right?
- I'm afraid so.
Wait, why do everything calm
down with this. I mean, he ..
- From the sky.
- Hm, buddy.
Bethany, wake up! Run!
Run!
Run ..
Come on, come on, come on.
Oh, Doctor Bravestone.
Welcome to Jumanji.
Do not just stand
there, let's get in.
- Come on, come on!
Come on.
Doctor Bravestone.
Famous archaeologist and
international explorer.
Already past 7 continents,
with bold browsing.
- Seriously, buddy.
- I can not tell you how honorable.
To meet you.
I'm not ashamed to say that you're
more handsome is seen directly.
- Thanks.
- Who are you.
Nigel Viegsly, serving you.
Ruby Roundhouse. Male lover.
Welcome to Jumanji.
I'm very impatient
for your arrival.
What do you know, Jumanji
is in great danger.
We depend on the four of
you to remove the curse.
- Curse?
- What curse?
Excuse me. Do you see
my phone anywhere?
Professor Sheldon Oberon.
Welcome to Jumanji.
Nigel Viegsly serves you.
I'm very impatient
for your arrival.
- What did he say?
- I think he's an NPC.
- What? Please speak English.
- Non-player characters.
He's one part of the game.
So whatever we ask him.
Anyway he's programmed to
respond to several things.
Understandable. Now
everything is clear.
Franklin Mouse Springberg.
Welcome to Jumanji.
Muse? Not a Mouse.
Oh, no, sir. I'm
pretty sure Mouse.
- Mouse?
- At this moment, from your structure.
And amazing behavior.
And you're here.
Doctor Bravestone will not go
anywhere without his trusted friends.
Friend?
Since Doctor Bravestone saved you from
Kunco oro-oro in the Peruvian jungle.
You never leave the side.
- Really?
- Can we discuss the curse again?
It's all in the letter sent
to you, Doctor Bravestone.
Maybe you should read aloud.
I have no mail ..
Wow.
Okay.
Doctor Bravestone. I'm writing to you
in severe situations in Jumanji.
We need your help.
Comrade, what's going on?
- What's going on?
- I think this is a scene snippet.
Many games have movie trailers to
support their background story.
My name is Nigel Viegsly.
Jumanji tour guide.
I was hired by Paul Parker.
Your bitter enemy. Professor Van Pelt.
To guide a good expedition.
You know, Doctor Van Pelt did a similar
search on the lethal jaguar tribe.
Graves located at the center
of the sacred Jumanji.
What you know surpasses
anyone, he is very obsessed.
And after years of research, he believes
in arriving at his destination.
Yes, I finally found it.
Van Pelt says he wants to find his gem
in order to perfect the document.
And he found it.
- This is real.
- Which I do not know.
He wants to take his
gem for himself.
I got it!
The ancient manuscript says
that the Jaguars keep Jumanji.
And whoever is blinded by it.
Will be consumed by dark forces.
And Van Pelt became the master
of the creature Jumanji.
Entering them. Control them.
And the bad curse once
again controls this land.
I asked him to return it,
but once in his handle.
He will never release it.
So I waited until she
fell asleep that night.
And I'm doing my business.
Capture the guide!
And kill anyone who
tries to stop you.
Then, here it is.
With your valuable help
and your companion.
You must use your special skills to
restore gems in the eyes of a jaguar.
And remove the curse.
I'm sure you want to
start right away.
- Actually I think ..
- Good luck ..
Fate Jumanji is in your hands.
- What?
- And remember ..
Your goal is pleasure
and suspense.
Restore the gem and
remove the curse.
If you expect to leave the
game, you must save Jumanji.
And mentioned his name.
Good luck. Jumanji's
destiny is in your hands.
- And remember, The goal...
- He said the same thing.
Restore the permission
and remove the curse.
If you want to leave the game.
You must save Jumanji.
And mentioned his name.
That's okay. We can handle this.
In the real world, people love you,
you can meet whoever you want.
That's how you tell yourself
when you're scared?
Can not you rate me for a while?
I'm in somewhere, I turn into a
man, and I can not find my phone!
I'm allowed to be sad.
Doctor Bravestone,
here's a map of Jumanji.
You should go to Bazaar
looking for the missing part.
- Bazaar.
- Looking for some what?
- Goodbye.
- Do you think a mouse on a statue?
And remember, if you want
to leave the game ..
You must save Jumanji.
And mentioned his name.
Do you want to put
it in the backpack?
No. - Come on, you're the only
one who has a backpack, Fridge.
Then what? We have a map,
so we have to search ..
Bazaar, I think.
So, we try to return the
gem to the jaguar statue.
And then, then we go home.
No problem.
Why can not we just go? Stop the
game, without doing everything.
We need to finish the game.
I think .. I think we
should save Jumanji.
Shit, there's a guy over there.
Do not cry! Do not Cry! Do not Cry!
Do not Cry! Do not Cry! Do not cry!
Do not cry!
There are very many
outbreaks out here.
This is hot.
Okay, here's what I'm ahead of me.
Play a video game.
This is what I do,
the main thing I do.
Play a game like this,
there will be a level.
In order to complete the game,
you must complete all levels.
The level will become even
harder when we finish it.
- We finish the level ..
- Excuse me, do you know where we're going?
- Somewhat.
- Somewhat?
Oh, that's great.
We are being well guided.
I think the missing part.
Oh, my God, that's definitely what we're
looking for, the missing map part.
Right above it. Nothing here.
What do you mean there
is nothing there.
It's a map like he said.
This is a map from Jumanji.
- Cartography.
- What's that?
You said it was a map. That's one
of Oberon professor's abilities.
Yes. That's right.
Oh, so you can not see this.
But I can.
The characters we choose
have special abilities.
So there must be a way of
accessing our capabilities ..
Oh ..
- Wow.
- What did you just do?
Strength. No fear. Climbing.
Speed. Boomerang.
Burning intensity.
What are you doing?
What just happened?
You just burned.
Weakness: Nothing?
How did you do that? List it.
Well, well, I thought, I
just pressed my big chest.
Yes, breasts here.
Let me show you.
Away from me.
At least tap in front of us
so we know where exactly ..
Strength: Karate, T'ai
Chi, Aikido, fight dance?
Dance battle? Is that something?
Weakness: Toxins.
Serious.
Peleontology? What
does that mean?
Studying fossils, I think?
That's kinda cool.
POWER, ZOOLOGl, WEAKNESS
WEAPON, CAKE, SPEED, STRENGTH.
I hate this game.
Weakness, cookies?
Yes, cookies are my weakness.
Along with speed and power.
Strength is my weakness.
Hey, can I, quick question.
How is strength my weakness?
Someone explained to me.
Why do I need speed?
Why do I need to be fast while I'm being
chased by a big zebra killer and whatever?
On this stupid hat.
You are also good
at storing weapons.
What does that mean?
Well, I thought you
were carrying my gun ..
In your backpack and you give
it to me when I need it.
Comrade. The map .. It is ..
- Changed.
- What does it mean?
- What's being said?
- Okay, well ..
There is not much information but in
the past, it does not write this.
Dam now exists. It
says, mighty Aungan.
I do not like that. I'm done.
- What else?
- Good.
And right here, it says, from D.
- Hippos come from depth. The one ..
- Yes, thank you, do the thing.
That's it, go ahead.
Then, from D is the first level. Then
Aungan Perkasa must be the second level.
Which direction?
Good. By GuAVAbERRY.
If it's east,
And it's here.
Right here, I thought.
What is this game?
Run!
Wait!
Come on!
Why is my track so slow?
- Run!
- Run, run!
We have to go, yes!
This is crap!
Oh my God!
Wow.
- Come on!
- Those guys have big guns!
- Oh, really? That's the last one.
- Take off your rucksack.
- Or what?
- In your rucksack. You have my gun!
- Oh.
- Come on, down, down!
Oh. Have your weapon.
- Oh, no, no. What is this?
- Yes, boomerang, one of my supremacy.
What are you going
to do with it?
I do not know, I guess kill.
- You wanna kill him with that?
- You got a better idea?
Oh watch out.
Watch this.
Good work.
We need to get out of here right
away before they finish us.
Oh oh, no, oh my God.
This works!
Okay, we have to go.
I can not beat their speed.
We have to go, go up to my back.
- I'd rather die.
- Come on my back.
No, I'll just die.
Put me down, drop me!
I do not think it looks
like this eventually.
No, no, no.
- We have to jump.
- Are you crazy?
We have no way other
than jump now.
- Jump!
- What the fuck!
We have to jump.
We do not even know the
depth of the water.
- We have to jump.
- No, I do not want to jump.
Jump, jump!
Ah, I think I got my gout.
It was the most embarrassing
moment of my life.
I will not do that again.
I'm most afraid of water.
He got me.
Oh no.
Martha?
Hey what just happened?
Is he dead? Is he dead?
Wait a moment.
What's that?
- You land on my back.
- You okay?
- I think.
- Get rid of.
- You're okay?
- You want to kill me?
Do you want to kill me?
As I thought. Remember
our initial fall from
the sky, this little
tattoo till our arm.
By God, have you seen this?
Spencer.
What do you say?
This is our life count.
Bethany eaten by kudanil
so stay 2 lines.
He is right.
Briefly, what happens if
all the lines are gone?
Well that means gameover.
What do you mean game over?
Do you mean we can
actually die here?
- I mean I'm not sure.
- You're not sure?
You're not sure Mr. Video Game?
Well, I'm also stuck here, okay?
But I think yes, we can die.
That is my biggest concern now.
We should find a way out.
Okay.
There seems to be another
village behind this mountain.
Maybe it's the village.
- Let's do it.
- Wait a minute, I have to urinate first.
I've been holding it all day,
but I can not take it anymore.
Can I come with you
and show you how?
I might need your help.
Oh yes, sure, I'll help.
So how do I do that?
Just a little bit out.
Remember to navigate,
it's very important.
Oh my God, you are serious, there
is a penis attached to my body.
- Martha, look at my cock.
- No thanks.
Is this the first
time you saw it?
Yes, this is the first
time I've seen it.
I've seen it when I was in junior
high school, that's a great thing.
Are you .. what are you doing?
Did you see it?
- Okay.
- Do not look here.
You never see, that's important.
Okay, good boy, we'll slow down
slowly, hopefully not hurt.
- Now what?
- Navigate, do not forget to point.
What's wrong with redirecting?
What's wrong with you?
Can we not discuss
this all the time?
Wow, wow, wow.
Oh this is much easier!
- Cool right?
- Yes, because it's so easy to set up.
The fact I'm holding the
penis is now so crazy.
Where is the stone?
In a safe place.
They are blurry?
We lost them in the forest.
I already know.
What do you mean sir?
I want every creature and
every soldier to hunt them.
Take what is mine.
Find them.
Be careful with the
land of friends.
The ground is slippery, I do not want
you to wound ankle anymore here.
- We can walk anyway.
- Okay.
- Hey can I borrow your coat? Thanks.
- Yes of course.
- What are you doing?
- I feel I'm wearing a bikini at school.
I did that once, they
saw me like anything.
Of course. - You know it's when you show
your skin, it's like in a relationship.
Really? Seriously, I
can not open my mouth
around you, you do not
know me but you hate me.
Wow, a moment, I
do not hate you.
- Really?
- No.
I just thought you were
like a popular girl,
everybody treats you
special, like princess.
Maybe that's what makes you
think about yourself, maybe?
That's fair.
But do you think maybe the
reason you are so judgmental...
is because you see people not like
you so you do not like them first?
No.
Maybe. Maybe.
Okay then.
I just said you're
good, that's all.
Thanks.
I think.
- Get away from me, Spencer.
- Why are you so mad at me?
My friend, do you
really ask me that?
You got me kicked out of school,
and you got me stuck here.
Oh we're not friends anymore, because
you're stuck in Jumanji? I do not think so.
We are not friends anymore because I'm
not cool enough to hang out with you.
So you pretend you do
not know me anymore.
So you can do your homework
yourself, because you're a crap.
And you do not know anything
about school lessons.
What did you say?
You know, I'm not
stupid, Spencer.
I want you to do one thing
only, I said do my homework
so you can go in the team
and you screw it all up.
And I can not come back
again and it is your fault.
I should be kidding you now.
- I want to see you try it.
- What did you say?
Oh okay.
- I see what's going on here.
- Comrade friends.
Do you think you're 6 feet 5 inches, 270
pounds of muscle all so I'm scared of you?
What do you think it is?
Maybe?
I said something to you. You're still the
annoying kid I've known since grade 7.
You never change.
Do not let your new
body make you arrogant.
Stupid.
No, no!
Spencer!
- You killed him!
- You're crazy!
Calm down, she'll come back.
- Do not call me stupid.
- Do not push me.
- Or what, Spencer?
- Or I'll push you back.
Did you just slap me?
You're hitting me?
Fridge, no.
I will beat you.
Enough!
We can not waste our lives.
We need each other,
like it or not.
We should do this together.
Can you say that again?
We should do this together?
But with the low
tone you just did.
That happens naturally.
What should we do here?
Look for the missing
folder section.
Can not we just ask?
No, I think we are around, see see
and most importantly, my friends ..
We just relax.
Fresh, fresh bread!
Does anyone have any money?
I'm really starving.
Get your fresh bread.
Friend, I think the game is
trying to tell us to stay ..
- We have to ..
- Stop doing that.
Oh my God is so good, I have
not eaten bread since 9 years.
- Are you serious?
- Do I look like kidding?
Let me try a bit.
Wait... what is this?
That is my favorite cake.
Cake?
But you said this was Bread.
I have not eaten until
I forget the taste.
I do not even ..
- Did something happen to me?
- No.
- Am I shaking?
- Am I weird?
- No.
- Am I still black?
- Yes.
Okay, okay buddy.
I'm fine, all is well.
No, no, no, I just found out I
like cake so I can not hold it.
Hey, all okay.
What's that?
As I said, you have
to be careful.
- When did you say that?
- Fresh bread.
Get out of here!
Dr. Bracer, thank God you're
here, Jumanji needs you.
Friend, have you heard this?
Ask him about missing part.
Oh right, hey, I'm Bethany.
I mean professor Sherly .. something, I'm
a map doctor and I have a missing map.
Dr. Bracer, thank God you're
here, Jumanji needs you.
Really?
We need to find
the missing part.
What you need is in the basket.
One wrong move, you die.
Mutual trust and never leave.
The missing part is not
what you think it is.
Oh my goodness.
- Good luck my hero, you might ..
- You might need it.
You've said a few times.
So, do you think there's a
snake in there or something?
Yes, it sounds quite
dangerous to me.
Why should it be
imprinted on me?
Since you're the hero, you
heard he said, now take it.
I do not want to do this!
Just do it!
Black Mamba!
It is a Black Mamba.
According to research the
poison is not directly killing.
But first give the sensation of numbness,
then fever then lose control of muscle.
How do I know all that?
- What should we do?
- You see what else in there?
I do not see anything, I
do not have enough time.
Okay, trust each other
and never blink.
I understand, I think this
is a staring contest.
- What?
- What are you talking about?
- Think! Never blink.
- Guys, I think he's right.
I think the snake should
not move too much.
I think someone should look at the
snake directly. And not blinking.
And then Spencer has to reach in
and take whatever's inside there.
- Why me again.
- Because it's your mission.
Okay, then who will look
at him and not blink?
I'm good at doing that.
This is your moment.
Now.
What should we do?
- You should give it that.
- What?
You must remove the poison and in the
blind spot to avoid being seen by it.
We must be careful because
he could suddenly move.
We have to break it.
I got this.
It's not a glaring contest.
Trust each other
and never blink.
You believe me and
I broke the snake.
I did it, I succeeded.
- Yes.
- Yeah you did it.
- Thanks.
- Oh yes, of course.
Hey buddy, this does
not look like a map.
The missing part
of the elephant?
Something is written
on this paper ..
When you see me,
start the ascent.
Start the ascent?
When you see an elephant?
Or elephant.
Oh you have to find elephants I
think, for the next level of play.
Hey!
Run.
Watch out!
Stop! By Guavaberry.
Watch out! Watch out! Beware!
I have to warn you, I think
I have a strong fist.
Trim.
> Trim, block, block.
Uppercut.
Evade. Hit the head.
Kapow!
Evade. Block.
Flip.
Backward, fist.
Throw!
That's great.
Let's do this.
Do what?
Put it in my bag.
Evade. Hit the head.
Throw up!
Hello doctor.
Been a long time.
I'm sure you have
something of mine.
We just want to go home.
Come on, follow me fast.
Capture them.
Come on, come on, come!
Come!
Go down, let's hurry.
Find them!
Okay follow me, we'll be safe.
Let's go.
Oh my God, I'm so glad
you will not know.
- Really?
- Very strong.
I mean I saw you in the bazaar,
and I figured, not possible.
But I think, yes that's right,
is now close to the wall.
Oh my God.
Let's go ahead.
- Be careful.
- Who are you?
- Yeah what are you thinking about?
- Correct. Sorry okay.
Let me explain a little.
What are you waiting for the pilot?
Who flew the plane?
- Yes, it's me.
- Wait for you to be here too?
- Step back 1 step and stop.
- Why?
Very scary.
That's terrible.
Wait.
Okay, let's take this board.
Follow me.
Be careful. That's a
terrible way to die.
That's right.
Come on.
I can, I can.
Cliffs, snakes, and more.
Okay.
Hello.
Yes.
Come on.
By the way, I'm Alex.
Spencer.
Martha, Fridge and Bethany.
Bethany.
- You're a girl?
- Women.
In real life you probably
will not listen to that.
They escaped, it looks
like they have help.
Stupid ..
They must have fled
through the aisle.
Sorry boss.
That will not happen again.
I know.
We succeed.
Margarita, that's
one of my skills.
That and fly the plane.
Although I was shot by some
Orangutans and fighter jets.
So .. Maybe not so great right?
However, toast.
- Thanks.
- Of course.
- I never drank alcohol before.
- Me too.
- You know what? No problem!
- Cheers!
- And I've had enough of that.
- This is good.
Can I ask again?
- Alex. From what is this candle?
- This?
Uh citronela, one of my
weaknesses is mosquito,
Which is a bit sad when you live
alone in the open in the forest.
You are single.
Who is this?
Who is Alan Parrish?
He's the person who
built this place.
Do you mean anyone else
is stuck here too?
Yes, I mean this is Alan Parrish's house.
I'm just riding.
So Alex told me how long
have you been in this game?
Uh hard to say. Time is not fun here.
But a few months I think.
- A few months?
- What?
Yes I do not have any
means of transportation.
Transportation? What's that?
Next level.
The first time I had a
balloon fly and leave.
Then, the whole plane and so on.
And when I stay has 1 more life.
I realize I'm in trouble.
And I will not get
out of here alone.
If there is something that is
eyeing me, I can not handle it.
You can not kill Black
Mom with a margarita.
Yes you can.
You need an animal
expert for that.
Alex, we can help each other.
You've been here a long time, and
among us we have a lot of power.
Yes, that's right.
I do not know bung, if I
die once more, I lose.
It really scares me to even
think back to that transport.
I do not want to die in Jumanji.
We just need to stay together.
We do that and we can
win, I know that.
Oh my God.
You are our missing part.
You are the person
we need to find.
This does not make sense, we go to the
bazaar and find the missing pieces?
It's not an elephant.
- That's me.
- Yes.
Good.
- Let's do this.
- Yes.
Hey you gonna drink
that margarita again?
This is a nice margarita.
That's it.
Transportation place.
There is also a vehicle there.
We have to pick it up, cross the
valley, and go to the jaguar statue.
Okay I see the place of
transportation, I see
the valley, but I can
not see the statue.
And that's weird, because it's the most
important thing in Jumanji, and that's big.
Like you.
You're drunk Fridge?
- No, I'm not drunk.
- He's drunk.
I only drank 3 margaritas.
Well you're 3 times bigger
than your actual size.
Whatever, whatever. - Okay Alex what
should we do? How do I get past the guard?
Last time I waited
for them to leave.
- How long?
- 3 weeks.
Oh we will die.
- Ok plan B.
- There might be another door there.
But we have to distract
the person first.
I know.
Distracting is what I do.
He's playing video
games, I'm distracting.
Bethany, I hate to
say this to you now.
But you now have no um ..
Opportunity for that.
Not me.
What?
- You have to go down and seduce them.
- No.
- And grab their attention as we enter.
- No!
I can not just go there and seduce
some strange warrior I do not know.
I know, but now we
have no other ideas.
I understand, but I
can not do that.
I can not talk to
men, I'm bad at it.
I'll give you some directives.
No sorry. We have to think of other
plans, no, I will not do that.
You just need to distract them
for a while until we get in.
I can not Spencer, I'm not .. I'm
not a really beautiful lady.
What do you think?
You're really great.
You can do anything.
That's lovely Spencer, why do not
we make you a romantic dinner?
Or you can go from here.
Okay, show me how.
Class starts immediately.
Okay in persuasion issue, the
key is to get them to see you,
Without letting them know
if you know they saw you.
You're like, it's me. And when they start
talking to you, do it in 3 things.
Decline, really interested,
or like a whore.
What you do depends on the
person you're dealing with.
This is like my dream
in my nightmare
I will not take it personally.
Now, hair is everything.
Touch it, move it.
Play with it, move a lot.
Give me that beat.
Okay now keep it
behind your ears.
Now, lower your head,
open wide eyes.
- Now shine.
- Shine?
Like anime characters,
now shine.
You need practice.
You really think he likes me?
Why are we still
talking about this?
- I mean what if he tried to kiss me?
- You just have to kiss it back.
I .. What if he tried to kiss
me, like, without warning?
What are you talking about?
You never kissed someone?
Do not... You're gonna
say that to everyone?
- Hey buddy, I found the door on the edge.
- Okay I'll tell them.
No, no, do not tell them.
Okay let's start your way.
Slowly slowly, make it
like an elegant deer.
Or a horse, step high.
One foot on the other.
And forward, bomb, bomb, not so.
And do whatever you can to grab his
attention, something like this.
You need a very long
time to do this.
Good, that's better.
Now smiling. You look scared.
- Oh you're so cute.
- You're so cute.
- I think I already understand.
- You can.
Now keep your lips
slightly open like this.
No, not disgusting, just relax.
Now touch the top of your mouth
with your tongue like this.
- Like this?
- Like this.
Like this.
Like this?
I thought you were ready.
- Good.
- Okay.
Make love like your life is at stake.
Because it's true.
Okay that's the door, we just
need something to cut the fence.
Okay, Fridge do you have something
for that in your backpack?
Yes, of course.
This .. I think I have ..
Some iron cutters.
Do you think that's good
for this situation?
Perfect is actually.
This is called the power
of the dear backpack.
Hey guys, I think it will work.
I also think so.
He's really great, and they do
not like meeting new people.
Great? - Well not like Cindy Crawford,
but for Jumanji, she's great.
- Bombs?
- Cindy Crawford?
- That's what you think?
- I just said that.
I'm sure they'll love it.
Alex.
What do you think is this year?
- What do you mean?
- Oh no.
This is 1996.
You're Alex Rigg is not it?
Yes, that's right.
What do you mean? Like
in that strange house?
Wait what are you talking about?
How do you know me?
- Alex, I do not know how to say this ..
- You were in this game for 20 years.
That may not be how
I would say it.
What?
No, you're kidding me right?
No, Alex Rigg, everybody
knows about you.
You're a lost child.
20 years ago.
20 years?
20 years old.
I do not even know how to say this but ..
Cindy Crawford is now 50 years old.
- But still sexy.
- Yes.
Yes ..
That's it.
Hey.
We will take you home.
Yes.
What happened to the butt?
Bethany what did you tell her?
- Is he sprained or maybe ..
- He can do it, just wait.
Hello little girl.
What are you doing here alone?
Hey you guys
I'm lost.
Can you help me?
Hello little girl.
What are you doing alone here?
You are very
interesting and funny.
What does he do?
There's an insect in his hair?
He forgot all his training.
Let's go.
Wait. I ..
I need to tell you about
the book I'm reading.
About microbiology.
It's related to my
secret biology.
Hello little girl.
What are you doing here alone?
You are a great woman.
(MUSIK)
Do you want to dance?
Which one, which one?
I hate this place.
Oh, that's a weird dancing game.
Alex, what do you think?
What's the plan?
- What?
- What do we take? Which one?
I do not .. I do not know, okay?
I told you ..
- We have to fly, right? Helicopter.
- I told you, I do not know.
He kicked their butt.
That's our friend.
Yes, great!
He destroyed them.
You're great, man!
Hurray!
Yes! Yes!
You are my hero.
We have to go.
You're great in a fight,
you're a great friend.
- Oh my God.
- You did it!
- I did it!
- Yes, give me a hug, mate.
Good we are hugging here, and that
makes us stupid, they've come.
The bike rider has
arrived, we have to go.
See, plane, we have
to fly, buddy.
No, I can not do that, okay.
I told you I'm not
a great pilot.
Maybe we should take
the school bus?
What? We can not keep them
away from that school bus.
You select the plane, maybe
we should use the helicopter.
No, I can not do it. OK?
I do not want to die.
I'm a little scared.
Okay, I'll do it.
How difficult to fly a helicopter, you
just press the button, it will spin ..
Okay, then I'll move ..
The lever, that's how
you back and forth.
Once we air, we'll all be fine.
I just .. I just need to go up,
because this has no ladder, so ..
Let me see, you know what,
I'll go in, be careful ..
- No, you're drunk.
- No.
Fridge, you're drunk.
Give me the key.
And Alex. Alex .. If I
can fight those guys...
You can fly this helicopter.
I know you can do it.
Come on.
Alex.
This is where we need you.
Remember the missing part.
Seaplane McDonough,
report for assignment.
Come on, guys.
Wow!
Wow, wow.
Oh!
I'm stuck.
- The controller is broken!
- What's your makasud?
Hold on!
Ow!
Oh God, we're gonna die!
We're going to die!
Oh God!
- This does not want to go up.
- What? What do you mean?
- The blades are damaged.
- What?
There should be a climb up
there and fix the propeller.
That's what makes
it up and down.
Hey, guys.
That can not be great.
It sure is bad.
Albino rhino!
They are rare animals, they
are big, white, and horrible.
No.
- They are getting closer.
- I'm getting a little conscious.
- Up!
- I can not ride!
I think I'm mostly drinking.
Hey, guys, what are we gonna do?
I will repair the helicopter.
- Yes!
- Tell me what I should do.
You must connect the control
cable to its rotor,
Control cable, phonograph record,
insert into rotor. - Wait, what?
I'll be right back.
Hey, where are you going?
Hang on!
- Be careful!
- He did not hear you.
I can fix this, I'll fix it,
it's just a helicopter.
It's a record,
it's a controller.
Spencer! Endure!
Spencer!
Quick!
We're out of the way.
Pull the lever!
What? We made it, I
think we'll die.
Comrades!
Yes!
Oops.
What?
I dropped the permissions.
- What?
- You dropped the eyes?
I lean back, I think I'll
throw up, but it does not.
And it fell out of my bag.
We need that gem!
I know.
That's the crazy part,
because I know we need it.
No. We're in trouble.
We're in trouble.
Alex, spin, we have to
go back and fetch it.
Yes, spin around.
Let's search it, everything open
your eyes, we work as a group.
There! I see it.
What are they doing?
It looks like they're
protecting it or something.
Okay, how are we
going to do this?
I do not know.
You're gonna take it,
do not you, buddy?
What do you need, boomerang, maybe
scissors, iron pipe, laces ..
I will help you, whatever you
need, I can get it for you, okay?
You select it.
- What?
- I'm sorry fella.
Sorry for what?
Alex, get ready
to turn sideways!
What?
As I give the
signal, turn right.
Now!
Oh, yes.
You pushed me out of the
helicopter, bastard!
Wow.
- You know, you're amazing.
- You're a great pilot, Alex.
And you're also
Spencer, you're great.
- Oh, thanks. But he is ..
- No, no, no. You ..
- You're doing great.
- Sorry Sorry. I am the one who sacrificed.
You do not know what it's like
to be on the rhino's side.
And you do not want to know.
I've seen a lot of things.
I immediately felt it.
Things that can never be
erased from my memory.
Oh, that's fun for you. Please laugh.
Come on.
Comrades, I have been trying for 20
years to cross this limit, okay?
Do you realize how big this is?
- What's happening.
- No!
No, no, no.
- Geez, no.
- Alex.
- Alex. No.
Alex, look at me. See me.
He's dying.
No, we can not let him die.
We're very close.
Does anyone know how to do
artificial respiration?
Yes, start by pressing the chest 3
times, and breathe through the mouth.
One, two, three.
How do you do this?
Okay, push his nose,
open his mouth, hold his
neck, one breath, two
breaths, and repeat.
Come on Alex.
Bethany, stop. Your tone.
Looks like you gave your life.
I'm okay with that.
What if you need to go home.
I want Alex to go home too.
What's happening?
Alex. Bethany gives
you one life.
Bethany are you okay?
I think so.
Bethany is that correct?
You gave me one of your lives?
I mean yes of course.
Thanks.
Wow, what do you guys see?
You have a problem.
Dear God, this thing is crazy!
20 years old, huh?
Yes. I think so.
You know, I keep thinking
of my poor parents.
What they experience.
And why, because I'm hiding in my
hideout, too afraid to finish the game.
Sorry.
I do not want to tell
you this, I just ..
You are very easy to talk to.
You know, I understand.
I mean .. sometimes, it's
easy to focus on yourself
so you forget that other
people have problems too.
That's very deep.
Thanks. I feel since I lost my phone, my
other senses are getting more sensitive.
Does the phone have any other
meaning in the future?
What about you, Alex?
What do you like.
In the real world,
what do you like.
I have a metal band. I'm
a drummer, like my dad.
Hey.
- Hey.
- What are you doing?
I .. I'm filling this out.
- Cool.
- Yes.
I'm glad you're here, I ..
There's something I
want to say to you.
Yes?
And I want to tell you now. Just
in case when we talk later ..
I no longer dare.
I like you, Martha.
I like, I have a crush on you.
Like very crush on you.
What?
Really.
And I've fancied since grade 7.
Really?
Wow, I think this never
happened before.
What do you mean? - I mean is .. no one
likes me, I can not believe I did this.
I .. I never told anyone
about my feelings.
I also have a crush
on you, Spencer.
- Really?
- Yes.
Yes! You're smart and
kind, and sweet.
Yes. I really fancy you.
Wait. You're sure this is
not because of... all this?
What? God, no. No,
that's not my type.
I like the nerds.
Really? I'm a nerd!
- That .. You never ..
- I never, I never kissed anyone.
- That's the first time. You ever?
- I have ever. No.
Okay. Nice. By Guavaberry.
Not visible right.
Oh, come on, hey!
I do not want to see that. I
do not want to, not today.
When you here confess your
love, I found the path.
Come on.
Dear God.
That's it.
We'd better start the path.
I think we should go
through this path.
No.
Can not be this easy.
The Defender.
What does it mean?
Only 1 way to find out.
Fridge. Give me the permission.
Spencer.
Oh.
Something will happen.
I do not like the drum.
Hey, you can not
just walk there.
No.
That's what this
game wants us to do.
Follow the path.
This is a trap.
You see the elephants
start climbing.
I will go up to the tree.
- Tree?
- Yes.
- Do you think that means?
- It's certain.
That's the way.
This is the last
resort of the game.
And I'm sure this is
what Bravestone does.
Did he just call himself
a third person?
Ehm .. I think the
fourth person.
Oh, how can he do that?
Climbing is one
of its strengths.
Ah .. I understand.
That means he is slow.
- No!
- Gosh!
Spencer!
God, he's met a panther.
No.
That sound cat.
Spencer!
Oh God, are you okay?
Yes, I think so.
You still have that gem, right?
- Yes.
- Thank goodness.
Hey, what happened?
I do not want to talk about it.
Okay, so we need a new plan.
- Right.
- Yes.
So is mine. Spencer,
you got an idea?
Can I talk to you for a while?
Now?
What's happening?
I can not do this.
- What are you talking about?
- I can not... do this.
Who do I lie to? I'm
not an adventurer.
- Actually I'm not brave.
- Spencer...
I just saw you hanging
on a helicopter.
It's easy to be brave if
you have a spare life.
Much more difficult if
you only have one life.
We... we have only
one life, dude.
Okay, that's... that's all we get.
It's been like that before.
The question is how
we will live it.
Depending on you you want
to be what kind of guy.
Did I just say some...
Gosh, this game is a hazard,
I have to get out of here.
Listen, we can do this, man.
We can do this together.
Together.
A good friend for adventurous.
Okay.
I did not know you
would be okay or not.
But all I know is football.
If the line means something...
they are the defenders.
Which means that
we have to break.
Everything...
We need to go.
Okay, here's what we'll do.
We will play whatever
it is called.
To double the chance of winning.
Betty, you're on the left.
I'm on the right.
Alex, you will venture deep
into the middle of the forest.
I'm leaving with Spencer.
No. There's something
else she should do.
Are you ready to dance?
Hey! Over here!
Let's get me!
- Thanks.
- Of course.
Go to its center. Hurry!
Oh, dude.
Okay, it's in action.
Stop!
Are these elephants and mice?
How are you, Mouse Finbar.
Animal observer. Observer of
animals and men's backpack.
Give me permission,
or your friend is dead.
- Do not give it to him.
- Shut up!
Stop!
Take me instead, okay?
Give me permission.
I can not do that.
5...
- 4...
- I can not give you the wishes.
3...
- Spencer.
- 2...
Because I do not have it.
Animal observer, shit.
Oh, no, no!
Elephant.
Start climbing.
Climb to it, and I'll get
the permission for you.
- Martha.
- Believe me, I'll get it for you.
- Okay.
- Now.
Come on, Martha!
I'll take that.
The game is over.
I do not think so.
That's why I'm going to do this.
Oh, Spencer.
No.
- Good!
- Wow!
Okay!
Call his name!
Call his name, all!
Jumanji!
- I think we made it.
- I think we won.
I think we beat it.
Friends, it's Nigel.
Nigel.
Excellent, trapped adventurer.
You removed the curse.
The entire population
of Jumanji thanked you.
Your task here is done.
So unfortunately, this is
where we will split up.
Seaplane McDonough.
I'll shake your hand.
Alex...
Please Professor Oberon.
Let's do this.
- I will miss you very much...
- Hurry me out of here.
See you, Ruby Roundhouse.
Wait.
Why should we go back?
I just...
I like to be like this.
Along with you.
Then... let's keep it this way.
Everyday.
Let's go home.
Doctor Bravestone...
Nigel...
I'm ready to go home.
See you, my dear friend.
Bye, Bravestone.
- Gosh...
- Good, good, good...
I'm back, man!
I will never complain about my
body again forever. I'm grateful.
I miss you.
Where is Alex?
Hey, see...
Are you afraid?
What do you think...
That means... it's possible...
Alex?
Hey, Daddy, can you
come here and help me?
Yes.
Hey, dad, can you
give me a minute?
- Oh yes, of course.
- I'll be right back.
Bethany?
Spencer?
Yeah.
Ruby Roundhouse?
And that would make you Fridge.
I'm surprised to see you guys.
All of you.
Then you get back.
Yes, that's right.
This makes me startled,
when I see it, so...
Oh, yes, everything's
fine, buddy.
Now you're an adult.
You have a baby.
Yes, that's right.
This is Andy.
And my daughter's name... my
daughter's name is... Bethany.
We renamed it the name of a
woman who saved my life.
This makes me happy.
Yo.
Impressive.