Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Thanks for Dutch srt dude! Translated by yusof125 with subtitle edit 3.2.8
Maribu's at six o'clock.
There is food for a week in that basket.
Unpack them.
They walk into.
Shake your tail feathers, Gogo.
Take it.
Touched.
Gogo, we just become aunts.
Hold.
- Seize them.
The eggs are beaten here.
Stay away, brutally.
Hold on tight, kids.
Severe turbulence for us.
Do not worry, Tini.
I take us to Zambezia.
Quality over Quantity (QoQ) ® eleases
Zambezia (2012)
Translation: Pink Jay
Control: Smokey
Come back.
Not your best landing.
- Daddy, what did you expect?
You can not just call
at me when I'm in the zone.
What, the Twilight Zone?
I did not know we now hunt giraffes.
I just tried something else.
Good thing you had a helmet on.
- I got nothing.
Come on, time for a real exercise.
Daddy, you're fast for an old bird.
Your father still has a few good moves
.
Why do not you go to the side
and see how I do it.
When you were a chick was
you had not such a big mouth.
But then I was not so fast.
Not bad for an old bird.
Come on.
- I'm right behind you.
Let's high-speed six
start.
Let me look upward
airflow control.
I will.
Keep the distance fixed.
- Held.
Connect the wings and...
Diving.
A crocodile, two crocodile...
- Three crocodile, four crocodile...
Five crocodile.
- Open your wings.
Pull on.
I did it.
I can not believe I have succeeded.
What was that?
- I did it.
Do you consider yourself dead injagen?
- Five crocodiles.
That's gotta be a new record.
Did you see that?
I saw a bruiser an idiotic stunt.
Where do you think I have to train?
For the fastest lizard hunter to be.
I do not know.
I try just fun.
I know, Kai, but...
Once you take care of yourself.
Because nobody else will.
Of course, Dad, whatever you say.
- How about lunch?
I got your favorite, insects surprise.
They go somewhere.
Why do we never go anywhere?
I've never even been outside the boundary.
There is no reason for it.
We have everything to survive.
Is it only that?
Only survive?
Did mother that?
Sorry, Dad, I did not say.
Why do not check the fence
.
I'm doing the rounds along the border.
- I'll go with you.
Check the fence but.
Boy, go check the fence.
The third time this week.
Mighty Fortress sticks.
Why do I say that?
Call Mommy, make the fence.
It's just a comparison.
Protect against the beasts.
Mayday. Take landing position.
- Hold on.
The only thing that is
bandits to eat my dust.
No.
I have the body of an old woman.
You're an old woman.
Hello, the egg.
- Right. Sorry, of course. Here.
Hello, boys.
Cute, is not it?
You have a friend for life.
I will have to make that crack.
Those thieving Maribu's.
Can you do that?
- She made the whole basket.
Where are you from?
Are you visiting someone?
I can not.
We are the only one here, so...
Are you in transit, or...
- We are on a mission.
We save these poor babies
for those bandits out there.
Where are you taking them now?
In Zambezia. - There is no
safer place across Africa.
Zambezia?
Where is that?
What are you saying?
Have you ever heard of the bird city?
We continued our course than I thought.
Darlings, it seems that
Tonight we fly by.
Wait, why rush?
We will never visit, stay here tonight.
What? Where should a large
bird as I sleep?
Do not worry, we make place.
It's not much but it's our home.
The ducklings can use the rest.
I can hardly see at night.
Well, that's a plan.
My name is Kai. Kai, the guy in the air.
So would my friends call me,
if I had friends.
I do not know how long I can keep him here.
He wants to see the world.
Other birds meet.
A free spirit, just like his mother.
I was too harsh.
And all that food.
I'm talking about nuts from Nigeria.
Seeds of Sudan, Burundi bananas.
Snails of Swaziland.
Swaziland? Where is that?
Are we there?
Look at these two, are not they cute?
We have future Hurricanes.
Hurricanes?
The Hurricanes patrolling the air.
They protect Zambezia.
Hurricanes are the best racers across Africa.
The eggs protect the orphans save
fight against the bad guys...
And the big city?
A Hurricane have would be great.
Wait, anyone to Zambezia?
Of course, there are all kinds together.
Well, almost any kind.
Except wanted Maribu's horrible.
Who are you?
- You thought we could escape?
Ten attack.
You do not get them while I'm waiting.
We want only the delicacy of that basket.
If we can solve this civilized
no one will get hurt. Understood?
To you is nothing civilized.
Stay away from her.
Daddy.
- What are you doing here?
Do not fight, I'm trying to help.
My dear brother.
Stay away from me.
I did what I could.
You brought this on yourself.
- You raptors are all the same.
He was just hungry.
We all have.
Maribu if we are already suffering enough.
Why us?
Here you will pay.
- Tendai?
Tendai, are you really?
After all these years?
Kai, I told you
no strangers to take home.
Aliens.
Come little ones, it's time to go.
No way, you just got here.
What was that all about?
Wait. Do you know her?
Maribu And who knew you.
The fence must be repaired.
Dad, come on, forget the fence.
Talk to me.
Did you Zambezia off?
You knew.
All these years and you've never told me
?
I have my reasons.
What reason have you to keep me here?
I do what's best for you.
The best for me?
Look for you. I have...
No friends and nothing to do, no life.
How can it best for me.
Gogo said ..
You never had her in our house to let.
If you have other birds
helps you get only in trouble.
But in Zambezia they Hurricanes.
Here we would all have no problems.
I'll tell you how it goes in Zambezia.
The strong as we protect the weak.
And who dies eventually?
We. Trust me
.
You do not know what you're talking about.
Yes, but I'll tell you what I know.
There is more to life than you,
your fences and your limits.
There is a whole world outside Khartoum.
Let's go to Zambezia. You, me and...
- I'll never go back there.
Then I'm sorry. Day in, day out,
teach me taking care of myself.
Maybe it's time I'm gonna do.
You know where to find me.
I do what's best for you.
Sorry, Dad, I need to do this.
With or without you.
Greetings, what do
above all alone?
I am looking Zambezia.
Then you go in the right direction on
. But you'd better...
Fly with us or you'll really tired.
Do not worry about me,
I'm used to fly alone.
Are we almost there?
- What will you do in Zambezia?
I would like for the Hurricanes.
A small bird with big dreams.
- Something like that.
Look.
I'm a Hurricane.
I'm depressed.
I am very depressed.
You know what I like to do when I'm down?
Food.
Try these little fellows here. Those who...
Why us?
They have the nerve to call us bandits.
Enter.
And now one of them...
Robbed me of my only brother.
And now I'm...
Only in the world.
Well, not entirely alone.
You have me, your fourth cousin.
Once removed, that's something, is not it?
Death is normal.
- Budzo.
It is part of the life cycle.
The last part.
I should not be so hard on him to be
.
Where is he?
He ​​can not be far.
Budzo.
I'm too tired to stand in the cold...
And cliques to fight, while
Zambezia thicker.
I love leftovers. You see, sir Budzo...
We are scavengers.
Yes, we eat carrion.
Right Cecil?
But all the things we could do together.
The Maribu's would have
the roots can dominate.
We are actually more a duo.
We have it all worked out.
So...
A trio, yes, that's better.
Strength in numbers. Cooperation.
Think about everything that you
so long denied.
Good food, good nests.
It is time that kingdom for yourself to take.
In order to rule on Zambezia.
- With a parliamentary system?
A coup.
That sounds good.
I take only a small share of the spoils.
Finally, how many eggs can a lizard eat
?
Collect all Maribu's.
Tell them that night they should work.
Nights are not good for me.
- I, as ruler?
I like to sleep.
Imagine the possibilities.
The pah, the prestige...
- The pudding.
No? Would not it help?
He's gone.
Look at that. The great Tendai.
It's us.
Training you or something?
This is heavy cardio sport.
Morning I do not eat much, you know.
Go into the slipstream fly. Go.
This is cool.
It is easier to get there, right?
Kai, we are there.
- That big old tree?
That's Zambezia.
- Where is the city?
Make jokes but, countryside bird.
Hey, your beak hanging open.
Job free for the landing.
- I'm coming.
Babies on board.
- I know her.
Gogo lands.
All hands on deck.
Crazy people. I need a cracker.
Stay close to me, we're going to land.
Seagulls have delayed
get and 15 minutes later.
Here you get value for your money.
The yellow zone is only
for students and owls.
Five children. One, two,
three, I miss a child.
Gogo, wait.
Thanks for the lift, Pavi.
Enjoy the big city.
We'll see you at the Spring Festival.
Careful with my eggs.
Watch where you fly, fly
is prohibited.
Sorry.
- Welcome in Zambezia.
The famous bird city.
Have you anything to declare?
I certify that this great city.
- Your name, sir?
Kai. Ouch, what are you doing?
It's just a small sample
, standard.
Dodo, give it to the school office off.
If you are looking for accommodation can I Mushana's proposals?
And if you need a guide...
- Stadsbezichtingen.
Okay, write me at.
- One more question.
You do not have a spring.
- No, no.
How long do you stay here?
- I do not know.
I think forever.
- Inhabitants, congratulations.
Citizen?
- You're the emigration.
I did it.
I am a real Zambeziër.
A Zambeziaan.
A Zambo...
I am one of you.
And where should the tire?
Here?
Good.
Perhaps the caterer
eating here drop.
Let the weaver birds here the flowers go?
Zoe?
Sorry. It sounds good.
- Which part?
All. I think we should do so.
You did not listen, do you?
The Spring Festival is the same every year, dad.
You do the
details to worry.
It is great.
It is great because we
us worry about the details.
Master Sekhuru, a new resident.
Thanks, Dodo.
It's a while since we had a falcon in Zambezia.
He's here for the audition
of the Hurricanes. That is tomorrow.
Wild you get to the team up?
- I, a Hurricane?
Who wants to fly abroad,
I've got too much to do.
We need to plan a party, right?
- You're probably right.
Besides, I'm happy under your wings.
Who cares for whom?
- Sekhuru, you'll never guess who I just saw.
Not in a million years.
Council, council, I can tell you.
Okay, I'll tell you.
Hello, Zoe.
Do not worry,
Gogo, I was just going.
You'll never guess.
- Was the Tendai?
What? How did you know?
- Because his son has just arrived.
How do you know so much?
You never go anywhere.
Where is he?
- Far from civilization.
It's called  Kathungu. With his son Kai.
- Kai has followed you here, it seems.
And Tendai? Do you think he is?
He was still angry, Sekhuru.
I think we will not see
provisionally.
Kai is perhaps
looking for answers.
Will you tell him?
- No, I promised.
But if there is a reason for Tendai
to come back...
Would be to pick up his son.
We wait and hope.
Mushana's,
your place in the sun.
Do you work here?
How are you? Excuse me, sorry.
- Looking nest for the night?
You again?
Only number 87 is still free.
The double-deluxe suite.
I'll take him.
Okay, where is it? Double-luxurious.
Here it is. The large.
The-luxury.
Here I can get used to it.
Hi, okay, I think we can share...
You too?
All of you?
- The bed is so...
The whole family?
- Feathered.
We're all in this together.
It is the double-deluxe.
Look, they have peppermint
on the pillow.
This is not peppermint.
Ezee, night tours...
Now exclusively daytime.
Nest 87. Is there a Mr. Kai present?
Mr. Kai sleeps.
Okay, poultry, out.
Hurry up, I have work to do.
Can I check-out later?
Welcome to Ezee Nocturnal Tours.
Now the safety...
Exclusive daytime.
Can you come back later?
- You ordered the tour.
Yes, but not at dawn.
- Actually you have done that, man.
Read the small print.
- Okay, who's that?
I am. I made it myself.
Are you jealous?
The name Ezee. Ezee is the company.
What brings you to Zambezia?
I had a change of scenery, I think.
Marvel.
For there is no better place than this.
I do not remember your name.
- It Ezee.
Beautiful, what is it?
- Ezee.
You do not get me to rub,
I'm new here. - My name Ezee.
Do you do all day?
- I hope not.
I am Kai from Kathungu.
Never heard of it.
But you now comes from Zambezia.
Time to the city on the
Ezee way to discover.
Countryside Bird, you know
how long we've been working on?
Sorry, let us get carried away, you know.
Ezee  showed me the city
view. Ezee on the way.
Just what we need, another Ezee.
I'm not Ezee, I am Kai.
Give him some space,
he is new in town.
As you take it easy
did the weaver birds and I were at work.
I must say, it was fun, but...
We must continue with the tour.
Should not we stay and the nice young lady...
Help? What's her name?
Believe me, the longer we stay,
the more damage we cause. Let's go.
I prefer frozen.
I mean, you got the worm first wash.
And then she says...
Spot not my voice. And I say,
I'm a mockingbird,
I can not help it.
You're not a mockingbird.
- A third of my mother's side though.
About  mother speaking...
The island of milk and babies.
- Fly on, little bird.
Or just go to the side, so I...
Handsome young falcon can see.
Who's your new friend?
Shake with that tail.
- I knew it, my friend.
You bring me luck.
Are the Hurricanes?
- Yeah, boy the Hurricanes.
The wildest birds in the air,
I've learned all my movements.
Gogo was right. They are great.
No, you're in Zambezia.
Here we say great. Try it.
- Amazing.
There is still hope for you, friend.
Excuse me, to hear, to hear.
Collecting boys.
Nigel, you too.
Beaks closed, ears open.
Friends, strays, Maribu's...
Zambezianen  when gathered, they created a
inside...
Inside.
- And outside.
Outside.
- If you had not noticed...
We are on the outside.
- Here we are.
In the cold, desolate, outside.
- In the cold Africa.
And why?
- I do not know. That is a mystery.
Because they did not like our appearance.
What is wrong with our appearance?
They want the tree house all to themselves
. How sporty is that?
Very sporty.
- Not really.
No, sorry.
- Not really. In my book.
And that's exactly why we should accept the proposal
of Budzo.
Since when are Maribu's servants
of a lizard. - He's got a point.
We work together with Budzo, idiot.
Not for him.
We are partners in this great undertaking.
Yes, teamwork.
We help Budzo on the island to get
and we share...
All good things.
Yes, I get hungry when I think of it.
Question. Would those Hurricanes
be a problem?
Hurricanes?
- Make him not to laugh.
Budzo possesses unrivaled brute force.
So we need help.
A new wind blowing through this valley
.
A wind of change.
Good impact. Give another.
Take it.
Boys anyway.
Worthless.
Does that door the prescribed weight?
I swear it smaller.
Hurricanes ready.
- How to become a Hurricane?
Have you not seen the posters? She hung everywhere.
Which posters?
- This.
I should have hung.
- Hurricane audition today?
Where?
- On the southwestern platform...
Man, just take a
poster. If you hurry...
You on time. Say that Ezee you send.
You know what, let's say that you do not know me.
Maybe you should not mention my name
.
Forget it. Hey, nuts.
And that recruits, the race field.
I told you he would not come.
He ​​is too busy to take it easy.
Racers ready.
Burger, this is forbidden.
Only Hurricanes and new recruits are allowed.
But I'm here to take the test to explain.
- Your name is not on my list.
Can you not set up?
- No, I'm sorry.
The rules state that no tenders
done, after the designated...
Look at that, just in time.
Fortunately for you, I love punctuality.
Go stand in line.
You have the entire process
accountable and back.
If you do not make it, you fail.
On your mark.
Ready. Beginning.
And there they go.
with firm braking
they fly straight into the first.
Gondo, shoot away from the group.
next, my personal favorite,
the chicane.
Excuse me.
Gondo still has the lead.
Now comes the infamous tornado tunnel test.
This is my friend.
Come on, Kai.
They go into the vertical track.
The first is, Kai.
The small falcon. I can not believe it.
Where did he come from?
The've met the selection, recruit.
Your movements are unorthodox.
You improvise, you think creatively,
I do not like that.
But you can be proud, a Hurricane,
recruit to be.
Recruit? I am not a Hurricane?
- That's the spirit.
It takes more than a race...
To join...
Of the most elite racing power of the world.
Well done, Kai.
We expect a lot from you, young falcon.
I will not disappoint you, sir.
Me? No, Kai, set Zambezia not disappoint.
Zambezia always comes first.
Remember that.
I love watching you, fast guy.
We go at dawn maribupatrioulle.
You better go to sleep. Recruits
sleep down there.
Arise.
Budzo.
- Comfortable, old friend?
It's nice to see a familiar face.
To be honest, you look stressed.
I Zambezia long ago.
I just want my son
get and go home.
I'm no threat to you.
There is still fighting spirit in you.
I see it, even if you can not.
And that's good, because you'll need it
.
You will see me in good stead.
We received the message that the Maribu's upstream active.
We will in sector six patrol
and there in sector seven.
Apparently this is a big swamp.
This is a stain.
Who has a stain on my card made?
We concentrate our eyes and our ears look good on.
I mean, watch out caps
and our ears...
Where they should be.
Torn.
Beware, Hurricanes.
Can we help you, ma'am?
- My Neville floats down the river.
I would recommend against dangerous currents.
Why I can not catch him.
- I am obliged...
By city regulations,
concerning the rescue...
A minor,
permission.
He is not a minor, he is my husband.
Hurricanes, rescue mission.
Recruit, that's not the right direction.
A crocodile, two alligator, three alligator...
Crocodile Six, seven crocodile, crocodile
eight... gotcha.
Thank God. If you give me that again call at
.
Hug me.
Good news, is not it?
He came like a stone falling from the sky.
- The rookie has skills.
You gotta learn that movement.
Attention.
I will keep you alert.
I'm coming.
Hey, buddy. This is my size.
The star of heaven.
Get out, uk.
- Where's the captain?
Do you have a license for this party?
The music is not according to specifications.
And the pleasure zone behind the yellow line.
Ezikiel, what are you doing here?
I'm with him, sir.
- Really? Recruit, is this your friend?
Evacuation Procedures.
Come on, friends. This need not be so?
So won, so clotted.
Birds from every nation,
get together for lentecelebratie...
That rhymes.
Come on everyone, this is a mix to be mixed
.
Do not be shy, we are all friends.
Slide to Please,
we have limited space.
Always striking coming, huh?
I'm sorry about last,
I am more accustomed to open spaces.
Then you are at the wrong party.
Where's your wingman?
It's a long story.
Only one day Hurricane
and he rescues a bird.
True?
- I'm just a recruit.
Gogo, I need to ask you something.
How do you know my father?
Long story.
- Gogo, tell me.
Silent now. listen to Sekhuru.
- I want to welcome...
You all, in
Spring Festival this year.
Together we celebrate the future generations of Zambezia.
Grab any weefvogel.
Gotcha.
- Good men, we have them.
Weefvogels, let the flowers go.
Here's something wrong.
The weefvogels never miss the signal.
Maribu's.
Tini.
Gogo, save the babies.
Not panic, the Hurricanes will get them.
Tini.
Stay in formation.
- They escape.
Wear them away.
No.
If you come closer let me...
Oh, jeez.
What are you doing?
Tini.
I will bring them to the last feather pluck.
Come on.
You have guts.
We will not do anything anyway.
We will never...
Tendai?
Tini?
- Do you know who that is?
You're dumber than I thought.
- What a big bill, do not you, Cecil?
She keeps talking and does not stop.
She goes on.
They should always have the last word.
Well, well.
Cecil, I'll be honest,
I did not think that you would succeed.
Exactly, yes. And now what?
Shall we weefvogels
a few coats to weave?
Now they Budzo bridge and weaving.
For you? Never.
- Cecil, the weefvogels rebel.
Do you see him? A double meaning.
Naughty thieves.
Their kind will never change.
My dear little Tini.
- They started.
Now we finish it.
- They're still angry...
That they were excluded from the founding of the city.
Many years ago.
I never thought that she would humiliate themselves to this.
An interesting situation.
You need some motivation.
And I get hungry.
- No.
No, wait.
- Do not listen to him, Tini.
Leave him alone. We will do it.
Make sure the bridge is strong enough...
To get me on that island.
Time for desserts.
- Wait, he gets a dessert?
I would also like pudding.
Chocolate perhaps with a cherry...
Our first priority is the
weefvogels unharmed back.
Our actions should not be guided by blind rage.
What would you have me do, Sekhuru?
- The Maribu are sloppy, yes.
Uncivilized, of course, but they have never
such devious actions.
Maybe insert a bigger plan behind.
- A reconnaissance mission. Confirmed.
Hurricanes ready.
No, no, not you, fast guy.
You need every bird that...
By your action
was almost a basket with weefvogels slain.
So you stay here, sir.
Let's see if you can handle
cleaning service.
Featherweight.
- He better stay behind.
It is truly a tragedy.
- A drama? Tell me about it.
It's not safe.
Let's take yellow today.
Yellow?
It's like I told Larry, who
Maribu's, yuck dirty.
You can not trust them.
- No, my cousin is married one.
He went off with their eggs.
- I'm not surprised.
How about some help?
They call that help,
where you come from?
I am a night hawk. I have both eyes
sight of a hawk.
In the night. It was a mess.
Hi Ezee. How is it, friends?
It is, 'how are you' and 'my friend'.
- Sorry, mate.
I had to stand up for you.
- No, you seemed confused.
Did you know Hurricanes free food?
- The recruits also?
How about a snack?
Do you by me a
sticky moth to give...
I'll get back with open arms?
How about two?
Welcome back.
I thought you were gone forever.
I knew you did not in
might abandon.
This is the Ezee. You said that you
nocturnal excursions kept?
I can not believe you me here...
've Brought.
I am allergic to danger.
We would nevertheless only a
look? I had...
Can know that you're a
magnet makes me.
Zoe.
- It works now al
Kai, you're grounded.
You can not be here.
Moreover, you will get lost.
I think think she likes you, friend.
- No.
I get it,
there anyone here wants to be a Hurricane.
I fly here often.
- Because you want to be a Hurricane.
That will never happen.
- You are now on a mission.
Come on, the night vision of Ezee
we will find weefvogels.
Do you hear that?
Of course I heard him,
I have night hearing.
Do you see anything?
- No, nothing.
Only a couple of trees, stones
and a bunch Maribu's.
Maribu's.
Still, you know what "concealed" means?
That I
home under the blankets should lie.
I can not hear what they say.
That's because we're too far away.
Do not go.
Yes, he goes to them.
This is not a look.
Kai, we need help.
At work, guys.
The weefvogels have
more grass.
Have you heard Cecil?
- Tini lives.
Yes, I look at you, Nigel.
You eat our bridge.
Cecil. Hello.
The boys and I do it, but I have a concern
...
Big lizard can we trust?
He ​​is cold blooded and so.
That's not good for the circulation.
- Stop whining.
I am too far to reverse.
Good enough, it was just a suggestion.
Just a
overwhelming feeling of danger,
that's all. Forget it.
We should call the Hurricanes.
- After this, I'm there.
I'll stay here as a backup,
because my knees are locked.
Who is that?
Stop playing games.
My Friend?
Ezee, are you okay?
Come on, Ezee.
You must stay with us, buddy.
Tell my mother I love her.
- We gotta get him out of here.
What the hell does he eat?
- What he does not eat?
I get help. Stay here.
Tini?
Fly at the first chance you get away.
Do not worry about me.
What is this chatter?
So we do not...
Where I come from.
Where you come from.
We'll find a way to escape.
We all do.
Let the beast angry.
Less talk, more weaving.
Do you want your friend to see a sign?
You and you, I have a job for you.
Come with me.
If you do not care, I work for Cecil...
And
I would like to hear what Cecil has to say.
I think it's good.
- There you have it. We go.
If Budzo on that island is
nothing can stop him.
We'll find a way. Kai and the rest of the
Hurricanes are looking for us.
My son is a Hurricane?
You'll never be a Hurricane.
- Listen to what we have discovered.
The weefvogels ..
Last night You have so many rules broken...
I have no form
long enough.
They make something...
Since you have no notion of what a team is
...
Can not be part of our team.
This is a crazy idea.
With certainty insane.
Maribu's. An invasion of Maribu's.
Hurricanes.
The next time someone 'stoop' says
may be a warning.
This intensive care is intense.
- I see someone feel better.
Another cramp. Hi friend.
That's fine. What a pain.
I think he now
frequently injured will be.
Sorry about the Hurricanes,
I know how much it meant to you.
I guess I'm just so used to fly
,
I have hurt the team.
We're in the same boat.
I'm in trouble.
Yes, but I'm from the Hurricanes kicked.
You do not know how that feels.
You're right. How would I know.
Sorry I got you last night delayed.
No one asked you to come.
- Anytime.
I can not believe how sensitive everyone.
- Maybe "everyone" is not the problem.
My friend do not leave me,
I'm feverish.
Excuse me, which one of you
has ordered a massage?
How many jobs have you got?
- I do not like being in a pigeonholed.
There you are. Come, Kai.
- Gogo Sorry, I'm leaving.
You can not go now, Tini needs you.
Zambezia needs you.
Zambezia and I can not get along, Gogo.
My father was right,
I do not belong here.
I do not have time for this nonsense.
Let me go crazy stork.
Do not lose them, Hurricanes.
- Make sure they do not lose.
It's a trap.
- Too late to warn.
Beautiful movement, old friend.
- Yes, a good show.
Gogo, let me go.
I should never have come here.
My father would...
Sekhuru, no more secrets.
Tell the child the story.
Or do you want history to repeat itself?
Yes, maybe it's time.
- Time for what?
That you come to know the truth.
Here you born.
Wait, am I in Zambezia born?
Welcome home, Kai. Come.
What is this?
Daddy?
- And?
My mother.
Amai.
- Do they live here?
They have together founded the Hurricanes.
To Zambezia monitor...
And protection of all birds in the river valley.
What happened to her?
Killer, she was my wife.
You're not still mad about that one little...
Thing that happened that one time.
It's just what I do.
You could say that it is my nature.
When nature calls, I answer.
Move, weefvogels.
We go from this valley...
A great omelet.
Monster.
- Thank you. I do what I can.
We got a nest against,
by a iguana...
Budzo named, was attacked.
Your mother fought bravely.
I lost a wing,
but she gave her life.
We can save the day an egg.
And that was me. If she had not been there,
I would not be here.
Zoe?
Now I understand your interest in Kai.
That was only a part of.
I recognize a good talent when I see it.
Why has my father told me this?
And why are you telling me this now?
Your father was blinded by grief.
He made me promise,
the past forever buried.
So he took me to Kathungu.
Away from it all.
Tendai was the value of
Zambezia not see
just what it had cost.
If you help them...
- Happen good things.
That's right, Gogo.
- Is the history lesson is over?
I've seen Budzo.
- What, Budzo?
Where?
- Last night in the woods.
The lizard was missing a claw.
- I had Maribu's talking about.
They work together with fixed Budzo.
- I do not know what they're up to...
But if Maribu's Budzo help
we are in great danger.
That brute can Tini better
with no claw touching.
We must return to the forest.
The Maribu can be flown anywhere
.
But Budzo must have left a trail
...
And that can lead us to the weefvogels.
No, it's too dangerous.
Do not know what to expect.
We have to wait for the Hurricanes.
By that time it may be too late.
- They should be back by now.
We should go, dad.
I knew it was risky,
but what choice do we have?
It is as you say,
Zambezia comes in first place.
You always want to be up there, right?
I am ready, Father.
I will find them.
Go.
- If you think I'm crazy...
You have not seen anything yet.
Do not make a sound.
Are you serious? What was that?
- What? I have old bones.
Look.
Lizard Print with claw less.
Soon he misses more claws.
- Okay, do a little softer.
Do not worry little Tini,
mom comes to your rescue.
Small  Tini.
- Maybe I should first take a look.
Good idea.
It is simply up for grabs.
I am already celebrating.
Where do you think it comes from?
Without us it would be but an empty
tree.
She has a point.
- Of course she has a point.
Tini? What is going on?
- It's Budzo.
He forced us to make a bridge
so he can come Zambezia.
They have a while ago.
- We need them to be.
And your father?
- What's wrong with him?
He's here.
I would even take a bath
'n Zambeziaan...
Be. There, I said it.
Of course we can not trust him
I trust myself barely.
Daddy.
Did you hear that?
I can hear sounds and that was a sound.
Go take a look.
- Why do I always look?
Look for yourself.
- Kai's.
Okay. You watch, I'll see.
- That's reasonable.
Kai, what are you doing here?
- What are you doing here?
I went after you.
- It's my fault you're in that cage.
I did not have to depart.
- Kai No, you were right to depart.
Sekhuru told me what happened to Mom.
We broke formation to chase an iguana to go.
Sekhuru order to save.
We were separated.
I left behind to Amai
Budzo to fight against.
Kai, I have robbed you of your mother.
I could not bear the thought.
No, Daddy. Budzo me
my mother robbed.
You Sekhuru and Zoe saved.
Zoe  If you encounter you will see it.
You're a hero to everyone. For me.
From my point is you are the hero.
Let's get outta here.
Did you hear that?
- Well, you heard it.
Tini. Where is my Tini.
Gogo.
- Tini.
Tendai. What's he doing here?
Gogo, we try...
That also works.
We go, you have
there a problem with that?
The exit is on the left.
Do not be a stranger.
Worms.
Budzo, old comrade,
a beautiful day for a coup.
Consider it a hostile takeover.
No, he is al
What is this? You betrayed us.
Maribu You are just as naive as the
Zambezianen.
No.
Sekhuru, come quickly.
Iguanas in Zambezia.
No, impossible.
Gogo, they may not reach the egg.
See what you've done.
They will destroy Zambezia and you in it.
Treacherous reptile, that was not part of the plan
. He would be alone.
No, Maribu are also birds.
- No birds like us.
Not after what they have done.
Zambezia is more than a
city. It's an idea.
The idea that we are all equally important.
Even Maribu's.
- Well said.
If they are willing to help,
they deserve to live here.
We've never trusted.
Why should we start now.
Because we no
Zambezianen can call to do that.
We do with you.
Do we do with them?
Yes, we do.
Grab your eggs now.
- We must work together.
But where are the Hurricanes?
- We are a defenseless target without them.
The Hurricanes are coming.
In the meantime, we stand.
And we will do.
- Tendai?
For Zambezia counting on.
You came back.
Is there something happened in my absence?
I hope you have some fight in you.
- We have more than that.
We have Maribu's on our side.
We're doomed.
I expected that they would be better to take.
Maribu's we have the bridge hung
and we can detach it again.
Sister. Is there anyone? Hello?
Where is everybody?
Is there a party where no one has told me anything about
?
Time to call it a turn
and fly away.
Where you going?
You know what?
When I came here
thought I could do everything myself.
And then I saw what Zambezia means.
I always say, it is easier together.
- That's right.
That makes this city special.
That makes it worth defending.
The Maribu are now down
because they finally understood.
It's true. They fight for the home team.
- Situation Change.
If we all work together and do our part...
We can win. Do you do that?
Budzo sits in the nest area.
He will address our eggs.
- Find your eggs.
Is this not exactly what I want...
They lay their eggs in one basket.
Budzo, this ends today.
- No bird can me.
Well, we'll see.
Daddy.
Well done, son. Show him
get no hold.
This is for my brother, my dear cousin
Cousin, he called me cousin.
Well, hold that rope
fixed. Come spanking...
Get it in a decent way.
Target in sight. Stay on course.
Bombs away.
Two wanted to go.
No!
Yes, yes.
Kai, follow me.
'Cousin', stands in the ring.
I tell you what 'hot wings' taste.
Okay, say we all have something we
kidding.
Your little experiment is over.
This community is a deviation from nature.
Let him go.
Daddy.
- Stop them.
Zoe, come back soon.
Put ​​your foot down somewhere else.
This is not my foot.
- It's the rescue.
Is someone there?
Team, execute exercise 26 on my character.
Where are you?
- Three, two, one...
Help.
Let's hear it.
Higher. Desperate.
Where is the rescue?
- That's for you.
But you're not even authorized.
Oh, I'm gonna fall again.
Budzo have our eggs. It's over.
- Holy crackers...
We live in a cuckoo clock.
- Good Lord.
Do we wait until they do something?
- Think you can handle Budzo?
Do you love us?
Exactly what Kai said,
together we can do anything.
You are an inspiration to other birds.
I do not know how you do it.
This is a very heavy responsibility.
Is this what the mighty
Zambezia has become?
Let's see what you got.
I must say, I'm
not very impressed.
If you are my friend bothers me
val tricky.
I shoot a macadamia in your eye.
Take it.
Orange is a bit too much.
- Do you?
I would have chosen yellowish green.
- Really?
Why can they weefvogels
so great good weave?
Hurricanes, straight.
Target for us.
Three, two, one...
Release.
Maribu's on our side?
What the hell?
Father.
In the attack.
Drafting.
Save your wings, men.
I've had enough of the lizard.
- Perform exercise 46.
On my mark. Three, two, one.
Kai.
- Zoe.
No.
Help.
Pull on, Kai, pull on.
- I'm not leaving you.
My friend.
I give him a blow to the heart attack
he has me worried.
Just like old times, huh?
I hear at the club.
- He's my cousin.
Yes, he is. A very strong bloodline.
- I love watching you.
Your mother would be proud.
I am also proud.
- Thanks Dad.
Daddy, this is Zoe.
- I was the little egg that has saved you.
It's an honor to meet you.
- The honor is mine.
Today we can honestly say that no bird...
Isolated.
What is he doing.
- I'm hip.
Let the 'funky chicken' call.
This is great.
- No, Daddy amazing.
Quality over Quantity (QoQ) ® eleases
Translation Pink Jay ~ Control: Smokey
Look what happens when I garnered my wing.
Beautiful.
- A secret blue color.
Thanks, I call it blauchtig.
- This is the Ezee way.
Pudding. Finally.
I fought single-handedly with Budzo
and I was nothing less than...
Impressive.
He was impressive.
I look good when I do this, right?
Yes, I do.
A newcomer.
Hello, would you like a snack?
How about two?