Between two points in
connection with a line
Easily connected.
Just like a punch.
When I feel right.
Use a quick way to solve the problem.
This way not everyone agrees.
But this is me.
Aku Zhu Fu Long.
Fu happy, long Bruce Lee
Weight 66.4 kg.
A policeman.
I really do not exist.
Trash, me spank you.
You do not hit me again ...
I'm so innocent brother Lin.
It was innocent, I'm Lin.
Get lost you.
Song Ke Er, it has not?
Want to call you how many
times? / Well come ...
Improvements for so long.
Everything was ready, waiting for you only.
You permainkan whom?
Quick, fast run.
Little fast, the director waited.
Well.
Directed I'm ready.
Go, hurry...
What can? / Rush what?
Wait a minute.
Phone / Ke Er
It is finished? / I is less
shuting one more time.
Have you done it yet? Remember take money
send angpao to mother me.
Hours a go picture, if
not I'm not married
You do not marry me, I'm serious.
You know seriously, please
do not be late and over again.
I prepared a suit in the closet
for you, wear remember.
There she is.
Wah / What?
Goods today, you know what
Already, the first job, see you later bye
Move aside.
Assistant director, instead of like this shuting
This scene until recently discharged nice.
What, can not I'm afraid of heights.
Wait no new stuntman shuting okay?
Jump, the camera has not been started.
One more time.
A Rong, so accidental.
Buy Steamed Bun and milk tea
Like it help you? / Mr. huang hungry
Mau does not help?
There is no need.
Why do not you leave
dressed so handsome.
Today's wedding photos
Hey remember next month to drink wine happy.
Both survived.
Remember to keep safety / Know
People do anything.
Eat pineapple again
easy fat
Today PM
You are about to make contact with the bank
What? Not handsome? I Ganteng.
Handsome / As hotel manager
Why? by Ke Er wedding photos?
More stuff you understand what the trend?
People who are married, brain penetration of water.
Early in the morning.
Hey wait ...
Wow the crowds once.
Tuan.
Sir, sir.
Information center, roads Huang Hou
there are cars parked haphazardly.
Please call a tow truck thanks.
Sir, pematik?
No, at the mini market there.
thanks.
Gila.
Host name?
Huang ling Chen.
Mr. Huang, you born on?
27-3-2000
Your host adult yet time, number KPT
You want to do?
I Hongkong administration police
Huang 7.u Rau, number 71 337
You are now in violation of parking
haphazardly, in a fine of 320 dollars
You can pay to use Internet
banking or the other does not matter.
SIM?
Believe ye not interfere with
police work?
I hope you die in work
Hello my wife, I was in the bank queue
Still not pull money?
I went down.
I kejarmu, am I wrong?
No, I'm too slow.
You clean up yet?
Soon / I was wrong right?
It is my fault.
Distinguished guest.
Wah yah flu?
Your signature flu insurance is definitely ...
It's okay / No signal.
It is okay.
Manager!
All squat.
All items are priced out.
Money in a safe deposit issued.
There is no spare key
Permainkan dare I?
Key?
Remove and want to be like him?
I did not give it to you
Son, uncle borrowed briefly
Borrow me okay?
You why pull
the car? / Borrow me okay?
Do not grab toys.
Finish him.
Actually fine
What is not wrong / Want to make me take lives.
Manager damn hotel.
Exit / Alarm let's go.
Fast.
Move aside.
Sir, wait a minute.
Do not move, police rancid.
Hey, the police do not move.
This car?
Does not matter.
Street / Do not matter I'm
the boss, let me go.
Why hit me?
Banting stir until he fell.
Zhu Fu Long / Ya
Immediately remove support
Must be at least the wound and
the victim, do not affect the public
Shoot him dead.
You fucking manager.
What I'm going to give up?
Not anything right, Mr. Huang?
Along, a little hard, execute them.
Serang together.
A long, opportunity comes,
out stance mainstay.
Stop, pull over
Who told so wicked
Love you a last chance
time, if you give up.
I told the judge consider
reducing the punishment if no
You also road dead / You who make me.
Police rancid die.
You forced me out stance mainstay
You now no chance.
Bananas post 24 hours to accompany you.
There I report on the spot.
See her handsome groom
Hongkong dukungmu entire audience.
Lao boss how?
What do you say?
Many people see, would
release little long.
Well.
Come, ye love hammer.
What news viewers
What really want to see things now?
See, the bride is happy
I see also the groom,
was happy to see again
This is clearly a great villain.
You're both fighting
View live events / ye
into my camera.
Move aside bald, on the say yourself
Know what?
Good, man.
It's criminal.
You said how many words the newlyweds
Die
Hit the gas.
Xiang jiao
Jiao Xiang exhausted already.
Hold.
It's okay / Thanks.
Now the situation is very severe.
Anytime influence
us / What, to the police headquarters
Wah so fast.
Why? LMil199ir-
Move aside.
Step aside / sir you did nothing?
Are you ok? Why did not
anyone tell you?
You worry about me / Zhu Fu Long.
Oh / Wait a minute.
I am today.
Of Shen Zhen returned to Hong Kong
want a wedding photo with you.
You?
You fulfilled the promise, and
play live.
What I saw A Chen is no danger, I
Silent does not help, he's my friend,
I also police / police what?
The entire Hongkong only you police?
Another policeman died yah?
I ikutimu ten years, you said
to me once will be the main character
Finally, I laugh at all of Hong Kong.
I'm still embarrassed.
Think of gossip alone / your head.
Even you never promoted
You can live by me?
If you can live by me, I
do not need to go to work
I told you not to work.
I how can not hidupimu / I do
not work, who is living for me?
Alas I better not say.
It's okay, just say so / not.
I told you to say, say.
In fact...
You become an actress what?
That is not a serious worker.
Looking at the TV to be an actress
In addition to the at people,
still at people.
For what hard?
You from the beginning to the end face so
What do you say?
Do not force continues.
One look.
one look
I love you 10 look.
That...
You hit me.
Asshole Zhu Fu Long / Looking at
me / You bilangi me well.
I still can not tell you.
Well today I obviously count on you.
Mother's birthday I was 60 years old,
you go jump into the sea.
I go for help people / Help who?
You wear pants what
That's what I love
Embarrassed, you think you're Superman, the world
is not there you will not play?
You have people who
disturb the world go round
Say what?
You care more about the criminals
it than I
I tanyamu, our unfamiliarity when?
Answer me fast / 8-7-2006 / I
like what color?
White / Name of dog
anyone? / Sunny, Dolly, Bobby
I mother father when unfamiliarity?
7-10-1957 I Why I do not know, you know?
This does not count / I like actor
Brad Pitt, Alpacino / False.
You said last week like
alpachino the week unchanged.
This week I did not like what
should not be? / You permainkan I
I permainkanmu, instead I want hajarmu.
The entire Hong Kong is 30 thousand police
Why do you want to hit the car to superiors
He also knows his calculations
He clearly told you,
you meddlesome.
I have a business, you say lah.
Three brothers Tony, you
there is no reason to forget about.
That year I was in Nan Sheng
Wei, one against three.
Destroy their syndicate
At least I was right services.
Because of you burn half Nam Sang Wai
That group does not stop demanding
Say you destroy the
environment, roasted bird
Lalu gang Bao Lou
I was in a back alley alone
Well then, Wushu champion
throughout the country Jin Mao zi
I almost died
You know the one.
Still want to deny.
It's not me / It's you.
I just wear a white shirt / No
can every time so.
I solved the case and help people
I got you promoted.
Mine is yours,
do not have to count
Now even the wife away.
This is why the actual world?
Have you not chase women, arrogant
The actress, very professional.
Give the whole community
Happy, high level work okay?
still women
Never mind.
I was in this division for how long?
Seven months?
Tonight at seven
In Fulinmen I celebrate promotion.
Do not be late yeah.
Sincerely.
All do not worry about me.
Remember three things.
Keep the promise, keep the appearance,
the spirit of sport
A Long.
The important thing is people are not okay
All carefully little security guard
Relax, we'll take care of your case.
Take care of your body.
Still no news, next month
do not have to collect money
Timely future home from work
Has been troublesome kak
Pak Zhu, repotkanmu.
Each time a cycling holiday, massage is also okay
I got news Nan Ya
Zi there noisier again.
I quickly set out.
I am worried.
Friends will be a problem.
A Long you think.
Each time a hero to help the world
Destroy the world first and can help people
For what [you say
what I do not understand
You once on the move,
friends Segaran.
I subtract no mistake,
all ready for the meal
So people, do not
disturb the world go round.
You can see here, the tree is very beautiful.
Slowly paddling, enjoy
a moment what is bad?
No need each time to break the wind, the race
So people who are important follow large current
Minta comfortable, comfortable.
I can not anymore.
I want to throw up...
Minta comfortable, comfortable.
carelessly
Who are planting trees?
There is no development, anyone
who fix the road?
I want to hang on ...
Come on ...
Hey this way who is correct?
Shortly failed, not embarrassing.
Due to intense and vigorous, although
there is frustration also boast
It was not me who told you.
This buddy.
Gold dragon punch
tail of the dragon
Er to you this year on the back of
golden broom, how?
Acting is there a change
About the film, you know what
Ke Er, spirit.
Men millennial there looking for you lately?
Actually ... / You were looking for him?
Matters of love, I do not like ngobrolkan.
You said work okay?
Actually I wanted to go to
Japan / Ping-Ping there ..
Cepat, Zhu Fu Long.
I want to have lunch / Good
It has been found
[Six Months Later]
What is this? / Yes
Good, all right.
Security guard / I go out to eat.
Happy birthday to me.
Happy birthday to Zhu Fu Long.
So people who are critical of what?
The important thing is, people do not anything
Boss, has been bothered
Boss, has been troublesome.
Bos has bothered
At die you bastard.
Next week the transfer of
a business agreement Tsukiji
You better bunches handle
Grand Master
Takasi, you have arrived
Be quiet, come here.
Watch TV, learn mandarin.
Call him come
ini San Ben Yong Er.
The banana waste it,
or eat wsang?
Joking / The waste bananas
It's the Japanese in the case
robbed the bank one of the victims
Directed JAV
Brain blood, her body Press
But it's okay, just a bit
of memory loss alone
Hey there.
Look.
Japanese police confirmed
He is no relation Tokyo
Return him to Japan
This I want to tell you do.
Data, ticket here, leaving the day after tomorrow.
The day after tomorrow so hurry?
You fool, better hurry.
You can clean up.
Report later move
you / It's not?
Naturally I I andzflkanmu.
Opportunities come / I know.
I'm with you well, you know.
You run so fast for what?
Hey you know why?
There is nothing / You rush
for what? / It's okay
Achen.
Pak Huang we continue to look for you.
Check upmu still not paid
do not worry, she helped pay
A Long this case you care.
Do not confuse well.
Hey I'm on the move I
count on well, thank you.
Tuan here pay.
Be it city suste r / Total 58000
Among these hemorrhoids cut free
Er this to me.
Zhu Fu Long.
You why fat much?
H yes I'm fat?
Looking much fat / fat
little, chubby many yah?
I could barely kenalimu.
I was transferred to the office
The evidence room, you know.
Sitting there, eating a lot.
So here goes.
I went on a diet.
Go where? I Went to
Iepang work, are you? l I
Then you remember carefully well.
Do not desperately
The important thing / person is okay.
Oh yes, these days ...
Congratulations, it's your drama.
Lots to like me too see
thanks.
Everything, the ship will fly.
Please all passengers
wear seat belts.
I sit down, dah.
Ke Er.
There was a time eating together.
Nona Ke Er.
The plane will take off.
This is my friend, Long.
This client / Tuan Long, happy ketemumu.
Oke good bye.
Dah.
What's up, here Edward
San responsible
I translator Maggie.
Mr. Long, Thanks.
Sorry.
You farted?
Not me.
Not me, I do not eat it hot.
It smells, it's dirt people.
I did not go to the loo / No
problem, I take leave of him.
Okay
Zhu pack you want to drink what I traktirmu.
Well.
You have? / I'm not okay, I'm okay.
Okay, thanks.
What you pack first came to Japan?
No
What used to be with a girlfriend? / Yes
But already separated.
Already last.
Maaf./Tidak anything.
I do not want to defecate
I know, I farted fart.
Damn.
You have time to die.
Distress.
Do not come close.
My neck.
Actually, so translators
work only part timeku
Actually, my dream.
Dancer
But the fox mind.
Now.
I want to see the helicopter.
Okay / Oh Yes
strike
He escaped, sir Long.
My neck.
Are you ok?
Unfortunately.
From Hongkong unlucky to Tokyo
Hey ... stop.
Please stop the car in front / Edward San
Wait..
The suspect in the back wearing the pants.
Damn!
That's my car.
Hello sir i Maggie Huang.
The translator of the Japanese police.
I was the Chinese.
I was at the university of Tokyo school.
Not a Beijing university, but Tokyo
22 years / hey.
Sorry / Where sauna? I also liked the sauna
Hello sir Huang / What? / Very well.
All current.
All current / Very good.
Not a problem, lotions, and diet I pay
Hey, but no matter.
That...
The suspect fled / Jittery?
Damn it / No, you heard
me do not worry.
Why let him get away?
You want so celakai why me?
Why? / Japanese police have the ability
They promise to me.
In 2hours certainly can
recapture the suspect.
It will be your call
What they would find
the suspect, if not
this is not for
you / It does not matter.
People either can reward bad / There is
news again call you okay
Ouch pain, sir.
troublesome
Sitting / What you find?
Big.
Let's sit down.
Did you find her?
He hilanglAPa?
What do you mean?
See you tomorrow
No, I can not go back
to Hong Kong / Japan okay first.
I do not understand your English
I'm going to lose jobs
I do not understand, translators ...
Maggie, a translator here ...
Not met, then what?
Tuan Edward
Halo / Why did you lie to me? they
say can not find back.
You know why? / I tell him.
Zhu Fu Long, I
peringatimu / You listen to me.
You lie to me / I told you
Well I assure you.
If you do not find him I
did not return to Hong Kong.
Let him bantumu, no matter what he says.
Xiao namanya In / Ya puck.
What is not wrong?
Mr. Edward is not a bag of me.
MenggHI199 "
Zhu Fu Long / Kamu siapa?
Xiao Sa
Halo
Finally found you.
Good, now I bring him here.
Both later meeting.
Kentutku sometimes pointless.
Xiao Sa
Over there?
iron site
Spirit.
Not hot.
All is not hot, it was feigned.
Anyway can earn
money, all too pleased.
I stayed at the top, to the top of sat.
Well you can, can not like this business.
How could you come to Japan?
Just tell you later.
I'm coming already 10 years.
Se Huang Chen martial sister to me.
Back in Hongkong I become a cop.
They call me a cruel god Hand
Your big name.
All men know.
Se Huang Chen told halmu
No need she said,
the headlines all I got.
Good environment.
Love better meet
You help pay the 200 thousand that
200 thousand what?
He said you would help me pay.
He used to bring women came to play
in Japan I were out of money.
Seriously.
He told me to ask you to borrow money.
My suitcase is lost, you know.
Shit, we both her permainkan
You go up and down stairs is not to
Money still have to pay.
Instead, want to pee
a little, not take it anymore.
You why not say
from the beginning, at the corner / Good.
Welcome.
Forest
One sake] Good
Closed today
I came looking for the lady boss.
People who are not related, depart.
Welcome.
Quick take alcohol, fast.
I know you chase debts.
Please love me a few more days.
Lose the ball would have to pay the money.
Five days.
Four days.
Three days
immediately pay
Please accept first flower / You
dare permainkan me?
You do not want the business?
You talk regulations yah?
You screw up my business, I
how to earn money
Can not earn how
to pay balikmu?
Quick pay the money / Stupid
Or all my life no everything.
Destroy place.
Spirit.
I treat all eat peanuts
Tasty.
Sorry
Who are you? What do you want?
Damn it, you can not beat him
I can hit, you are not
allowed / Talk fine
I hope you die.
What do you say?
Sorry.
You can not even take care of children.
I give you money, do not hit him.
This much only, please you receive.
Pay the money is also not in order.
Do not hit !!
All aside.
remove KTP
What are you doing?
Distress.
Round diet.
Stand aside ...
Zhu fu Long, naik.
You do not have anything right?
Not for nothing / The police came,
when once downloaded it.
Xiao Hu / Police this.
Completed new fighting comes, you see.
You have to bother.
We go / Right.
Enough.
Director, finally ketemumu.
I did not expect to sit one plane.
I particularly hockey, do not know you how.
Things you shuting
Do not
Very nice, create more there feeling again.
More out feeling more action.
Do not! I will not let my son.
It seems there are people.
You know this one gram how much?
Hey you for what? Why?
Tunas!"-
In addition to recording, you still
no evidence what else?
Do not know...
We play the game okay.
Like baseball?
Says, quickly said.
Dodge what?
Tunas!"-
I remember
Merely talking.
Stop.
Do not
I told you also at
I / Talkative.
I just now saw the police
with the mob together.
This world why?
Whatever there is, here area
there are some rogues
They had one henchman / Do not care?
Every day we open the door to do business,
in addition to patient no way
Business.
Now the repair money, enough
to pay three times the debt.
Intervened.
Because gemukmu friends.
What are you looking at?
Do not think help me, you are great.
Like so please people so superman course
Disrupt the world go round
Xiao Hu
Hu Xiao you close to
him for what? / Does nothing
Long uncle I want to
learn kung fu / No need.
I see great kungfumu.
He's great / pm
You have to stay on at
Why did not reply, you'll have a jolly
Mrs. boss / Silent
Go, go ...
Xiao Hu kembali.
Bibi ... this sister Xiao Sa give you.
Xiao Hu was his nephew.
Xiao Hu collision mother's father died
He lived in Japan keep Xiao Hu
Do not want to go home with me to Hong Kong.
Still says I can not
give the warmth of family
separation only
Hypocrite woman
Then I continued to wait,
wait up to 10 years
Why always hold
cigarettes not turn on?
He says I look
so very handsome
He was afraid I would die much suction.
Then I did not turn it on
You also QHHWRQ-
The man of the century
You see what a banana?
Post bananas this case
how can trust
Nonamu it, he played drama
I often watch.
Membership play
See and know
But pretty well.
People are so beautiful,
there is no reason sukamu.
Heil Why? I Basic
You wait.
The love you see in a moment.
It's me, six pax
At that time I was in Bao Lo Lunch
You may not
have ever heard of it? / Great.
Zhu Pak Japanese police have
found San Ben Yong Er.
Tuan Long.
Morning
This is what you want
The body in Dong Jin Wan
You do not feel weird?
His body was no cocaine
The cause of death of toxins and weak suction.
This is an inheritance
He create evil.
Fleeing to Hong Kong, in the chase back.
He committed suicide
She said she committed suicide.
Just like that?
Japanese people talk very captious
Well
One person was going to kill himself
why not suicide
Chinese people any fixed direction
Last autumn leaves exhausted
Return to home
She did not explode
Examining the corpse takes time.
Yesterday there was here dead ice
The body will be changed
really cool
Older brother beat him in severe
Surely there kedendam.
No need to bother again okay
Back to Hong Kong
Okay.
thanks.
Dah.
Edward San
Topimu
Change again / do not touch.
Japanese police had found him, you
care so he was dead or alive.
Back to Hong Kong, but
you have to pay money first.
Do not keep the money.
[Why is there so people
can not easily give up,
you know the rest of Tokyo there are
how many San Ren Yong
This is how many times, how many numbers
This guy right?
If not take a look-see and go
I am hungry.
Can certainly find a clue.
You can do it.
I do not believe any none
It has been found is not?
I found a banana
oh
To.
I told you.
So people do not easily give up.
Quick help from him.
I can not, dogs
Go dog.
I told you, I'd love to face.
Hajar saja.
You why, at me not at dog
Ouch my butt.
Nurut dog.
Do not move...
Do not move.
There is nothing right Xiao Sa? / It's okay
but my bum
You become a cop how many years?
Decadal / Wah ten-
yearly turn out this way.
Why?
People ten years at least so boss
Masingrmasing the pursuit
of different, now very well.
Kak Long, fully restored, is / Smart.
This phone never take in water.
Open the file.
But there is still one video
can not open
So they took care of for a while.
This is not a Cu
I know, I take it you go
All the love of applause
Welcome the host Okinawa
Ke Is
It was not the girls? / Yes
Wow so beautiful.
We come to work, little professional.
Street
Today there is Miss Song Ke Er participate
Invite.
The rapid movement slightly, you create what
Quickly bring the fish up to the car.
To.
This is how the tail?
Still do not go looking for
Makin eat why high
This is what fish
Fish there
Very delicious.
Bastard, stop.
Stop.
Xiao Sa's okay, right?
What people hit by?
Chase
come on
Xiao Sa do not go
Ready-Shit '
Hey is not it all right, realize.
Want to fight well
You create what / Grandpa
We'll deal / Zhu Fu Long.
come on
Ayo / Zhu Fu Long
Zhu Fu Long are you doing
anything, here for what?
Everything sorry / This is the
interrupt our work.
Disturb us / To er
I still want to work, you have made what
They are hoodlums Japan
They all mafia, hey there are no police?
Somebody help me / hey
What is your responsibility for this?
He almost killed the grandfather I
You nonsense
I will tell the police / I'm a cop Hongkong
You are the bad guy, I'm a good guy okay.
I do not care what you
say / Someone call the police
Ke Is
I know who you are
Away from my town.
You do not feel like Takeshi
in Hongkong I've borgolmu.
Motions
Wait a minute.
Maaf In Ke Is
You listen to me / You hear me okay.
He's my boss.
I am working.
She Mafia] I know
I just come to work, I have my basic.
This is the first time I got out of work
What no one looking for
me, you just glad?
I do not want you going on something.
You heard me last
time / What is the last time
The last time you hear me okay?
Every time I hear you, ikutimu.
I do not need
I need one honor
Ouch / You go, I beg / OK
We're friends, I just want to say to you.
I do not want you to follow these evil people.
Together okay? you yourself think.
Xiao Sa ayo
He is very rindumu.
You do / Sir Edward San
Yakuza
How are you, sir
Mr.
Ride your car.
One minion / I understand
I also understand
This guy is really frustrating.
Dizzying.
Create the overtime.
Fast road / I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Sorry all
It is okay.
It is okay
This is the dizzying.
Hlei
Edward told me they do not demand of you.
Drugs Japanese police know.
But they had no proof.
You believe me? / Not a problem.
This Japanese I'm sorry.
Thank you / Do not crap.
I'm a cop 113.4 kg
What would disrupt the world go round?
I continue to think correctly.
Apparently one.
Actually I'm superman or strange animal?
Future home on time
Like so please people, so
superman only / Why do you celakai I
Want to accompany you watch the evidence room?
Back to Hong Kong.
I ikutimu 10th annual
I just want to pass a quiet day with you.
You can give me?
There is a lot in life do
not need theatrics right?
You from the beginning to the end of the face
Do not force continues.
He mafia / What no one find I
play the play you just happy?
You said how many times to me
let me be the protagonist
I want to tell you a word.
Looking down the first car.
Hey do not go, say clearly first.
Not so easy to understand?
I want to sell Feng Hua Ju, then
bring Xiao Hu returned to Hong Kong
You said you were separated?
We have long separated okay?
I came to Japan 10 years waiting for you
You love me what the word is inappropriate severance
You are now a powerful
return to the world of martial
How many days ago destroyed my shop,
now destroyed fish market
You want to pretend stern look
Good does not sell
Wear panties on the head so superman
Hey you do not contemptible job I used to
I truth, not a lie / Good
I did not say anymore,
anyway after I sell
I will return the money to you,
we are not mutual debt later
You think only my money debt
alone, you much debt
You want this yah
Well I obviously count for you
Both count only please.
Each day tell yourself
, great head.
It was the golden fleece
Just like that, if not I lihatmu
What could be the fragrance / you do not think you are.
So many people play mahjong you.
Japan's roads.
I do every time for money they had come.
They hate you
Do not be distressed again.
No you consider my feelings?
You got the feeling of what? / Never mind.
Do not do that again okay
Why?
Look at me the experience.
Although I had a lot of mouth,
I would have to talk
This fool
He clearly loves
Although she was ugly and fat
little, say the word honest.
But it is very rare.
You are
I do not think you do not like him.
Otherwise you will not let him
That day he was at the time very anxious reaction
Looks right.
I'm just saying.
It is in this world.
No one can wait for
others 10 years.
I'm telling you right
Remember
The quarrel pleasures of life.
Do not give up / You do not go.
Can not give up.
Well
Changing very rapidly
Hey, why?
I want to fight them
Spirit.
Halo
What do you want
Quit eating noodles
Bersukung / Thank you.
Spirit
Fast ...
Main movie like this?
Look, toast
I want to tell you a word.
Long time no see
Tonight we are not talking
Just drink wine okay? / OK
Okay / Mari.
I want to tell you a word.
Actually that night.
The word that you said I was
thinking / Night which
Finding your sister that night
I know
Hey you do not think much
I know myself
no talent to play the movie
You are crazy
Lately fame yourselves
The world needs you beautiful movie like this
Also nice body
A great actress
You got a lot of fans / Fans where
You buy it for me, I know
Not every time I had a buy
Just kidding.
We're toast.
Cheers, distress misspoke again.
If we love each other mutually.
Why fights
Do not fight.
We have only mutual communication
Or we start again.
We say pisah
So good
Separation, and the inverse number of times,
the problem is you become a cop
I continue to feel no sense of security.
There is no sense of security I
marahimu / I quit this job
I stop / You be quiet again
I open a shop like this okay?
I stopped, earn
money why not?
True, or not?
You say.
I say / promise / Yes
Promise, okay.
OK / not lie to people.
Big
Cheers.
Cheers ...
Cheers
Cheers.
Everything is okay?
It is okay.
No problem?
Everything is okay?
Okay.
Well, everything is okay.
Why can there be a large earthquake
Next time do not come to Tokyo
Why? you injured?
Seriously?
Where?
You just said what predication?
Really.
You lied to me?
You can not be a cop.
You do not become a cop,
you would not be happy.
In this world.
There are a lot of people.
It takes people like you.
But not including me.
Halo / Along what you make
Corpses, Cu Ti bastard
you want me to Tokyo / No, listen to me
I can not hear, immediately return to Hong Kong
You think yourself superman?
You want to stop the world spinning
You fool yah
You got to hear me speak? / Listen to me.
I'm more willing to be fools
Also do not want to forever
regret, and more.
The world spins itself okay
You dare to argue.
You just stupid.
Sister, my money they say
Videos that there is Xiao Sa
You still waiting for?
At Ci problem handed to us.
Leave it to us.
I can not finish.
Please you signature.
Guaranteed / Sudahlah.
damn it
Quick signature
You are outrageous.
Al'!
Quick signature
fast
Morning...
Wah
I came gonna say goodbye
Please
You are here only because
my grandfather like you
But now he is dead.
crook
You assume I can not theatrics
I am an actress
I scold
damn it
In kak kak Xiao Long?
I find him a very long time
Not found / I do not know.
His videos I've clean up
No nothing, I help aunt
Love him / Oh
You know how much money one gram?
Ya
Hey you why
Bos has returned
A Long you where?
We go vode it is
no evidence for the Yakuza crime
Hey my shirt.
From Amgt /
Hey golden hair
Why did you take my phone
I rely on the phone's rich
Each day barbecue
My hands were like this, I get what
You damn.
By mandarin
Spirit
Fang hua phone evidence
they committed a crime
There is no need to sell him our
Feng ju hua quickly go
fast
Evidence at his / Off You
Tul199"
to
P0nsel
Now we come back to me.
Fang-hua quickly go.
I beat
already
Fang Hua / You do not have anything
It is okay
Feng Er
How about you?
Tul199"
You again.
Wah Xiao sa / It's okay
Only a knife wound.
What are you doing?
I think.
Smoke cigarettes, well off dead handsome
Men do not smoke new handsome
You why not say from the beginning?
Dangerous / I.
Want to say / I
Eh
You call an ambulance
The road to
One can not even less,
Come on.
Police
You came very nice / I know.
Outside there are people fighting / It's okay
Dont worry
All normal, back
To.
Stop / Really frustrating.
Who do you think you are?
Do you superman, not
You little monster, monster bag
You monster / No, you monster
Death Yong er with him
there must be a relationship / What?
Really?
You with Dao Cang
basic
You're a mafia.
Are you there evidence?
You go back to Hongkong
This Japanese.
You quickly slow no karma / Karma
you say I used to be
So the thing I want to
I fart in the car.
Yong Er Dao Cang I love.
And guess yourself is Bruce Lee
You see / You said what?
You do not like
Bruce Lee did not wear a hat
I would laporkanmu on supervisormu
You record what
I invite you to be a translator stupid
So I simplify work.
There are a lot of things
I now pecatmu / I quit
Sick
For Jangafl! "
Stop
You
There are bastards
Dangerous quickly come
hit
Come on / You boys rancid
Stop / Yes you continue to run.
It's karma.
Er to you where I'm sorry kecewakanmu.
Aku Shimakura
I want a cell phone.
If you do not bring you here.
You will see your boyfriend
fell from the tower Tokyo
This
Al'!
Ke Is
Ke Is!
Tuan Long
I'm glad you can invite me.
Spirit / I'll have this place for you.
Here's your proof.
You base scum
Hey heat does not
A Long you will not die.
You do not die.
You do not have anything right?
you die I how
At least I'm not going to force you
to watch me play movie
You also do not need to
give the money to the mother I had.
You want to say what say,
You pressed ..
Sister / Sorry.
Sorry yah / boss
Just now I think you're dead.
Fortunately the bullet passes through
I'm very disappointed in you.
What you see
bastard this fat anyways
APifl / What you see
in this fat ugly bastard
I'm fat? / You say she's fat
I love fat men, so / Yes
Yes look at you.
You are like
Tusuk giqi / Ya
Toothpick.
I do not know why
you do this to me.
Japanese Yakuza.
You are from Hong Kong.
Why are you in my life?
Do not move
Ke Er is okay right?
A Long.
Wah
Ke Is
Ya! 37
fast
Everybody hear me, give up immediately
Police had surrounded
We want to catch you.
A special Long I came to Japan for you
Do not worry, colleagues and face / Si
stupid this is new now come,
Maggie, this time the police
Japanese fast reaction.
Pak Zhu uploaded on the Internet
CNN, YouTube, Facebook, we chat,
everyone can see it.
You know the Japanese people they love her
I love my life, too,
slowly driving.
We still want saunaan
A long.
Thanks
come on
A Long.
A Long
Come,
A Long carefully
A Long teirma.
A Long execute this toothpick
A Chen what you did nothing?
SI M you shot?
What?
A Long you still want to fight how long
Come on I can not stand.
Tul199"
Ya
You lost, man.
I toothpicks
It is okay now
Do not talk.
Why do / do not talk
I know I told you to stop talking.
What do you want to say
I am wrong..
Also not every time is always your fault.
Simply, A Long.
P0lisi Japanese came.,
should they
If you wait longer can not go back
to Hongkong quickly go.
Okay
It is okay
Do not be scared.
Hold me alone.
This time I will not let
Will not
The important thing is people are not okay
Wah
We almost died, too tight Ke er
Do not let go
Apparently in the world other than the line
straight, there is another line
Circles, triangles and other shapes
As in life
Not having to use one
way solve the problem.
Because they have to understand the respect and kejagaan
Actually, what's the difference skinny fat
Like water
Water will be like
This word there
Zhu Fu Long 113.4 kilo
say what is important?