Subtitles by explosiveskull
Fear.
Fear is something
that everyone experiences.
Fear is a feeling
that we all know.
For me, a fear
that shaped my life was...
God, that sucks.
"Recount a time
when you faced a fear,
challenge or failure.
How did it define you,
or how did you overcome it?"
Hello?
Tyler? What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
My mom is gonna hear you.
You see this mask?
Got it on sale.
Very scary.
Sorry.
I was in the neighborhood.
- I texted you like 10 times.
- I told you my phone's off.
If I miss this deadline,
I don't get into Columbia.
You'll be here with me
the next four years.
Consider me your safety school.
Close by, good parties...
Oh, really. Do you also offer
a creative-writing program?
Oh, I'm super creative.
Look, I got you a care package.
- Pringles. And a little bit of Red Bull.
- Heh.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You are so busted.
- So, so busted.
- I've got it.
Mom,
this is not what it looks like.
No, I know what it is.
I heard the entire thing.
Do people
not whisper anymore?
"Hey, I brought Pringles
and Red Bull."
"You better be quiet
'cause my mom will hear us."
Tyler, go home.
Okay.
Uh, just to clarify,
do you mean back out the window
or out the front?
Okay, I'll use the window.
Sorry, Sarah,
I'll see you tomorrow.
Ooh! I'm good.
Ah! Still good!
- Go to bed.
- Mom, I can explain.
We'll discuss this
in the morning.
- Sam is gonna love this.
- You go to bed too.
- What'd I do?
- I don't need a wingman.
- Okay. Going to bed.
- Hmph.
Ow.
You need to stop
electrocuting yourself
- and eat your breakfast.
- Mom, this is due tomorrow,
and it's worth 50 percent
of my grade.
How about you eat 50 percent
of your eggs?
Sonny, seriously?
Sorry. I'm getting close.
Coming.
Coming!
Morning, Ms. Quinn.
- Good morning, Sam.
- How you doing?
Kathy! Thank
you for taking Sam.
We'll be back in three days.
We owe you.
You definitely do.
Sonny!
Grab your backpack.
Sarah, let's go!
I've got an errand to run
- on the way to school.
- Coming!
My condolences on your bust
last night.
Good thing I'm here,
in case any other dudes
try to climb
through your window.
Sonny. I'm gonna kill you.
Kill him in the car.
Okay? Go, go, go.
♪ Halloween with pumpkins
And mice ♪
♪ Halloween, it's so nice ♪
♪ Halloween ♪
- Faster, faster.
- ♪ With pumpkins and mice ♪
Hey, Kathy.
Hey, kids. Heh, heh.
Mr. Chu.
Wow, you practically got
a theme park here.
Check this out.
Oh, my... Oh! Whoa!
It's like being in the movies!
I'm gonna have these puppies
up and running in no time.
You know, for the kids.
- Ha-ha-ha. Okay.
- All right. Bye.
He doesn't actually have kids,
does he?
No, he does not.
Ooh!
All right, everybody,
let's make this quick.
You can each pick out a pumpkin
to carve if you want to,
but meet me at
the register in five minutes,
- all right?
- Okay.
Alrighty.
Right here? Really?
Yes, here. Everywhere.
It's called marketing.
Anything you wanna
say to me?
Mom... Mom, I was
working all night. I swear.
I swear,
Tyler just snuck over and...
I've just been so stuck
on this essay...
You're a great writer.
You always have been.
When you have to sum up
your whole life in one essay,
it all just sounds so...
unimpressive.
Honey. I think you're very
impressive and very capable.
You do?
Thank you.
I do.
Which is why I need you
to watch Sonny and Sam
this week
while I'm working doubles.
Mom! No!
My essay is due Friday.
Sonny's bigger than me.
He doesn't need a babysitter.
Ha, ha. Have you seen what he
blows up when he's supervised?
Hon, I know you're focused
on getting out of here.
But if I don't cover
these shifts at work,
I could lose my job.
I need to know
I can count on you.
Okay. Fine.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
Well, you have earned yourself
some corn cushions, little lady.
Really? Mom.
You're looking real nice today.
Thank you. Heh, heh.
Blue is very in this year.
- I see you got the memo.
- I guess we're in the know.
Okay. Hey, you know,
the adult diapers
are 2-for-1
if you wanna grab another.
- I just need one today.
- Okay. All right.
I don't need them.
They're for the nursing home
- where I work.
- Of course.
- I... I don't... Heh, heh.
- Hey, no judgment.
- Um, okay. Heh, heh.
- I use a toilet. Heh, heh.
All right. Well, hopefully,
I'll, uh, see you around soon.
Yeah. Yeah.
Thanks for checking me out.
Ringing up my purchases.
You know.
Yes. Yeah. Well, both.
- Yeah. Heh.
- I'll just get my diapers and go.
Yeah.
Happy Halloween!
Yeah, I can help you.
Hey, wait up!
Oh, dude,
science fair sign-ups.
If I can just get
my Tesla Tower to work,
easily win. It'd be so cool.
What do you mean?
You're already cool.
We are treasure hunters.
People respect us around here.
- Ew.
- Hey, Junk Bros.
Spit wads? What are you, 9?
What'd you say?
Sam, what are you doing?
I got this.
You know,
we were gonna TP Principal
Harrison's house tomorrow night.
But now,
I think I'm just gonna spend
the whole night
chasing you guys around.
Hey. Boys,
move it or you're tardy.
Of course, Ms. Hoover.
I was just extolling
to my good friends Sam and Sonny
my deep love for homework
and all things learning.
Get to class.
Yeah.
What a jerk.
I'd like to check
this book out, please.
And you are...?
Tyler Mitchell.
Okay, Tyler Mitchell.
Oh. Yeah, you have four books
you haven't returned
since sophomore year.
And your account is frozen.
Damn.
It's gonna cost 40 bucks
to unfreeze it.
I just spent it
on tickets for us
to see DJ Bisky
at the Den tonight.
You have to come.
You can't say no.
My way of saying sorry
for getting you busted.
I-I can't.
My mom is making me
watch my stupid brother
all week and his friend...
Come on. Don't wait for college
to start having fun.
Show starts at 8.
Get your brother
a babysitter.
Okay. Sam, what do you think?
Nice. Looks just like you.
Hello.
Yeah. Yeah, you're speaking
to a Junk Brother.
Yes, ma'am. This afternoon?
Let me check with my associate.
- Hang up on her.
- This is our opportunity.
- We're too busy. Stop it.
- We're doing this.
I have my Tesla Tower project,
I have algebra. No way.
- Fine, fine, fine! Whatever.
- Sam.
All right. Fine.
You are in luck.
Yeah, we can squeeze you in.
24 Ashley Lane?
No, no problem. No problem.
Yeah. Fear not, ma'am.
Junk is our middle name.
"Junk is our..."?
Do you even hear yourself?
Get your shoes on.
It's time to get rich!
I already have my shoes on.
I guess this is it.
24 Ashley Lane.
Twenty-four is the number
of people murdered here.
All right, Sonny.
Let's do this.
Hey. I don't like the way
those things are looking at us.
We're treasure hunters, Sonny,
remember. Come on.
Hello?
Some treasure.
This place
is definitely haunted.
Dude, there's more stuff
over here. Come on.
This room's
even worse.
Come on, Sonny,
it's not that bad.
There is nothing
to be afraid of.
Who stuffs a cat?
How much are they paying us
for this?
Can't believe you said
we'd work for free.
Not for free.
The lady said
we could keep any junk
we don't throw away.
Some of that stuff
can have monetary value.
You know what else
has monetary value, Sam?
- Actual money.
- Just start cleaning. Come on.
Found some more stuff
in the attic.
- Okay, what do we got?
- Maybe this is worth something.
It's stuck.
Dude, I think
we just found a treasure chest!
- Go get it.
- Jackpot!
This is amazing.
It's like a whole room in here.
I told you.
We come here, we find treasure.
Help me with this.
I bet this thing
is filled with gold
and diamonds and Bitcoins.
Uh, you know Bitcoins
are cryptocurrency, right?
It's not real coins,
it's virtual coins.
It's really cool. It starts
with a process called mining...
Stop being a nerd
for a second and help.
- Yeah, sorry.
- Thank you. Here.
All right. You ready?
Three, two, and...
What?
It's locked.
Who would lock a book?
Here's a key.
Oh, man.
Well, what's in it?
Nothing.
It's just a beat-up old book.
Doesn't have a title page.
- So much for treasure.
- Well, look.
We still have all this stuff.
This is a good haul.
Just grab the book anyway.
- It's gotta be worth something.
- Yeah.
Sam. Sam, turn around.
Where did that come from?
"My name is Slappy.
What's yours?"
Wait, I think it says something
on the back.
"Karru marri odonna
loma molonu karrano."
He's so creepy.
It's kind of like he's alive.
I don't think
anything's been alive
in this house
since that cat.
I mean, look at this place.
- But I'm alive now!
- Aah!
Oh, Sonny, just give me a kiss.
Just one smooch.
- That's not funny.
- Yes, it is. It's hilarious.
It's a business.
We're running a business.
Take this more seriously.
It's too easy, Sonny.
Come on, man.
Hey, I'm taking him.
Don't know why
you took that thing.
- What do you mean? He's awesome.
- Whatever.
Hey, it's the Junk Sisters!
Oh, great.
Well, at least we know
our marketing's working.
No teacher around
to save you now.
Hey, are you wearing
my old sweater
from my grandma's yard sale?
Leave us alone.
Okay.
Give me back my sweater
and I'll let you go.
Really?
Unless you want
your face punched.
Whatever.
And your box.
Fine. Just take it.
Yo, what we got?
- What's this?
- Let's see. Old radio.
- Is that a ruler?
- That's a dog toy.
A stupid book.
Wow.
Great business
you guys are running.
Heh. Your turn.
No. No,
I'm not giving you my box.
Sam, just give it to him.
I like my face unpunched.
No way.
We worked for this stuff.
- Hey, Tommy!
- Oh!
- Look at that.
- Tommy, give him back!
Want your doll? You dress him up
when you get home?
Tommy, this isn't funny.
Sam...
What the...?
What is going on?
Tommy, pull up your pants!
They're stuck.
Thank you very much.
Sonny, we need to go!
Go! Go! Go! No, don't touch
my underwear! God! Stop!
No! Go get them!
- Go!
- Okay, okay, okay!
Better pedal faster!
Oh, no.
Come on,
don't make it easy for us!
We need to go!
We're gonna get you, man!
They're gaining on us!
Faster!
- What just happened?
- I have no idea.
Get back here, you two!
Ah.
Why does this keep happening?
Sarah!
You won't believe what happened.
You are never
going to believe this.
We were in this crazy,
abandoned, creepy house
and found this fireplace,
which had a cat on it I twisted.
It went to a secret
compartment that opened.
Then there was a treasure chest.
Okay, but long story short,
we found...
this guy!
Th-this guy.
This... guy.
Wow. It's like you're actively
trying not to be cool.
Here. Mom specifically said
you should fold the laundry.
I'll be in my room if you
need me, but do not need me.
Hey, Sarah?
This specifically says you are
supposed to fold the laundry.
Sarah.
♪ I spend all the time
Waiting at night for you ♪
What am I doing?
We already banned jumping.
I banned sucking, yet here you are.
Now, come on.
Hey! Yes!
Yes!
It's 4 to 1.
Why are you celebrating?
Scoring is a reason
for celebration.
Bye, I'm leaving!
- Where you going?
- Out. I'll be back by 10.
If Mom calls,
tell her I'm in the shower.
You were gonna help me
with my science presentation.
There's two dummies
on the couch.
Practice on one of them.
Ouch.
Tyler!
All right, there we go.
Okay. And...
Sergeant, your orders
are to guard this porch.
It was more than
a hundred years ago
when Nikola Tesla
first lit up the sky
over Wardenclyffe, New York.
Tesla wanted to create a world
where anything
could be transmitted
through giant electric towers:
Power, sound,
maybe even brain waves.
It was like
the original Wi-Fi.
But suddenly and mysteriously,
he shut down his lab in 1908.
His tower
never lit up the sky again.
Until...
today!
May I have a volunteer?
You, sir, in the gray suit.
Hold this
and prepare to be amazed.
I present to you all:
Tesla!
Don't give me that look.
I'm trying
to bring back your tower.
Bravo.
I, for one, think it's
an electrifying presentation.
Sam. I'm not
gonna fall for that again.
Ha-ha-ha. Very funny.
It's like a microphone?
You're talking through
your cell phone or something?
Sam.
Sam, it's a stupid prank.
You ever heard
of personal space? Mm!
How are you talking
to me right now?
You brought me to life.
Don't you remember, Sonny?
- Sam?
- What?
What's the problem?
Just come up here. Please.
Dude, I told you,
I don't care about Tesla.
- Right now, Sam.
- Fine!
I've always wanted a brother.
Please don't try
to educate me on Tesla.
Hello, Sam. Thank you for saving
me from that moron today.
Oh, he's battery-operated.
No, no, no.
Sam, Sam, he's alive.
Sorry for what
happened with Tommy.
I guess you could say
he got hosed.
- That was you?
- Yep.
And now that we're family,
we can be brothers!
I think I'd make
a great Junk Brother.
Right. Just a sec. Sidebar.
Are we losing our minds?
I don't think
we can at the same time.
Okay, but just to clarify,
we're talking
to a puppet right now.
Yeah.
Maybe he's alive.
Of course I'm alive!
Heh-heh-heh.
And I can make
all your problems go away.
Didn't your sister tell you
to fold the laundry?
There. Now you have time
to do your homework.
Oh, what's that? You don't want
to do your homework?
That's okay.
I just did it for you.
You know algebra?
A squared
plus B squared equals
of course! Heh, heh.
This is amazing.
It's all correct.
So you can change
all of our grades.
I can only change
the things right in front of me.
But whatever I see,
I can bring to life.
Karru marri odonna loma
molonu karrano.
Round one. Fight!
That is awesome.
I will never question
picking up junk again.
Wait until Mom
and Sarah find out.
Slow your roll there, kid.
Let's just keep this
our little secret for now.
Give me a chance
to win them over first.
Ah, you're terrible at this.
Heh-heh-heh.
I'm literally crushing you
right now.
Can't believe you're losing
to a puppet.
Right. And I'm not
even using my magical powers.
Heh. Hm?
Back so soon?
- Don't ask.
- Are you okay?
- What happened?
Well, turns out the guy I liked
is a total scumbag.
Mom expects me to run
this entire house by myself.
And if I don't figure out
this essay by Friday,
I'm never getting out of this
town. So no, I'm not okay.
Why are you guys
acting so weird?
- Us?
- Nothing.
No reason at all. Mm-hm.
I'm working
on my science project.
- We're just playing video games.
- Just us two.
- Nobody else.
- Mm-hm.
I'm going to bed.
Good night.
Who just said that?
- Me!
- Sam.
Good night.
It's a new thing we're doing.
- Hit the hay.
- Good night, Sarah.
Night-night.
That is not cool, Slappy.
What the hell?
- Ugh. God, they are such tools.
- Boo!
Missed you at the show
last night.
Bet you did. You have fun?
It was okay.
A bunch of us just hanging out.
Totally casual.
Right.
- What's with the dummy?
- Oh, him?
We were just hanging out.
Totally casual.
Fly, little ghost.
Hey, whoever that is, can you
toss me up some more string?
Sure.
Okay.
That's hilarious.
Sarah?
Oh! Hey, hey, hey,
not funny, not funny.
Sarah, stop fooling around.
I'd say you're the one
fooling around.
How are you talking?
I love the theater.
I always bring down the house.
Wait, no! What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Tell me, Tyler.
What does it say
on that top step?
Uh... It's not a step?
Maybe you'll remember that
the next time you
step out of line with my sister.
It was a puppet, man.
It was a puppet.
It had these
supernatural powers.
He could move things
with his mind.
I swear.
She knows! Ask her.
It was in her locker.
Please tell him real quick.
Sarah, tell him!
It's just the meds
kicking in, sir.
Last guy said he saw a dragon.
It wasn't a dragon.
It was a puppet.
Nikola Tesla
constructed this tower
right here in Wardenclyffe,
New York
to beam bolts of electricity
across the world.
And today...
we are going
to beam bolts of electricity
across this classroom.
Someone beam me
out of this classroom.
May I have a volunteer?
You, ma'am,
in the pink sweater.
Hold that and prepare
to be amazed.
Behold:
The power of Tesla.
Mr. Quinn, unplug that now!
That was awesome!
And that was my presentation
on Nikola Tesla.
Any...? Any questions?
Today's picture day!
This is not good.
I'm so busted.
Oh, great,
the fire department's here?
They're definitely gonna
make you repeat a grade.
Please tell me you guys
had nothing to do with this.
Sonny blew up the science wing.
It was so cool.
It was an accident.
What are you doing here?
Tyler Mitchell just got loaded
into an ambulance.
He said the dummy
you guys put in my backpack
attacked him
with supernatural powers.
We didn't put Slappy
in your backpack.
Get in.
You're telling me
that you discovered
a walking, talking dummy
and you didn't tell me?
He seemed like a nice guy
at the start.
- He had great manners.
- He told us to keep it a secret.
A, I'm your sister.
And B, as a general rule,
when an animated doll
tells you to keep secrets,
that's a red flag.
He's not just some doll.
He's got powers.
He can move stuff with his mind.
You guys, this is insane.
I mean,
why would he go after Tyler?
Maybe he heard you complaining
about him last night.
Great.
What else did I complain about?
Mom.
Hey, kids, you wanna see
the mummies come to life?
- Sorry, Mr. Chu!
- Don't have time to talk now!
Your loss!
- Mom!
- Ms. Quinn!
Hey. You didn't tell me you got
a ventriloquist dummy. How fun!
He was sitting at the table
like a little person.
"Hi, kids. My name is Bobo.
And I like listening to Mom."
Heh, heh.
Mom, his name is Slappy,
and I would not do that
if I were you.
Slappy.
That's a ridiculous name.
No, no. His name is Bobo.
- Mom, you don't understand.
- Ms. Quinn, he's alive.
I think these guys
are trying to play
some sort of
a Halloween prank on us,
but I'm not buying it.
Are you? No.
Oh, let me get that.
But nice try. Very creative.
Stay right there.
Don't go anywhere.
Hi, kids. Good day at school?
Oh, my God. He sounds
even creepier than he looks.
Ha-ha-ha. We're gonna be
such a happy family.
You're not our family.
Do it, Sonny. Turn him off.
Hearing you say that
makes me mad.
"Karru marri odonna
loma molonu karrano."
Don't do that.
Do it again.
"Karru marri odonna
loma molonu karrano."
It worked.
And trust me.
You don't want to find out
what happens...
when I get mad.
- Okay.
- Hm?
Well, that was
an interesting phone call.
Anything you wanna tell me?
Yes, we've been trying to.
That dummy is evil.
You blew up the science lab?
Yeah, there was that too.
Do you know
how much damage you've caused?
It wasn't Sonny's fault.
I'm sure it was an accident.
- It wasn't an accident. The dummy did it.
- Yeah.
Do I look like a dummy
to you?
We're telling
the truth!
Here's some truth for you.
Halloween is canceled
for the three of you.
- What?
- Canceled.
- Come on.
- You know...
I expect this kind of
craziness from the boys.
But I felt like
you were gonna help me
keep things under control,
Sarah.
Mom.
I'm disappointed.
- Come on. Mom.
- Mom, please.
Not as disappointed
as I am.
My room.
Now.
We've got a problem.
Yeah. I have never seen
your mom that mad.
I'm talking about
the psycho dummy on our couch.
Did somebody call
a family meeting without me?
No, no. Slappy,
why would you think that?
We were just planning
a surprise party for you.
Well, I've got a surprise
for the three of you.
This is my house now.
And under my roof,
I make the rules.
Sorry, but you just got voted
out of this family.
- Huh? Aah!
- Oh!
What do we do with him now?
Fireplace.
No. No way.
I would have nightmares
the rest of my life.
No. I have a better idea.
Ugh. We've
been walking forever.
It's like this whole place
is made of poison ivy.
Stop complaining.
How much farther is it?
Here.
This should work.
Am I the only one that feels
like we're committing a crime?
It's a dummy. The only crime
we're committing is littering.
- Ready?
- Yeah, yeah.
Okay, watch out.
It's done.
Let's get out of here.
Sonny, come on.
We just killed a puppet.
Trust me, we had to.
And I say we just
forget it ever happened,
because no one
will believe us anyway.
It's over.
He's locked in a suitcase.
There's no way
that dummy's getting out.
Who you calling "dummy,"
dummy?
What do you want from us?
I just want to be
part of the family.
He's gonna break
through the windshield.
Is everyone okay?
Yeah.
Think so.
Where's Slappy?
Guys, I think we just made
things a thousand times worse.
♪ I've been driving
In my car ♪
♪ Trying to find
Some sign of life ♪
♪ One is a guy
That is kind of creepy ♪
♪ It's a little stickling
Said sleepy ♪
Trick or treat!
There you go, Hank.
All right,
come on in. Zoink!
Step right up.
Don't be scared.
Welcome to my haunted house.
Boo!
All right.
Here you go. Happy Halloween.
Hey, what's up, my witches?
Little Frankenstein humor.
Zoink!
Beat it.
Here you go.
Bye-bye!
Hey, my princess.
Hey, my cowboy.
- I'm not a cowboy!
- Yes, you are. Bye-bye!
"A mysterious disturbance
recently took place
"in the town
of Madison, Delaware.
"Neighborhoods were ravaged
and the high school destroyed.
"An FBI spokesman said unusual
weather patterns were to blame,
"but there were rumors
of a cover-up
"for something far stranger.
"Sightings of giant insects,
Abominable Snowmen, and even...
...an evil ventriloquist dummy."
Oh, we're so dead.
"Creatures believed to come
alive from the original
manuscripts of horror author
R.L. Stine."
- The book.
- What book?
In that abandoned house, we
found this old locked-up book.
And when we unlocked it,
that's when Slappy appeared.
Yeah, but Tommy Madigan
took it from us.
Well, how do you know the book
was written by R.L. Stine?
Wait a second.
"From 1979 to 1985,
"legendary horror author
R.L. Stine
lived in Wardenclyffe,
New York."
- Here?
- That's not good.
"Stine started
his writing career
"with a since-unpublished novel
titled Haunted Halloween,
"a tale of a demonic dummy
who sets out
to create a family
of his own by..."
By...? By what?
By bringing Halloween
to life.
I love a good holiday sale.
Hello, old friends.
If those kids don't want me
to be a part of their family,
I'll raise one of my own.
Karru marri
odonna loma molonu karrano.
Karru marri...
Okay.
Yes.
Trick or treat.
Welcome
to the family,
Walter.
Serving families
is what I do. Heh, heh.
Heh, heh. Come along,
then, brother.
Just wait until you see
what I have planned next
for this town.
Guys, this is bad.
This is really,
really bad.
You know what we need to do?
We need to call the police.
And tell them what?
That an evil dummy
is about to bring
Halloween to life?
- Yes!
- Great idea, Sam.
They'll come and arrest us.
- Wait, guys, I found a number.
- For Stine?
No, says here
nobody knows where he is,
but this is for
Richard Shivers.
He's the president of the
R.L. Stine Appreciation Society.
- What are you doing?
- I'm calling.
Good day, you've
reached Dr. Richard Shivers
and the R.L. Stine
Appreciation Society.
If you're trying to
reach Stine, don't bother.
Otherwise,
leave a message.
Hi, Mr. Shivers,
my name is Sarah Quinn.
I live in
Wardenclyffe, New York.
I desperately need to
get in touch with R.L. Stine.
This is gonna sound crazy,
but I think one of his stories
has come to life.
Hi, Mr. Shivers...
Well...
Looks like we're on our own.
Wait,
where are we going?
To find Tommy Madigan
and get that book.
Get that one.
No way he's gonna
be able to get that.
Oh.
- Tommy! Tommy!
- Tommy! Hey.
Tommy! Tommy!
What do these idiots want?
I'll take care
of this.
We need that book.
- It's really important.
- It's super important.
The book with
the lock on it.
Okay, okay.
What book?
The one you stole
from us, Tommy.
Oh, yeah.
I've got it right here.
- Oh, really?
- No, idiot.
Why would I be carrying a book
around with me on Halloween?
Now, go back home
with your babysitter.
I'll be there in a bit
to egg your house.
Listen,
you little punk,
I'm not the babysitter.
I'm Sonny's sister.
You're gonna give us
that book back
or I'll make your life
a living hell.
The only thing you'll use that
toilet paper for is to wipe...
Okay. God, you don't have
to be so mean about it.
Let's get
out of here.
Book's at my house
in my room.
But it's hidden, so good luck
finding it, losers. Heh, heh.
Those are some
awesome costumes.
Is this actually
happening?
Guys, we gotta find
that book!
Evening, Mr. Tesla.
You don't mind if we bring
your tower back to life, do you?
What did he say?
Shut up.
Tesla used this tower
to project electricity,
but I'm going
to use this tower
to project my magic
in ways he never imagined.
It takes a genius
to know a genius.
- Whoa.
- Heh-heh-heh.
Come along,
Walter.
We've got work
to do.
Very well.
Let's go.
This is Tommy's house.
Well, I guess
we just knock?
Knock loud. He
lives with his grandma.
Okay.
Wait! Guys,
there she is.
She's asleep.
I guess we'll just
have to wake her up.
- Hello! Come on.
- Hello!
- Tommy's grandma!
Wow.
Guess she's a deep sleeper.
It's locked.
Find another way in
and go get that book.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna make sure
nothing surprises us. Go!
- Ow!
- Shh.
What?
I can't believe we're
breaking into someone's house right now.
Shh.
Hey, they got gummy bears.
Who cares?
Stop screwing around.
Hands off!
Sam, stop
screwing around. Let's go.
Okay, all right.
Watch this, Walter.
Whoa. Whoa.
Why settle for
a small family, Walter,
when we can project
my power everywhere
and bring all of
Halloween to life?
Yeah.
Karru marri odonna loma
- molonu karrano.
- Whoa.
Karru marri
odonna loma
molonu karrano.
Hyah! Ha-ha-ha!
- Sam, I found it. Yeah.
- You found it?
"R.L. Stine."
How did we miss that?
- That can't be good.
- Yeah. We gotta go.
Let's just go
back out the window.
All right.
- Oh.
- Ah!
Sam!
The hand
has my hand!
Just rip it off!
Throw it!
Sam. Turn around.
They're moving.
Sonny,
they're just gummy bears.
They're so tiny and cute.
What can they do?
Hey there, little guys.
Sam, you just ate
half their family.
I would not do that
if I were you.
Why are they walking
towards us?
Okay. All right.
Maybe
they just want us
to stay and play.
God, where is everyone?
Oh, there's one
on my back, Sam!
Okay, okay!
- Pull harder!
- I'm trying!
- Whoa.
- Ha-ha-ha!
Go for the window, Sam!
I'm coming!
Whoa!
Just! Stop! Giggling!
Sam! I need some help
over here...
Sonny!
Mom, we're under attack!
Sonny, what are you
talking about?
Where's Sarah?
Who's attacking you?
Gummy bears.
What? Honey, you're mumbling.
Put Sarah on the phone.
- Sonny.
- Whee!
What...?
Okay, that's it.
Do not leave the house!
I'm coming home.
Sonny, help!
Sam, I'm coming!
Hurry!
No, no, no!
You'll never take me alive!
That is my new favorite book.
- You okay?
- I think.
Let's get out of here.
What are you guys
doing in there?
Oh, no big deal, really.
Just being mauled
by my favorite
comfort food!
Wait. Just stop.
Stop, stop!
What are you guys
even talking about?
Everything is alive, Sarah.
Even candy.
Well, is that the book?
Let's read it.
There's something you need
to know about this book.
What?
Look out!
Whoa!
That's what.
This is not
a normal book, Sarah.
Who would write this?
♪ They did the monster mash ♪
♪ The monster mash ♪
Oh, what is this?
Okay.
- Huh?
- Oh!
- Hyah!
- Oh, you rehearsed that, did you?
Best costume of the night, sir.
Go!
Look out, look out! Ah!
What's going on?
There! Let's take
the alley. It's empty.
Wait, wait!
We need to read the book
and see how we can end this.
Let me see.
"It was nearly Halloween
in the town of Wardenclyffe..."
Blah, blah, blah. Here!
"His revenge
was to create a family
by bringing Halloween to life,
but that wasn't enough."
That seems like
plenty of revenge to me.
"Because he wanted more than
a family. He wanted a mother.
His plan was to..."
Was to what?
Keep reading.
I-I-I can't.
That was the last page.
It's an unfinished manuscript.
What?
Okay, great.
What do we do now?
Slappy's gonna go after Mom.
That book is the only thing
we have to stop him.
We have to go to
the nursing home and save her.
Mom's not at
the nursing home.
Where is she?
- On her way home to save us.
- What?
She called while we were
attacked by gummy bears.
Why answer
at a time like that?
Maybe because unlike you, Sarah,
I pick up Mom's phone calls.
Really? Guilt trip much?
We need to find your mom
before Slappy does.
Now, come on,
let's go!
Your woodworking skills
are impressive.
Yes.
This will do nicely.
Oh, I used to manage
a hardware store.
- Walter. Focus, please.
- Yes.
Now tell my monsters to get me
Mama and get me that book.
Yeah. Yes.
Run!
Duck!
Look out!
What the...?
That's Mr. Peters!
- Nice doggy.
- It's right behind you!
Ah! Not on my leg!
Help!
That's Mom! That's Mom!
Come on!
You bunch of scallywags!
Kids, watch out!
Behind you!
Okay, now's our chance.
Give me the book.
I'm gonna protect Mom.
You get the ladder
and meet me at that tree.
- Wait till it's safe, then go.
- Okay.
Okay, okay.
Oh, my God! We're all gonna die!
Run for your life! Ah!
Oh, my God.
Oops. Not a monster.
All right, let's go!
Come on!
Halt!
My orders are
to guard this porch!
No way.
You like carving pumpkins,
huh?
Look what you did
to poor Terry.
Hiya! I'm round.
Sergeant Squash,
open fire.
Oh. Ow!
We need to find
another way in!
No. This is my house.
I'm hit! Medic!
What are you doing?
Put me down!
Hiya! Happy Easter.
- No, no!
- Ugh!
Yes! Let's go.
Sarah, I was so worried.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Just hang tight.
I'm gonna get you down.
I promise.
I just need you to trust me.
Don't worry about me. Run. Hide!
Ghost at 11 o'clock!
No, no, no! Get back here!
That's my book! Ah!
We gotta go.
Sarah!
Sarah, let go of that ghost!
Do not let go
of that ghost!
- You okay?
- No, that ghost took the book.
- Mom!
- Oh, kids. Help!
No, no, no!
- Sarah!
- Mom!
It's heading for the Tesla lab.
Slappy brought
the tower to life.
That's why
this is happening.
We have to stop him.
Uh, guys?
Sonny, what do we do?
I don't know.
You're the older one.
No, no, no.
It's me, Mr. Chu!
Mr. Chu?
Shh! Follow me!
To the basement now!
Don't ruin the Mylar.
I'm saving it for next year.
Go, go, go.
Let me get this straight.
We are living a Goosebumps
story right now?
Okay, clearly you're a fan.
This is the greatest thing
I've ever heard!
Hold on. Let me guess, let me
guess, let me guess. Um...
Monster Blood.
No, too on the nose.
Yeah, you're right. Um...
The Scarecrow Walks
at Midnight.
No. Haunted Halloween.
I don't know that one.
How does it end?
That's the problem.
It doesn't.
Mm! Mm!
Hello, Mama.
Remember me?
You put me on your lap.
Put those cute words
in my mouth.
What was it you called me?
"Bobo"? Ha-ha-ha.
Can't talk?
Don't you worry.
From now on, I'll do
the talking for both of us.
I'm gonna make you
so proud, Mama.
Onarrak unolom
amol
annodo irram
urrak.
It's working.
Yes.
My mind is literally
blown right now.
I mean, we get to finish
our Goosebumps story!
This isn't a creative-writing
exercise, Mr. Chu.
Slappy has our mom!
Yeah, and then you get to
save your mom. It's Chapter 22:
"The kids save their mom
from the demonic dummy."
Well, the only thing
I had to save my mom
was that book,
and I lost it. So...
Sarah. This is not
your fault.
If anything, it's my fault.
I'm the one who found the book
and brought Slappy to life.
And I even told Slappy
about Tesla.
Mom trusted me to
take care of you guys,
and I told her
I would save her.
I failed.
I know I always say that
I can't wait
to go to college
and get started on my real life,
but you guys are my life.
This is a classic
Goosebumps moment.
Do you remember
Say Cheese and Die...?
- This is real life, Chu!
- Okay.
Guys, Slappy is using the Tesla
Tower to power Halloween.
If I can get in there,
maybe I can
shut it off,
and we can save Mom.
But there's
monsters everywhere.
How are we gonna
get past them?
Easy.
Camouflage.
Welcome to my crafts lab.
Wow.
♪ Steady on my grind and got no
Time for playing games ♪
♪ Money on my mind, I'm kicking
As I'm taking names ♪
♪ The heat is on
Get out the kitchen ♪
♪ If you can't handle
The flames ♪
♪ I'm hustling
I was born to win ♪
♪ Ain't never gonna change ♪
♪ Let me tell you now
I don't know how ♪
♪ But the whole world's
Gonna know my name ♪
♪ Just wait and see
They gon' talk about me ♪
♪ Things ain't never
Gon' be the same ♪
♪ Are you ready? ♪
♪ Better make way
'Cause I'm coming through ♪
♪ Are you ready for me? ♪
♪ You know I'm gonna be
Legendary ♪
Jeez,
they're still everywhere.
It's actually working.
Come on. We gotta
get to that tower.
I can't believe
we're really here.
I can barely see
out of this thing.
Is it cool?
Is it awesome?
Hey, fanboy. Let's focus.
Right. Sorry.
Let's go.
Don't. Move.
Come on, let's go.
Come on!
Look at this place.
It's so creepy.
Stay close.
No wonder Tesla
abandoned this place.
Shh, shh, shh.
Do you hear that?
Come on.
Oh, no.
Not Haunted Halloween.
Oh, my writing was
so cliché back then.
I knew it! I knew I came up
with that first.
That clever little dummy's
writing his own ending.
Not in my book,
he's not.
Oh, gnomes.
Don't you dare.
Stay.
Ow! Son of a... Ah!
Oh, witches!
Get away, witches!
- Guys, do you hear that?
- Shh!
Wow.
Whoa.
Welcome.
Slappy.
Walter?
Where's my mother?
Don't you mean our mother?
There's my sweet little babies.
I just love a family reunion.
- Mom.
- What did you do?
I had a papa once!
He let me down.
But a mother's love
is forever.
Turn her back now,
you psycho!
Oh, should I?
Unfortunately,
I have other plans.
Walter!
The book, please.
Yes.
This book.
Go prepare the tower!
I'm going to do what
Stine couldn't:
Finish this book,
once and for all.
Spoiler alert:
The manuscript gets destroyed
in that tower,
and my Halloween family
lasts forever!
Mama,
babysit the children for me.
Yes, dear.
We can't let him
destroy that book.
Sonny, turn this thing off.
I'm going after Slappy.
Just you and me now,
Slappy.
Can't hear you. I'm too far
ahead of you. Hee-hee-hee!
This is amperage
and this is voltage?
None of these cables
make any sense.
What about here?
Start pulling levers.
- No, no, Sam, don't!
- Ah!
Slappy booby-trapped
all this stuff.
Careful, Sarah. It'd be a shame
to fall from that height.
Plenty more
where that came from.
Come on, Sonny,
turn this thing off.
Oh, no. Sonny hurry up.
Slappy's at the top.
Do something.
I can't do it, Sam.
Come on, Sonny.
You are the smartest kid I know.
Sam, I couldn't even do
my little science project.
Slappy did that.
And even that one shorted out.
Wait. That's it.
We turn it up. All the way up.
We blow the fuse.
- Yes!
- The fuse is over there.
And now to finish this story
and destroy the town.
No!
What do you think
you're doing?
Writing my own ending.
Spoiler alert:
I save the town
and put you back
where you belong.
What's the matter?
Writer's block?
Again?
- Grab that lever. Yes.
- This one?
On my count,
we push up at the same time.
Ready? Go!
Give me the book.
You're not gonna
get this book, Slappy.
I have a friend
who might think otherwise.
Nowhere else to run, sis!
Fine. You win, Slappy.
I'll give you the book,
but you gotta turn my mom back.
Deal.
It all ends
Slappily ever after.
You forgot one thing:
Never judge a book
by its cover.
What?
No!
Sonny, what's happening?
Mom.
We need to get out of here!
It's working!
Go, kids!
Hello?
Someone called for me?
- Sarah? Oh! Oh...
- Mom!
Hello?
I got your message.
I'm here.
Don't worry.
Everything's going to be okay.
I need typing paper,
a thesaurus,
Diet Coke,
and a quiet place to compose.
Preferably in a comfortable
chair with lumbar support.
Are you R.L. Stine?
Me? No, I'm Dr. Seuss.
R.L. Stine was unavailable.
Yes, of course,
I'm R.L. Stine!
Then I guess this
belongs to you.
Don't open it.
My first book.
You realize I wrote this
when I was around your age.
More of an amateur work, really,
but I am sure you'll all agree
it shows the undeniable promise
of a brilliant young writer.
Why do you have
a typewriter?
I was going to
save you with it,
although it appears you found
a way to save yourselves.
- A typewriter?
- It's been done before.
Once before.
Maybe twice.
Maybe more.
Kathy?
Walter, manager
at Fred's Pharmacy.
It's nice to see you.
Hi. It's nice to
see you too.
What are you doing here?
I don't know.
Walter! Walter!
You got turned into a monster.
You were big, green, ugly.
You were Slappy's henchman!
Weather patterns.
Very strange weather patterns.
But I think everything's
back to normal now.
Fine. Okay, yeah,
the weather has been weird.
It's true. Okay, thanks.
What happened to your shirt?
I don't know.
Ixnay on the onsters-may.
- Go ahead, ollow-fay.
- What?
Means "follow." Pig Latin.
Oh, the youth today.
So funny running into you.
Right? I always hoped we'd run
into each other outside of work.
Yeah, me too.
Hey, if you're not
busy next week,
would you wanna
have some dinner?
- Yeah. Yeah, heh, heh.
- Yeah? That's awesome.
So they don't remember
what happened to them?
The transmutation process
seems to have wiped
their memories clean.
All those who were affected
won't remember a thing.
Tommy?
- Are you okay?
- Oh, my God. Guys.
I had this crazy dream.
I'm so glad to see you.
You know, can't believe
I'm saying this,
but I'm glad
to see you too, Tommy.
Kids falling
from the sky.
My work here is done.
I'm a writer too.
Well, an aspiring,
very stuck writer at the moment.
My condolences.
All the horrors
in the world can't compare
to the terrors
of the blank page.
Um, any advice
on college essays?
Well, first rule of writing:
write what you know.
Thirty years,
and I couldn't figure out
how this book should end.
And somehow you figured out
how to finish it
in one night.
I believe in you.
Hm. "Write what you know."
Recount a time in your life
when you faced a fear,
challenge or failure.
I think most of us
are afraid
that we don't have
a story to tell.
That there's nothing
special about us.
And then a moment comes
when you least expect it
where you have to step up,
no matter
how terrified you are.
But what
I've learned is that
it's good to be scared
sometimes.
Scared of losing
the people we love.
- Stop, stop!
- It's a ventriloquist dummy.
- Oh.
- Really?
- That's not funny, Mom.
- Too soon.
No, I like it.
Congratulations,
Sonny.
Thank you so much,
Principal Harrison.
Or scared of not
achieving our dreams.
Because those moments
remind us
just how special
our stories really are.
- Here's to us.
- Indeed.
- Hey, Sarah!
- Hi, Mr. Chu.
Watch this.
I like it.
Yeah, I just made it
life-size this year.
You know, just in case.
No, seriously, you know,
just in case.
Right. I'll see you later,
Mr. Chu.
Bye!
And maybe when you
face enough of your fears
life stops being
so scary after all.
♪ Now's the day
To make our dreams alive ♪
Hey, honey.
What happened?
I got in.
I knew it.
I knew you could do it.
Oh, I'm so proud
of you!
I guess I'm proud.
- Thanks, Sonny.
- Come on, bring it in.
Congratulations.
Here, take off your jacket.
Guys, give her some
ornaments, please.
Oh, yeah,
yeah, yeah.
- I'm so happy!
- Ha-ha-ha!
- Here, put that right there.
- Yeah, I like that one.
Finally, a new book.
Yes.
Hello, Papa.
Slappy! I thought
the book got you.
Maybe those others,
but not me.
Why is that?
You know
I always survive.
You wrote me that way.
In fact, I wrote my own story
while I was gone.
And guess what.
You're the main character.
No.
No!
You try living in a book
for a while, Papa.
Hyah!
Hands off!
Hiya! Look at my candle.
Slappy Halloween.
Subtitles by explosiveskull