Listen to me, please.
You're like me, a Homo sapiens.
A wise human.
Life, a miracle in the universe,
appeared around
four billion years ago,
and we humans
only 200,000 years ago.
Yet we have succeeded
in disrupting the balance...
that is so essential to life on Earth.
Listen carefully to this
extraordinary story, which is yours,
and decide what
you want to do with it.
dd
These are traces of our origins.
At the beginning, our planet
was no more than a chaos of fire,
formed in the wake
of its star, the sun.
A cloud of agglutinated
dust particles,
similar to so many
similar clusters in the universe.
Yet this was where
the miracle of life occurred.
dd
Today, life- our life-
is just a link in a chain of
innumerable living beings...
that have succeeded one another
on Earth over nearly four billion years.
And even today, new volcanoes
continue to sculpt our landscapes.
They offer a glimpse of what
our Earth was like at its birth—
molten rock surging from the depths,
solidifying, cracking,
blistering or spreading
in a thin crust,
before falling dormant for a time.
These wreaths of smoke curling
from the bowels of the Earth...
bear witness to the Earth's
original atmosphere.
An atmosphere devoid of oxygen.
A dense atmosphere,
thick with water vapor,
full of carbon dioxide.
A furnace.
But the Earth had an exceptional
future, offered to it by water.
At the right distance from the sun—
not too far, not too near—
the Earth was able to
conserve water in liquid form.
Water vapor condensed and fell
in torrential downpours on Earth,
and rivers appeared.
The rivers shaped
the surface of the Earth,
cutting their channels,
furrowing out valleys.
They ran toward the lowest places
on the globe to form the oceans.
They tore minerals from the rocks,
and gradually the freshwater
of the oceans...
became heavy with salt.
Water is a vital liquid.
It irrigated these sterile expanses.
The paths it traced
are like the veins of a body,
the branches of a tree, the vessels of
the sap that it brought to the Earth.
dd
Nearly four billion years later,
somewhere on Earth
can still be found these works of art,
left by the volcanoes' ash, mixed
with water from Iceland's glaciers.
There they are- matter and water,
water and matter-
soft and hard combined, the crucial alliance
shared by every life-form on our planet.
dd
Minerals and metals
are even older than the Earth.
They are stardust.
They provide the Earth's colors.
Red from iron, black from carbon,
blue from copper, yellow from sulfur.
Where do we come from?
Where did life first spark into being?
A miracle of time,
primitive life-forms still exist
in the globe's hot springs.
They give them their colors.
They're called archaeobacteria.
They all feed off the Earth's heat-
all except the cyanobacteria,
or blue-green algae.
They alone have the capacity to turn
to the sun to capture its energy.
They are a vital ancestor of all
yesterday's and today's plant species.
These tiny bacteria...
and their billions of descendants...
changed the destiny of our planet.
They transformed its atmosphere.
What happened to the carbon
that poisoned the atmosphere?
It's still here,
imprisoned in the Earth's crust.
We can read this chapter
of the Earth's history...
nowhere better than on the walls
of Colorado's Grand Canyon.
They reveal nearly two billion years
of the Earth's history.
Once upon a time, the Grand Canyon
was a sea inhabited by microorganisms.
They grew their shells by tapping into
carbon from the atmosphere...
dissolved in the ocean.
When they died, the shells sank...
and accumulated on the seabed.
These strata are the product of those
billions and billions of shells.
Thanks to them, the carbon
drained from the atmosphere,
and other life-forms could develop.
It is life that altered the atmosphere.
Plant life fed off the sun's energy,
which enabled it to break apart
the water molecule...
and take the oxygen.
And oxygen filled the air.
The Earth's water cycle
is a process of constant renewal.
Waterfalls, water vapor,
clouds, rain, springs,
rivers, seas, oceans, glaciers.
The cycle is never broken.
There's always the same
quantity of water on Earth.
All the successive species on Earth
have drunk the same water.
The astonishing matter that is water.
One of the most unstable of all.
It takes a liquid form
as running water,
gaseous as vapor...
or solid as ice.
In Siberia, the frozen surfaces
of the lakes in winter...
contain the traces of the forces
that water deploys when it freezes.
Lighter than water, the ice floats,
rather than sinking to the bottom.
It forms a protective mantle
against the cold,
under which life can go on.
The engine of life is linkage.
Everything is linked.
Nothing is self-sufficient.
Water and air are inseparable,
united in life
and for our life on Earth.
Thus, clouds form over the oceans
and bring rain to the landmasses,
whose rivers carry water
back to the oceans.
Sharing is everything.
The green expanse peeking through the
clouds is the source of oxygen in the air.
Seventy percent of this gas, without
which our lungs cannot function,
comes from the algae
that tint the surface of the oceans.
Our Earth relies on a balance...
in which every being
has a role to play...
and exists only through
the existence of another being.
A subtle, fragile harmony
that is easily shattered.
Thus, corals are born
from the marriage of algae and shells.
The Great Barrier Reef,
off the coast of Australia,
stretches over
350,000 square kilometers...
and is home to 1,500 species of fish,
4,000 species of mollusks...
and 400 species of coral.
The equilibrium of every ocean
depends on these corals.
The Earth counts time
in billions of years.
It took more than four billion years
for it to make trees.
In the chain of species,
trees are a pinnacle,
a perfect living sculpture.
Trees defy gravity.
They are the only natural element
in perpetual movement toward the sky.
They grow unhurriedly toward the sun
that nourishes their foliage.
They have inherited from those
minuscule cyanobacteria...
the power to capture light's energy.
They store it and feed off it,
turning it into wood and leaves,
which then decompose
into a mixture of water,
mineral, vegetable and living matter.
And so, gradually,
the soils that are indispensable
to life are formed.
Soils are the factory of biodiversity.
They are a world
of incessant activity...
where microorganisms feed,
dig, aerate and transform.
They make the humus, the fertile layer
to which all life on land is linked.
What do we know about life on Earth?
How many species are we aware of?
A 1 Oth of them? A hundredth perhaps?
What do we know about
the bonds that link them?
The Earth is a miracle.
Life remains a mystery.
dd
Families of animals form,
united by customs and rituals
that survive today.
dd
Some adapt to the nature
of their pasture,
and their pasture adapts to them.
And both gain.
The animal sates its hunger,
and the tree can blossom again.
dd
In the great adventure
of life on Earth,
every species has a role to play,
every species has its place.
None is futile or harmful.
They all balance out.
And that's where you,
Homo sapiens- "wise human"-
enter the story.
You benefit from a fabulous...
four-billion-year-old legacy
bequeathed by the Earth.
dd
You're only 200,000 years old,
but you have changed
the face of the world.
Despite your vulnerability,
you have taken possession
of every habitat...
and conquered swaths of territory...
like no other species before you.
dd
After 180,000 nomadic years,
and thanks to a more clement climate,
humans settled down.
They no longer depended on
hunting for survival.
They chose to live
in wet environments...
that abounded
in fish, game and wild plants.
There, where land,
water and life combine.
dd
Human genius inspired them
to build canoes,
an invention that
opened up new horizons...
and turned humans into navigators.
dd
Even today,
the majority of humankind...
lives on the continents' coastlines...
or the banks of rivers and lakes.
The first towns grew up
less than 600 years ago.
It was a considerable leap
in human history.
Why towns? Because they allowed humans
to defend themselves more easily.
They became social beings,
meeting and sharing
knowledge and crafts,
blending their similarities
and differences.
In a word, they became civilized.
But the only energy at their disposal
was provided by nature...
and the strength of their bodies.
It was the story of humankind
for thousands of years.
It still is for one person in four-
over one and a half billion
human beings-
more than the combined
population of all the wealthy nations.
Taking from the Earth
only the strictly necessary.
For a long time, the relationship
between humans and the planet...
was evenly balanced.
For a long time, the economy seemed
like a natural and equitable alliance.
But life expectancy is short,
and hard labor takes its toll.
The uncertainties of nature
weigh on daily life.
Education is a rare privilege.
Children are a family's only asset,
as long as every
extra pair of hands...
is a necessary contribution
to its subsistence.
The Earth feeds people,
clothes them...
and provides for their daily needs.
Everything comes from the Earth.
Towns change humanity's nature,
as well as its destiny.
The farmer becomes a craftsman,
trader or peddler.
What the Earth gives the farmer,
the city dweller buys, sells or barters.
Goods change hands,
along with ideas.
Humanity's genius is to have always
had a sense of its weakness.
Humans tried to extend
the frontiers of their territory,
but they knew their limits.
The physical energy and strength with
which nature had not endowed them...
was found in the animals
they domesticated to serve them.
But how can you conquer
the world on an empty stomach?
The invention of agriculture...
transformed the future of the wild
animals scavenging for food...
that were humankind.
Agriculture turned
their history on end.
Agriculture was
their first great revolution.
Developed barely
8,000 to 10,000 years ago,
it changed
their relationship to nature.
It brought an end to the uncertainty
of hunting and gathering.
It resulted in the first surpluses...
and gave birth to cities
and civilizations.
For their agriculture,
humans harnessed the energy
of animal species and plant life,
from which they at last
extracted the profits.
The memory of thousands of years
scrabbling for food faded.
They learned to adapt the grains
that are the yeast of life...
to different soils and climates.
They learned to increase the yield
and multiply the number of varieties.
Like every species on Earth,
the principal
daily concern of all humans...
is to feed themselves
and their family.
When the soil is less generous
and water becomes scarce,
humans deploy prodigious efforts
to mark a few arid acres...
with the imprint of their labor.
Humans shaped the land with the patience
and devotion that the Earth demands,
in an almost sacrificial ritual
performed over and over.
Agriculture is still the world's
most widespread occupation.
Half of humankind tills the soil,
over three-quarters of them by hand.
Agriculture is like
a tradition handed down...
from generation to generation
in sweat, graft and toil,
because for humanity it is
a prerequisite of survival.
But after relying on
muscle power for so long,
humankind found a way to tap into
the energy buried deep in the Earth.
These flames are also from plants.
A pocket of sunlight.
Pure energy— the energy of the sun—
captured over millions of years
by millions of plants...
more than a hundred million years ago.
It's coal. It's gas.
And above all, it's oil.
And this pocket of sunlight freed
humans from their toil on the land.
With oil began the era of humans
who break free of the shackles of time.
With oil, some of us acquired
unprecedented comforts.
And in 50 years, in a single lifetime,
the Earth has been
more radically changed...
than by all previous
generations of humanity.
Faster and faster.
In the last 60 years, the Earth's
population has almost tripled,
and over two billion people
have moved to the cities.
Faster and faster.
Shenzhen, in China, with its hundreds of
skyscrapers and millions of inhabitants,
was just a small fishing village
barely 40 years ago.
Faster and faster.
In Shanghai,
3,000 towers and skyscrapers...
have been built in 20 years.
Hundreds more are under construction.
Today, over half of the world's
seven billion inhabitants live in cities.
New York.
The world's first megalopolis...
is the symbol of the exploitation
of the energy...
the Earth supplies to human genius.
The manpower
of millions of immigrants,
the energy of coal,
the unbridled power of oil.
Electricity resulted
in the invention of elevators,
which in turn permitted
the invention of skyscrapers.
New York ranks as the 16th-largest
economy in the world.
America was the first
to discover, exploit and harness...
the phenomenal revolutionary
power of black gold.
With its help,
a country of farmers became a country
of agricultural industrialists.
Machines replaced men.
A liter of oil generates
as much energy...
as 100 pairs of hands in 24 hours,
but worldwide only three percent
of farmers have use of a tractor.
Nonetheless, their output
dominates the planet.
In the United States,
only three million farmers are left.
They produce enough grain
to feed two billion people.
But most of that grain
is not used to feed people.
Here, and in all other
industrialized nations,
it's transformed
into livestock feed or biofuels.
The pocket of sunshine's energy...
chased away the specter of drought
that stalked farmland.
No spring escapes
the demands of agriculture,
which accounts for
70% of humanity's water consumption.
In nature, everything is linked.
The expansion of cultivated land
and single-crop farming...
encouraged the development
of parasites.
Pesticides, another gift of
the petrochemical revolution,
exterminated them.
Bad harvests and famine
became a distant memory.
The biggest headache now...
was what to do with the surpluses
engendered by modern agriculture.
But toxic pesticides
seeped into the air,
soil, plants, animals,
rivers and oceans.
They penetrated the heart of cells...
similar to the mother cell
that is shared by all forms of life.
Are they harmful to the humans
that they released from hunger?
These farmers,
in their yellow protective suits,
probably have a good idea.
The new agriculture abolished
the dependence on soils and seasons.
Fertilizers produced
unprecedented results...
on plots of land thus far ignored.
Crops adapted to soils and climates...
gave way to the most productive
varieties and the easiest to transport.
And so, in the last century,
three-quarters of the varieties developed
by farmers over thousands of years...
have been wiped out.
As far as the eye can see,
fertilizer below, plastic on top.
The greenhouses of Almeria in Spain...
are Europe's vegetable garden.
A city of uniformly sized
vegetables...
waits every day
for the hundreds of trucks...
that will take them
to the continent's supermarkets.
The more a country develops,
the more meat its inhabitants consume.
How can growing worldwide
demand be satisfied...
without recourse to concentration
camp-style cattle farms?
Faster and faster.
Like the life cycle of livestock
which may never see a meadow,
manufacturing meat faster than
the animal has become a daily routine.
In these vast food lots,
trampled by millions of cattle,
not a blade of grass grows.
A fleet of trucks from
every corner of the country...
brings in tons of grain, soy meal...
and protein-rich granules
that will become tons of meat.
The result is that it takes
100 liters of water...
to produce one kilogram of potatoes,
4,000 for one kilo of rice...
and 13,000 for one kilo of beef.
Not to mention the oil guzzled in
the production process and transport.
Our agriculture
has become oil-powered.
It feeds twice as many
humans on Earth...
but has replaced diversity
with standardization.
It has offered many of us
comforts we could only dream of,
but it makes our way of life
totally dependent on oil.
This is the new measure of time.
Our world's clock
now beats to the rhythm...
of these indefatigable machines...
tapping into the pocket of sunlight.
Their regularity reassures us.
The tiniest hiccup
throws us into disarray.
The whole planet is attentive
to these metronomes...
of our hopes and illusions.
The same hopes and illusions
that proliferate along with our needs,
increasingly insatiable desires
and profligacy.
We know that the end
of cheap oil is imminent,
but we refuse to believe it.
For many of us, the American dream
is embodied by a legendary name:
Los Angeles.
In this city that stretches
over 100 kilometers,
the number of cars is almost
equal to the number of inhabitants.
Here, energy puts on
a fantastic show every night.
The days seem to be no more
than the pale reflection of nights...
that turn the city into a starry sky.
Faster and faster.
Distances are no longer counted
in miles but in minutes.
The automobile shapes new suburbs
where every home is a castle,
a safe distance from
the asphyxiated city centers,
and where neat rows of houses
huddle round dead-end streets.
The model of a lucky few countries...
has become a universal dream,
preached by televisions
all over the world.
Even here in Beijing,
it is cloned, copied and reproduced...
in these formatted houses
that have wiped pagodas off the map.
The automobile has become
the symbol of comfort and progress.
If this model were followed
by every society,
the planet wouldn't have 900
million vehicles, as it does today,
but five billion.
Faster and faster.
The more the world develops,
the greater its thirst for energy.
Everywhere, machines dig,
bore and rip from the Earth...
the pieces of stars buried in
its depths since its creation:
minerals.
In the next 20 years, more ore
will be extracted from the Earth...
than in the whole
of humanity's history.
As a privilege of power,
80% of this mineral wealth...
is consumed by 20%
of the world's population.
Before the end of this century,
excessive mining will have exhausted
nearly all the planet's reserves.
Faster and faster.
Shipyards churn out oil tankers,
container ships and gas tankers...
to cater for the demands
of globalized industrial production.
Most consumer goods travel
thousands of kilometers...
from the country of production
to the country of consumption.
Since 1950,
the volume of international trade...
has increased 20 times over.
Ninety percent of trade goes by sea.
500 million containers
are transported every year,
headed for the world's
major hubs of consumption,
such as Dubai.
Dubai is one of the biggest
construction sites in the world—
a country where the impossible
becomes possible.
Building artificial islands
in the sea, for example.
Dubai has few natural resources,
but with the money from oil, it can bring
millions of tons of material and people...
from all over the world.
It can build forests of skyscrapers,
each one taller than the last,
or even a ski slope
in the middle of the desert.
Dubai has no farmland,
but it can import food.
Dubai has no water,
but it can afford to expend
immense amounts of energy...
to desalinate seawater and build
the highest skyscrapers in the world.
Dubai has endless sun
but no solar panels.
It is the city of more is more,
where the wildest dreams
become reality.
Dubai is a sort of culmination
of the Western model,
with its 800-meter high totem
to total modernity...
that never fails to amaze the world.
Excessive? Perhaps.
Dubai appears to have made its choice.
It is like the new beacon
for all the world's money.
Nothing seems further removed
from nature than Dubai,
although nothing depends
on nature more than Dubai.
The city merely follows
the model of wealthy nations.
We haven't understood that we're
depleting what nature provides.
dd
What do we know of the marine world,
of which we see only the surface,
and which covers
three-quarters of the planet?
The ocean depths remain a secret.
They contain thousands of species
whose existence remains a mystery to us.
dd
Since 1950, fishing catches
have increased fivefold,
from 18 to 100 million
metric tons a year.
Thousands of factory ships
are emptying the oceans.
Three-quarters
of fishing grounds are exhausted,
depleted or in danger of being so.
Most large fish have been
fished out of existence,
since they have no time to reproduce.
We are destroying the cycle of a life
that was given to us.
On the coastlines, signs of
the exhaustion of stocks abound.
First sign: Colonies of sea
mammals are getting smaller.
Made vulnerable by urbanization
of the coasts and pollution,
they now face a new threat: famine.
In their unequal battle
against industrial fishing fleets,
they can't find enough fish
to feed their young.
dd
Second sign:
Seabirds must fly ever greater
distances to find food.
At the current rate, all fish stocks
are threatened with exhaustion.
dd
In Dakar, traditional net fishing
boomed in the years of plenty,
but today, fish stocks are dwindling.
dd
Fish is the staple diet
of one in five humans.
dd
Can we envision the inconceivable?
Abandoned boats,
seas devoid offish?
dd
We have forgotten
that resources are scarce.
500 million humans live
in the world's desert lands,
more than the combined
population of Europe.
They know the value of water.
They know how to use it sparingly.
Here, they depend on wells
replenished by fossil water,
which accumulated underground in the
days when it rained on these deserts,
25,000 years ago.
Fossil water also enables crops
to be grown in the desert...
to provide food for local populations.
The fields' circular shape...
derives from the pipes that
irrigate them around a central pivot.
But there is a heavy price to pay.
Fossil water
is a nonrenewable resource.
In Saudi Arabia, the dream of industrial
farming in the desert has faded.
As if on a parchment map,
the light spots on this patchwork
show abandoned plots.
The irrigation equipment
is still there.
The energy to pump water also.
But the fossil water reserves
are severely depleted.
Israel turned the desert
into arable land.
Even though these hothouses
are now irrigated drop by drop,
water consumption continues
to increase along with exports.
The once mighty river Jordan
is now just a trickle.
Its water has flown to supermarkets
all over the world...
in crates of fruit and vegetables.
The Jordan's fate is not unique.
Across the planet,
one major river in 10...
no longer flows into the sea
for several months of the year.
The Dead Sea derives its name
from its incredibly high salinity...
that makes all life impossible.
Deprived of the Jordan's water,
its level goes down
by over one meter per year.
Its salinity is increasing.
Evaporation, due to the heat,
produces these fine islands
of salt evaporites-
beautiful but sterile.
In Rajasthan, India,
Udaipur is a miracle of water.
The city was made possible
by a system of dams and channels...
that created an artificial lake.
For its architects,
was water so precious...
that they dedicated a palace to it?
India risks being the country
that suffers most...
from the lack of water
in the coming century.
Massive irrigation
has fed the growing population,
and in the last 50 years,
21 million wells have been dug.
The victory over famine
has a downside, however.
In many parts of the country, the drill
has to sink ever deeper to hit water.
In western India,
30% of wells have been abandoned.
The underground
aquifers are drying out.
Vast reservoirs will catch the monsoon
rains to replenish the aquifers.
In dry season, women from local
villages dig them with their bare hands.
Thousands of kilometers away,
800 to 1,000 liters of water...
are consumed per person per day.
Las Vegas was built out of the desert.
Millions of people live there.
Thousands more arrive every month.
The inhabitants of Las Vegas are among the
biggest consumers of water in the world.
Palm Springs is another desert city...
with tropical vegetation
and lush golf courses.
How long can this mirage
continue to prosper?
The Earth cannot keep up.
The Colorado River,
which brings water to these cities,
is one of those rivers
that no longer reaches the sea.
Even more alarmingly,
its flow is diminishing at source.
Water levels in the catchment lakes
along its course...
are plummeting.
Lake Powell took 17 years
to reach high-water mark.
Its level is now half of that.
Water shortages could affect
nearly two billion people...
before 2025.
Yet water is still abundant
in unspoiled regions of the planet.
The wetlands.
These wetlands are crucial
to all life on Earth.
They represent
six percent of the planet.
Marshes are sponges
that regulate the flow of water.
They absorb it in the wet season...
and release it in the dry season.
The water runs off the mountain peaks,
carrying with it the seeds
of the regions it flows through.
This process gives birth
to unique landscapes,
where the diversity of species
is unequaled in its richness.
Under the calm water
lies a veritable factory...
where this ultimately linked
richness and diversity...
patiently filters the water
and digests all the pollution.
Marshes are
indispensable environments...
for the regeneration
and purification of water.
These wetlands were always seen
as unhealthy expanses,
unfit for human habitation.
In our race to conquer more land,
we have reclaimed them
as pasture for our livestock,
or as land for agriculture
or building.
In the last century, half of
the world's marshes were drained.
We know neither their richness
nor their role.
All living matter is linked.
dd
Water, air, soil, trees.
The world's magic
is right in front of our eyes.
dd
Trees breathe groundwater
into the atmosphere as light mist.
They form a canopy that alleviates
the impact of heavy rains...
and protects the soil from erosion.
The forests provide the humidity
that is necessary for life.
They are the mother
and father of rain.
dd
The forests store carbon.
They contain more than
all the Earth's atmosphere.
They are the cornerstone
of the climatic balance...
on which we all depend.
dd
Trees provide a habitat for three-quarters
of the planet's biodiversity—
that is to say, of all life on Earth.
Every year, we discover new species
we had no idea existed—
insects, birds, mammals.
dd
These forests provide
the remedies that cure us.
The substances secreted
by these plants...
can be recognized by our bodies.
Our cells talk the same language.
We are of the same family.
dd
Mangroves are forests
that step out onto the sea.
Like coral reefs,
they are a nursery for the oceans.
Their roots entwine
and form a shelter for the fish...
and mollusks that come to breed.
Mangroves protect the coasts
from hurricanes,
tidal waves and erosion by the sea.
Whole peoples depend on them.
Yet, they were reduced by half
during the 20th century.
One of the reasons
for the ongoing disaster...
is these shrimp farms installed
on the mangroves' rich waters.
Ventilators aerate pools
full of antibiotics...
to prevent the asphyxiation
of the shrimps,
not that of the mangroves.
Since the 1960s, deforestation
has constantly gathered pace.
Every year, 13 million hectares
of tropical forest-
an area the size of Illinois-
disappear in smoke and as lumber.
The world's largest rain forest,
the Amazon,
has already been reduced by 20%.
The forest gives way
to cattle ranches or soybean farms.
Ninety-five percent
of these soybeans...
are used to feed livestock
and poultry in Europe and Asia.
And so, a forest is turned into meat.
When they burn,
forests and their soils...
release huge quantities of carbon,
accounting for 20% of the greenhouse
gases emitted across the globe.
Deforestation is one of the principal
causes of global warming.
Thousands of species
disappear forever.
With them, one of the links
in a long chain of evolution snaps.
The intelligence of the living matter
from which they came...
is lost forever.
Barely 20 years ago, Borneo,
the fourth-largest island in the world,
was covered by a vast primary forest.
At the current rate of deforestation,
it will have totally
disappeared within 10 years.
Living matter bonds water,
air, earth and the sun.
In Borneo,
this bond has been broken...
in what was one of the Earth's
greatest reservoirs of biodiversity.
This catastrophe was
provoked by the decision...
to produce palm oil,
the most consumed oil
in the world, on Borneo.
Palm oil not only caters
to our growing demand for food,
but also cosmetics, detergents
and, increasingly, alternative fuels.
The forest diversity was replaced
by a single species- the oil palm.
Mono culture is easy,
productive and rapid.
For local people,
it provides employment.
It is an agricultural industry.
Another example of massive
deforestation is the eucalyptus.
Eucalyptus is used to make paper pulp.
Plantations are growing, as demand for
paper has increased fivefold in 50 years.
Mono cultures of trees
are gaining ground all over the world.
But a monoculture is not a forest.
By definition,
there is little diversity.
One forest does not
replace another forest.
At the foot of these eucalyptus trees,
nothing grows,
because their leaves form a bed...
that is toxic for most other plants.
They grow quickly,
but exhaust water reserves.
Soybeans, palm oil, eucalyptus trees-
Deforestation destroys the essential
to produce the superfluous.
But elsewhere, deforestation
is a last resort to survive.
Over two billion people-
almost a third
of the world's population—
still depend on charcoal.
In Haiti, one of the world's
poorest countries,
charcoal is one of
the population's main consumables.
Once the pearl of the Caribbean,
Haiti can no longer feed
its population without foreign aid.
On the hills of Haiti, only two
percent of the forests are left.
Stripped bare, the soil no
longer absorbs the rainwater.
With no vegetation
and no roots to reinforce them,
nothing holds the soils back.
The rainwater washes them
down the hillsides as far as the sea.
Erosion impoverishes
the quality of the soils,
reducing their suitability
for agriculture.
In some parts of Madagascar,
the erosion is spectacular.
Whole hillsides bear deep gashes
hundreds of meters wide.
Thin and fragile,
soil is made by living matter.
With erosion, the fine layer of humus,
which took thousands of years
to form, disappears.
Here's one theory
of the story of the Rapa Nui,
the inhabitants of Easter Island,
that could perhaps
give us pause for thought.
Living on the most isolated
island in the world,
the Rapa Nui exploited
their resources...
until there was nothing left.
Their civilization did not survive.
On these lands stood
the highest palm trees in the world.
They have disappeared.
The Rapa Nui chopped them
all down for lumber.
They then had to face
widespread soil erosion.
The Rapa Nui could
no longer go fishing.
There were no trees to build canoes.
And yet the Rapa Nui formed one of the
most brilliant civilizations in the Pacific.
Innovative farmers, sculptors,
exceptional navigators,
they were caught in a vise of
overpopulation and dwindling resources.
They experienced social unrest,
revolts and famine.
Many did not survive the cataclysm.
The real mystery of Easter Island
is not how its strange statues got there.
We know now.
It's why the Rapa Nui
didn't react in time.
It's only one of a number of theories,
but it has particular
relevance to us today.
Since 1950, the world's
population has almost tripled.
And since 1950, we have more fundamentally
altered our island, the Earth,
than in all of our
200,000-year history.
Nigeria is the biggest
oil exporter in Africa,
and yet 70% of the population
lives under the poverty line.
The wealth is there, but the country's
inhabitants don't have access to it.
The same is true all over the globe.
Half the world's poor
live in resource-rich countries.
Our mode of development
has not fulfilled its promises.
In 50 years, the gap
between rich and poor...
has grown wider than ever.
Today, half the world's wealth...
is in the hands of the richest
two percent of the population.
Can such disparities be maintained?
They're the cause
of population movements...
whose scale we have yet
to fully realize.
The city of Lagos had a population
of 700,000 in 1960.
That will rise to 16 million by 2025.
Lagos is one of the fastest-growing
megalopolises in the world.
The new arrivals are mostly
farmers forced off the land...
for economic or demographic reasons,
or because of diminishing resources.
This is a radically new
type of urban growth,
driven by the urge to survive
rather than to prosper.
Every week, over a million people...
swell the populations
of the world's cities.
One human being in six
now lives in a precarious,
unhealthy, overpopulated environment,
without access to daily necessities...
such as water,
sanitation or electricity.
Hunger is spreading once more.
It affects nearly one billion people.
All over the planet, the poorest
scrabble to survive on scraps,
while we continue to dig for resources
that we can no longer live without.
We look farther and farther afield,
in previously unspoilt territory...
and in regions that are
increasingly difficult to exploit.
We're not changing our model.
Oil might run out?
We can still extract oil
from the tar sands of Canada.
The biggest trucks in the world
move thousands of tons of sand.
The process of heating
and separating bitumen...
from the sand requires
millions of cubic meters of water.
Colossal amounts of energy are needed.
The pollution is catastrophic.
The most urgent priority, apparently,
is to pick every pocket of sunlight.
Our oil tankers are getting
bigger and bigger.
Our energy requirements
are constantly increasing.
We try to power growth
like a bottomless oven...
that demands more and more fuel.
It's all about carbon.
In a few decades, the carbon
that made our atmosphere a furnace,
and that nature captured
over millions of years,
allowing life to develop,
will have largely been
pumped back out.
The atmosphere is heating up.
It would have been inconceivable
for a boat to be here just a few years ago.
Transport, industry,
deforestation, agriculture-
Our activities release gigantic
quantities of carbon dioxide.
Without realizing it,
molecule by molecule,
we have upset the Earth's
climatic balance.
All eyes are on the poles,
where the effects of
global warming are most visible.
It's happening fast- very fast.
The Northwest Passage that connects
America, Europe and Asia...
via the pole is opening up.
The Arctic ice cap is melting.
Under the effect of global warming,
the ice cap has lost 40%
of its thickness in 40 years.
Its surface area in the summer
shrinks year by year.
It could disappear before 2030.
Some predictions suggest 2015.
Soon these waters will be free of ice
several summer months a year.
The sunbeams that the ice sheet
previously reflected back...
now penetrate the dark water,
heating it up.
The warming process gathers pace.
This ice contains
the records of our planet.
The concentration of carbon dioxide...
hasn't been so high
for several hundred thousand years.
Humanity has never lived
in an atmosphere like this.
Is excessive exploitation of our resources
threatening the lives of every species?
Climate change accentuates the threat.
By 2050, a quarter
of the Earth's species...
could be threatened with extinction.
In these polar regions, the balance
of nature has already been disrupted.
Off the coast of Greenland,
there are more and more icebergs.
Around the North Pole,
the ice cap has lost...
30% of its surface area in 30 years.
But as Greenland
rapidly becomes warmer,
the freshwater of a whole continent...
flows into the salt water
of the oceans.
Greenland's ice contains 20%
of the freshwater of the whole planet.
If it melts, sea levels will
rise by nearly seven meters.
But there is no industry here.
Greenland's ice sheet
suffers from greenhouse gases...
emitted elsewhere on Earth.
Our ecosystem doesn't have borders.
Wherever we are, our actions
have repercussions on the whole Earth.
The atmosphere of our planet
is an indivisible whole.
It is an asset we share.
On Greenland's surface,
lakes are appearing on the landscape.
The ice cap has begun
to melt at a speed...
that even the most pessimistic
scientists did not envision 10 years ago.
More and more
of these glacier-fed rivers...
are merging together
and burrowing through the surface.
It was thought the water would freeze
in the depths of the ice.
On the contrary,
it flows under the ice,
carrying the ice sheet into the sea,
where it breaks into icebergs.
As the freshwater
of Greenland's ice sheet...
gradually seeps into
the salt water of the oceans,
low-lying lands
around the globe are threatened.
Sea levels are rising.
Water expanding
as it gets warmer caused,
in the 20th century alone,
a rise of 20 centimeters.
Everything becomes unstable.
Coral reefs, for example,
are extremely sensitive...
to the slightest change
in water temperature.
Thirty percent have disappeared.
They are an essential link
in the chain of species.
In the atmosphere, the major wind
streams are changing direction.
Rain cycles are altered.
The geography of climates is modified.
The inhabitants of low-lying
islands here in the Maldives,
for example, are on the front line.
They are increasingly concerned.
Some are already looking
for new, more hospitable lands.
If sea levels continue
to rise faster and faster,
what will major cities like Tokyo,
the world's most populous city, do?
Every year, scientists' predictions
become more and more alarming.
Seventy percent of the world's
population lives on coastal plains.
Eleven of the 15 biggest cities
stand on a coastline or river estuary.
As the seas rise,
salt will invade the water table,
depriving inhabitants
of drinking water.
Migratory phenomena are inevitable.
The only uncertainty
concerns their scale.
dd
In Africa, Mount Kilimanjaro
is unrecognizable.
Eighty percent of its
glaciers have disappeared.
In summer, the rivers no longer flow.
Local peoples are affected
by the lack of water.
Even on the world's highest peaks,
in the heart of the Himalayas,
eternal snows and glaciers
are receding.
dd
Yet these glaciers play
an essential role in the water cycle.
They trap the water
from the monsoons as ice...
and release it in the summer
when the snow melts.
The glaciers of the Himalayas are the
source of all the great Asian rivers-
the Indus, Ganges,
Mekong, Yangtze Kiang.
Two billion people
depend on them for drinking water...
and to irrigate their crops,
as in Bangladesh.
On the delta of the Ganges
and Brahmaputra,
Bangladesh is directly
affected by the phenomena...
occurring in the Himalayas
and at sea level.
This is one of the most populous
and poorest countries in the world.
It is already hit by global warming.
The combined impact of increasingly
dramatic floods and hurricanes...
could make a third
of its landmass disappear.
When populations are subjected
to these devastating phenomena,
they eventually move away.
Wealthy countries will not be spared.
Droughts are occurring
all over the planet.
In Australia,
half of farmland is already affected.
We are in the process
of compromising the climatic balance...
that has allowed us
to develop over 12,000 years.
More and more wildfires
encroach on major cities.
In turn, they exacerbate
global warming.
As the trees burn,
they release carbon dioxide.
The system that controls our climate
has been severely disrupted.
The elements on which it relies
have been disrupted.
The clock of climate change is ticking
in these magnificent landscapes.
Here in Siberia
and elsewhere across the globe,
it is so cold that the ground
is constantly frozen.
It's known as permafrost.
Under its surface lies
a climatic time bomb: methane,
a greenhouse gas 20 times
more powerful than carbon dioxide.
If the permafrost melts,
the methane released...
would cause the greenhouse effect
to race out of control,
with consequences no one can predict.
We would literally be
in unknown territory.
Humanity has no more than 10 years
to reverse the trend...
and avoid crossing
into this territory—
life on Earth
as we have never known it.
We have created phenomena
we cannot control.
Since our origins, water, air
and forms of life are intimately linked.
But recently,
we have broken those links.
Let's face the facts.
We must believe what we know.
All that we have just seen
is a reflection of human behavior.
We have shaped the Earth in our image.
We have very little time to change.
How can this century carry the burden
of nine billion human beings...
if we refuse to be called
to account...
for everything we alone have done?
dd
The cost of our actions is high.
Others pay the price without
having been actively involved.
I have seen refugee camps
as big as cities,
sprawling in the desert.
How many men, women and children...
will be left by the wayside tomorrow?
Must we always build walls...
to break the chain
of human solidarity,
separate peoples and protect the happiness
of some from the misery of others?
It's too late to be a pessimist.
I know that a single human
can knock down every wall.
It's too late to be a pessimist.
Worldwide, four children
out of five attend school.
Never has learning been given
to so many human beings.
Everyone, from richest to poorest,
can make a contribution.
Lesotho, one of the world's
poorest countries,
is proportionally the one that invests
most in its people's education.
Qatar, one of the world's
richest states,
has opened its doors
to the best universities.
Culture, education, research and
innovation are inexhaustible resources.
In the face of misery and suffering,
millions of N.G.O.'s prove
that solidarity between peoples...
is stronger than
the selfishness of nations.
In Bangladesh, a man
thought the unthinkable...
and founded a bank
that lends only to the poor.
In barely 30 years,
it has changed the lives...
of 150 million people
around the world.
Antarctica is a continent
with immense natural resources...
that no country can claim for itself,
a natural reserve devoted
to peace and science.
A treaty signed by 49 states has made
it a treasure shared by all humanity.
It's too late to be a pessimist.
Governments have acted to protect nearly two
percent of the world's territorial waters.
It's not much, but it's two
times more than 10 years ago.
The first natural parks were created
just over a century ago.
They cover over 13% of the continents.
They create spaces where
human activity is in step...
with the preservation
of species, soils and landscapes.
This harmony between humans
and nature can become the rule,
no longer the exception.
In the United States, New York has
realized that nature does for us.
These forests and lakes supply
all the drinking water the city needs.
In South Korea, the forests
have been devastated by war.
Thanks to a national
reforestation program,
they once more
cover 65% of the country.
More than 75% of paper is recycled.
Costa Rica has made a choice between military
spending and the conservation of its lands.
The country no longer has an army.
It prefers to devote its resources
to education, ecotourism...
and the protection
of its primary forest.
Gabon is one of the world's
leading producers of wood.
It enforces selective logging—
not more than one tree every hectare.
Its forests are one of the country's
most important economic resources,
but they have the time to regenerate.
Programs exist that guarantee
sustainable forest management.
They must become mandatory.
For consumers and producers,
justice is an opportunity
to be seized.
When trade is fair,
when both buyer and seller benefit,
everybody can prosper
and earn a decent living.
How can there be justice and equity...
between people whose only tools
are their hands...
and those who harvest their crops
with a machine and state subsidies?
Let's be responsible consumers.
Think about what we buy.
It's too late to be a pessimist.
I have seen agriculture
on a human scale.
It can feed the whole planet if meat production
doesn't take the food out of people's mouths.
I have seen fishermen
who take care what they catch...
and care for the riches of the ocean.
I have seen houses
producing their own energy.
5,000 people live in the world's
first ever eco-friendly district,
in Freiburg, Germany.
Other cities partner the project.
Mumbai is the thousandth to join them.
The governments of New Zealand,
Iceland, Austria, Sweden...
and other nations
have made the development...
of renewable energy sources
a top priority.
I know that 80% of the energy
we consume...
comes from fossil energy sources.
Every week, two new coal-fired generating
plants are built in China alone.
But I have also seen, in Denmark,
a prototype of a coal-fired plant...
that releases its carbon
into the soil rather than the air.
A solution for the future?
Nobody knows yet.
I have seen, in Iceland,
an electricity plant powered
by the Earth's heat— geothermal power.
I have seen a sea snake
lying on the swell...
to absorb the energy of the waves
and produce electricity.
I have seen wind farms
off the coast of Denmark...
that produce 20%
of the country's electricity.
The U.S.A., China, India,
Germany and Spain...
are the biggest investors
in renewable energy.
They have already created over
two and a half million jobs.
Where on Earth doesn't the wind blow?
I have seen desert expanses
baking in the sun.
Everything on Earth is linked,
and the Earth is linked to the sun,
its original energy source.
Can humans not imitate plants
and capture its energy?
In one hour,
the sun gives the Earth...
the same amount of energy as that
consumed by all humanity in one year.
As long as the Earth exists,
the sun's energy will be inexhaustible.
All we have to do is stop drilling
the Earth and start looking to the sky.
All we have to do
is learn to cultivate the sun.
All these experiments are only examples,
but they testify to a new awareness.
They lay down markers
for a new human adventure...
based on moderation,
intelligence and sharing.
dd
It's time to come together.
What's important is not what's gone,
but what remains.
We still have
half the world's forests,
thousands of rivers,
lakes and glaciers...
and thousands of thriving species.
dd
We know that the solutions
are there today.
We all have the power to change.
So what are we waiting for?
dd