(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Subtitles by explosiveskull
Resync by GoldenBeard
(THUNDER CRACKS)
HANNAH: Everyone was warned,
but no one listened.
A rise in temperature,
ocean patterns changed
and ice caps melted.
They called it extreme weather.
They didn't know
what "extreme" was.
In the year of 2019,
hurricanes,
tornadoes,
floods
and droughts
unleashed a wave of
destruction upon our planet.
We didn't just lose towns
or beachfronts.
We lost entire cities.
The East River swallowed
Lower Manhattan.
A heat wave killed two
million people in Madrid
in just one day.
But in that moment,
facing our own extinction,
it became clear
that no single nation
could solve this problem alone.
The world came together as one,
and we fought back.
Scientists from 17 countries,
led by the U.S. and China,
worked tirelessly.
Not as representatives
of their nations,
but of humanity.
They found a way
to neutralize the storms
with a net of
thousands of satellites
each deploying countermeasures
designed to impact the
basic elements of weather,
heat, pressure and water,
all overseen by the
International Space Station.
They gave the satellite net
a technical name,
but we all came to
call it Dutch Boy
after the story of the child
who plugged a dam
with his finger.
(EXPLOSIONS)
This is what saved us all.
And it was built by a team
led by one man...
my father.
- Thank you.
- Keep the change.
Uh, Jake Lawson.
I have a Senate...
Senate hearing in room 12.
Yeah.
Lawson?
- You're the Dutch Boy guy, right?
- Yeah.
Man, I need to shake your hand.
Oh, okay.
Tornado? Zap!
Blizzard? Zap!
Monsoon?
- Zap?
- Zap!
Everybody down here owes you,
Jake Lawson.
If you need anything,
you just ask.
- (INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- (CAMERAS CLICKING)
(GAVEL BANGING)
SENATOR CROSS:
The Senate Committee
assigned to oversee Dutch Boy
will now hear
from Jacob Lawson,
Climate ISS Chief Operations
Coordinator.
May the record reflect that
he was nearly one hour late.
Yeah, sorry about that. Uh...
(CLEARS THROAT)
I literally had to fly in
from outer space.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(SIGHS) Here we go.
Mr. Lawson, we find ourselves
heading toward a crossroads.
As you know, as per
UN Resolution 28-14,
the United States will be
handing over control of
Dutch Boy
to an International Oversight
Committee in three years.
This in spite of the fact that
we actually built the thing.
Uh, excuse me, Senator.
(STAMMERS) I don't wanna
slow things down.
Uh, you said "we" built it?
Yes, indeed, I did.
Because I know what I did.
I'm the guy that led the team
that built the station.
I was up there
with an international crew
of 600 people,
not just Americans.
And I know all of their faces,
but I don't remember yours.
We had a plumber up there.
He looked a little like you.
- (AUDIENCE CHUCKLING)
- Very clever, Mr. Lawson.
Yes, Dutch Boy was
an international effort
and, yes,
- it may, one day, very well...
- (CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
...belong to the world.
But until it does, we have
authority over its operation
and we have authority over you!
And you have been flouting
that authority.
I have report
after report here.
Failure to follow procedures,
numerous violations
of the chain of command.
And then, there was
the incident where
you punched a federal
inspector in the face.
Well, your federal inspector
doesn't know
that a capacitor
holds a charge
even when it's disconnected.
He was grabbing
for the damn thing.
I saved his life!
You can make all the excuses
you want, Mr. Lawson,
but there's one thing
you cannot defend.
And that would be the day
you brought
Dutch Boy online...
...and operational
without our consent!
And what would
that have taken, Senator?
There were a series of storms
building in Southeast Asia
and the North Atlantic
that would have killed
tens of thousands of people.
Dutch Boy was ready.
We went green. It works.
You're welcome.
Mr. Lawson, if you continue
to defy our authority...
...Dutch Boy will go on
without you!
Am I making myself clear?
Yes.
Good. Oh, and one more thing.
To ensure compliance,
this committee will be
sending up new support staff.
Naturally, when
they get up there,
you'll have to send some of
your people home.
We'll leave those choices
up to you.
Senator, respectfully,
my crew didn't do
anything wrong.
Excuse me, I'm not
asking for your input.
These people left their homes
and their families
and risked their lives
to save this planet.
- This hearing is adjourned.
- (GAVEL BANGS)
I'm not cutting a single one
of those people loose!
Excuse me?
People like you need people
like me. You know why?
So you can take credit
for everything we accomplish.
So you can go to
your constituents
and your cronies...
SENATOR CROSS: This meeting
is adjourned.
...and your mistresses
and puff out your chest
- and say, "Hey, look at me!"
- Sit down, please!
- Well, I'm looking, Senator.
- Excuse me.
- JAKE: We're all looking.
- This meeting is adjourned.
This meeting is adjourned!
Thank you.
(GAVEL BANGS)
Well, that was going well, huh?
Up to a point.
No, Jake, that didn't go well
at any point.
But, hey, what are you good
at, little brother, huh?
Like working the angles,
smoothing ruffled feathers?
You can fix it. You always do.
It's like a talent.
It is a talent.
Of a sort.
(SIGHS) I wish I could
help you. I really do.
But it's not that simple,
not this time.
Why not?
Well, as of last week,
they have put me in charge
of Dutch Boy.
(CHUCKLES) Well, that's great!
That's great! You kidding me?
(SIGHS)
You're kidding me.
Look, what do you want me
to do? Huh?
You leave me no choice.
I told you this had to
go well, and it didn't.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
I'm sorry, Jake.
You're fired.
Jesus. It's over 120
in this mother.
COLLNER: Fan out.
(ICE CRACKLING)
(GASPS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Hi, Agent Wilson.
Assistant Secretary Lawson.
Oh, you look nice today.
I'm wearing the same thing
I always wear.
Exactly.
Have you seen I, uh,
well, got on a new tie?
I observed.
We're trained to notice
any disturbing details.
(MAX CHUCKLES)
- Sarah, come on.
- Assistant Secretary Lawson,
I'm not permitted to engage
in casual conversation
while I'm at a post.
We are being watched.
We're always being watched.
Well, if we're always
being watched,
then what's the point of
hiding anything?
You're interfering
with my duties.
I'd rather not shoot you.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, it would be
an honor to be
the first person
that you kill.
- (CELL PHONE BUZZING)
- Hang on.
SARAH: What is it?
Uh, the president's called
a security briefing.
It was not on the schedule,
so I guess I'm now on duty.
I like the tie.
Home by 7:00. Love you.
I'm sorry,
I didn't catch that.
I didn't say anything.
Move along, sir.
Yes, ma'am.
PRESIDENT: What the hell
happened here?
MONTGRAFF: One of
our thermospheric satellites
malfunctioned
over Afghanistan.
A UN recon team found it,
Mr. President.
And the members of the Climate
Council, they're aware?
Yes, and they've all agreed
to keep the incident discreet.
But with this many people
in the loop,
I'm not sure
how long it's gonna keep.
And we're sure this was
caused by Dutch Boy?
Absolutely.
Can we assume that this is
an isolated incident?
Dr. Quigley?
We're fairly certain, yes.
It's great to know that
you're "fairly certain."
This is a serious malfunction.
So your proposal is what?
Simple. We shut down
all Central Asian satellites
until we know what went wrong.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, I'm serious.
Do you know how difficult
it was to get every one
of these nations
online for this?
PRESIDENT: We have worked
extremely hard
to assure these nations
that this system will
protect them, and it has.
And let's not forget, people,
it's an election year.
We shut Dutch Boy down,
the press is gonna jump
all over this.
DR. JENNINGS: Oh, my God!
300 people died
in that village.
(SCOFFS) I mean,
who gives a damn
about the politics of it all?
Look, we cost those people
their lives.
The only thing we should be concerned
about here is how to fix it
and making sure
it never happens again.
And how do you propose
we do that?
(SIGHING)
We can't do anything.
What I mean is, the problem is
not gonna be solved in this room
and, well,
certainly not by us.
No, no, we need
an international team
on the station itself.
You know, not suits.
Engineers, coders, builders,
doing a comprehensive
systems check,
no matter the cost,
no matter the politics
and we need 'em up there now.
We are set to transfer
full authority for Dutch Boy
to the international community
in two weeks.
I will not be the president
that hands over damaged goods.
Not now, not ever.
So we are gonna handle
this problem
and its solution in-house
and we are gonna send up
one man.
One of our own,
who reports only to us
and that we can control.
Understood?
So find me that someone.
Now.
Yes, sir.
Look, I know you're not gonna
like it, but as I see it,
there's only one person
to go after for this.
Your brother, Jake.
Come on, not Jake.
Seventeen countries, hmm?
Seventeen countries had teams
working on Dutch Boy.
They all reported to him.
Nobody knows what's under
the hood better than him.
Come on.
Can we weigh other options?
Max, how long
have you known me?
(CHUCKLES)
Ever since I was transferred
to the State Department.
That's right.
I handpicked you.
I believed in you.
You're smart.
And I was right about you.
I'm right about Jake.
If this is gonna
be a problem...
No, sir.
Good.
WOMAN 1: Afghan satellite
zero-niner-six inbound.
All crews prepare for incoming
Afghanistan satellite.
WOMAN 2: Replacement satellite
standing by.
HERNANDEZ:
Afghan sat is locked in.
Replacement cleared
for launch.
(ALARMS BLARING)
MAN: And away on sat 5-A.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Airlock doors secured.
I want a full dissection
of all components.
Priority one.
MAN: Afghan satellite
dissection commencing.
I will take care of this.
Make sure they depressurize
the fuel intake.
Yeah, we got it, man.
(WHIRRS)
(BEEPS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Makmoud. Oi, Makmoud!
I'm about to obliterate
your top score here, pal.
I have to do
some reprogramming.
Oh, come on!
He's got no pride of
ownership, that lad.
(BEEPING)
(LAUGHTER)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- (BUZZER BLARES)
- (GASPS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Please
stand clear of the doors.
Please stand clear
of the doors.
(SCREAMING)
Uncle Max?
Hey! What you doing up there?
What is that?
A solar generator?
Dual access sun-tracking
solar generator.
Replacing the power converter.
Oh, God! (CHUCKLES)
You're getting more
like your dad every day.
Hey, where'd he find that?
Are you seriously asking
that question?
MAX: Oh, of course.
He made it, right? Here.
Come here, you.
(GRUNTS AND LAUGHS)
MAX: Ah, it's good to see you!
How you doing? You okay?
I'm really great.
Okay, what's going on here?
All right,
this is freaking me out.
You're supposed to be
nine years old.
Thirteen.
You were supposed to be
a part of my life,
but shit happens.
Ouch.
So what's going on here?
You living with him now?
He gets me
two weekends a month.
Oh, good.
Ah, well, how's your mom?
Hmm, justifiably pissed.
I bet. (CHUCKLES)
JAKE: Hannah, it's time.
What's up, Jake?
Hannah, I thought I told you
not to talk to strangers.
(SIGHS) Come on.
Don't listen to him.
Your Dad and I were your age,
we were so close we had
our own secret code.
- That's true.
- JAKE: Really?
I don't remember that.
Yeah, you do.
No, I don't.
Well, it was nice seeing you.
Hey, look, you take care.
What's with all the car parts?
I build electric motors
for the retirees
down in Vero Beach.
Keeps me busy.
Seems hardly worth
your talent.
Kidding?
Having the time of my life.
It's a little early,
don't you think?
(GRUNTS)
I got fired by my own brother.
Then I lost my family,
my house, my dog,
so happy hour starts
around 11:00 out here.
Okay, saw your niece,
you don't want a beer.
Road's that way.
There's something wrong
with Dutch Boy.
JAKE: No, there isn't.
Well, an entire village of
dead Afghans
may disagree with you.
Yeah.
And then yesterday, an airlock
just opened by itself.
We lost one of our crew.
Dutch Boy is not
my problem any more.
That I am calling bullshit on.
'Cause other than
your daughter
and your precious soccer club,
Dutch Boy was all
you ever gave a damn about.
Oh, yeah, once.
Yeah, but you took care
of that.
You don't care?
No?
Well, then, what are you doing
living out here, hmm?
(DEEP RUMBLING)
Look, I know you think
I'm a weasel,
someone who just moves
pieces around a chessboard
for a living.
Well, guess what, yeah.
Yeah, I am.
But that is how you get
17 countries
to agree to build
a space station.
Now, you build things, right?
And there is something wrong
with the thing that you built
and people are dying.
If you really think
you're the best,
which I know that you do,
then how the hell can you
stand there and say no?
I'll be taking orders
from someone, I suppose.
Yeah.
So what? Is that a yes?
Long as it's not you, yeah.
(TYPING)
(DIALING)
(LINE RINGING)
Hey, this is Max.
Leave a message.
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (HORN HONKING)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKS CANTONESE)
You got any room
in there for me?
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORNS HONKING)
(GASPING)
- (GASPS)
- (BRAKES SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
(BEEPING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(STRAINING) Okay.
I think this is everything.
I made you
a packed lunch as well.
Did you hear about the gas
main explosions in Hong Kong?
Yeah, it just hit the news.
It's terrible.
Was it anything like what
happened in Afghanistan?
No, nothing happened
in Afghanistan.
Are you going back
up to space?
- No.
- Yes, you are!
You're leaving today
to fix Dutch Boy.
(SCOFFS) What did I tell you
about eavesdropping?
You've never told me anything
about eavesdropping.
You don't really do
much parenting.
(SIGHS)
How do you know it's safe?
Of course it's safe. I've been
up there a hundred times.
Don't treat me like
I'm a child. Someone died!
- It was an accident.
- Someone got sucked out!
It was an accident.
See, that's what I'm going
up there to fix, okay?
You don't have to worry.
Hey, think of it like
I'm going
on a vacation
for a week or two.
To a place 250 miles
straight up
and negative 450 degrees?
Some holiday.
Yeah, you got a point.
- (JAKE SIGHS)
- Why'd Uncle Max fire you?
Unbelievable!
Did you do something wrong?
No, look,
your Uncle Max and me...
It's not just about
the one job.
You know, sometimes,
younger brothers resent
being younger.
So they get bossy. They think
they know everything.
They tell you how to act,
how to talk
and after a couple decades,
you just get tired
of listening to it.
Maybe you should listen.
- (HORN HONKS)
- (HANNAH SIGHS)
My lift is here.
- Gotta go.
- What?
Wait, I thought I was
taking you to the airport.
You really
wanna see Mom? Great!
We can all fly home
to Atlanta together.
Got it covered.
Quit acting like you're mad.
Hannah, what do you want
from me?
I want you to
come back alive.
(TEARFULLY) And you're not
exactly the reliable type.
Hey.
(SOBBING)
I know I haven't always
kept good on my promises,
but I'm coming back.
- I...
- Promise.
- I promise.
- (EXHALES DEEPLY)
Come here.
I'll be back soon, okay?
MALE NASA ANNOUNCER: OV-104
is now at T-minus one hour
and ready for boarding.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
We're at T-minus one minute
and counting.
Have a safe trip, sir.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Booster
rocket separation confirmed.
Hate to interrupt, Major Tom,
but in a few seconds,
you should be able
to see the net.
How's it feel to be back home?
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENTS
OVER SPEAKERS)
Look at you, girl.
Livin' and breathin'.
- Mr. Lawson.
- Hey.
Ute Fassbinder.
Nice to meet you.
JAKE: Yeah, I remember you.
Yeah, you were
the German scientist.
You were here when I was here.
Thermospherics, right?
UTE: Yeah.
The containment shell needs
a fresh coat of sealant
where the APT ducts push
through the channel housing.
Not good. That's wrong.
And you hear that?
- I'm sorry.
- Shh. Listen.
That wobbly hum?
That's a bad
step-down transformer.
All these things, they have
to be watched, cared for.
Mr. Lawson.
No, I know, I know.
It's not your fault,
but when I left, everything
here was perfect.
So, maybe I need to speak
to your Chief Scientist
about the fine art
of giving a shit.
I'm the Chief Scientist. I've
been promoted a year ago.
Right, congratulations.
One of our crew died
this week, Mr. Lawson.
Sorry about the transformer.
Let me introduce you
to your team.
Oh, of course, an American.
Actually, my brother and I
were born in the UK,
but thank you.
Yeah, but you've got the old
Stars and Stripes
on your arm there
and a cowboy look in your eye.
(CHUCKLES)
- (SHUSHES)
- Oh, no offense.
This is just
a serious situation
and the last thing
we need is some
Washington stooge
to come and supervise us.
Do we, lads?
Well, you got one,
so how about we start
with names and positions?
UTE: Mmm-hmm.
Adisa, structural.
Duncan Taylor,
systems and OS analyst
and loyal British subject.
Hernandez, robotics.
Dussette.
Satcom and security.
And you are?
This is Mr. Jake Lawson.
You're Jake Lawson?
The Jake Lawson?
You look much older
than I would've thought.
(STAMMERS)
I mean, you look good,
but your physical
appearance is not...
Does not match
the amount of time
that has elapsed in your life.
Am I getting fired?
(SIGHS) Okay, we don't have
a lot of time.
So we have three
situations to examine.
Afghanistan, the scientist
that died here,
and the new incident
in Hong Kong.
Hong Kong? No, that was
a gas main explosion.
We all watched that
on the telly.
All right, okay. You just
keep believing that.
I, on the other hand,
have a mystery
that I'd like to solve
and prevent more deaths,
so feel free to join me.
Or not.
MAX: All right,
quick question.
Okay, active shooter,
the president and I are both
in the line of fire.
Who do you save first? Me...
The president.
Oh, come on.
You could take a second
just to think about that.
Sorry, baby.
Job comes first,
same with you.
No, that's not true.
No, I have priorities
and you...
(CHUCKLING)
You are my priority.
Come on, let's do it.
I kinda want to,
but, um,
you just keep talking.
I mean, why do we always
have to be sneaking around?
Hmm? Come on, let's do it.
Let's get married.
We can't.
- (SIGHS)
- It's against the rules.
One day, baby.
(PHONE RINGING)
- Mmm. You're gonna get that.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
Because your job comes first.
No...
I'm gonna get it 'cause
I don't want it to interfere
with this.
See?
Now I might just not save you.
Yeah, hello?
Max, it's Cheng.
Cheng, God, tell me
you're not in Hong Kong.
- Cheng?
- CHENG: Last night,
I was right
in the middle of it.
It was horrible.
That's why I'm calling.
Phone service
just came back on.
Yeah, well,
you're lucky to be alive.
MAX: I mean, those gas pipes?
I'm not so sure
that was the cause.
What do you mean?
I don't follow.
(PHONE BEEPS)
CHENG: It was abnormally hot
before the pipes blew.
The satellite sensor should've
recorded it, right?
I've checked over
a dozen times but I can't
get access to Dutch Boy's
Hong Kong satellite.
My access has been blocked.
Check your HoloFrame.
MAX: I don't understand.
We both have clearance.
CHENG: Exactly.
And the only people that have
the authority to block it
are in the building
you work in.
Wait. What do you mean?
If someone is covering up
a system defect,
there's potential for critical
failure on a global scale.
If Dutch Boy
has a catastrophic failure,
it can create something
far worse
than the very thing
we're trying to prevent,
what we call a geostorm.
(STAMMERS) What? Slow down,
Cheng, all right? A what?
A geostorm.
Simultaneous catastrophic
weather events
triggered all over the globe.
Once they pass
a minimum threshold,
the storms will start
causing new storms
like a chain reaction,
until they merge together.
It's gotta be a glitch.
I'll give you a call
when I know something.
All right. Thanks.
MALE REPORTER:
These pipes had not been
well maintained
or upgraded in years.
MAX: Cheng thinks Hong Kong
has something to do
with Dutch Boy.
You know, he's implying
some kind of cover-up.
I just got a text
and POTUS called
a last-minute press briefing.
(SIGHS) What, you can't stay?
Oh, when duty calls,
duty calls.
"Neither rain nor snow
nor gloom of night," right?
Honey, that's
the Postal Service.
We're the Secret Service.
(WHISPERS) Secret Service.
(WHISPERS) Oh,
there's a difference? Really?
I didn't know that.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(MAN SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
RICO: Grab his laptop.
Let's go.
So the satellite
that went rogue
over Afghanistan,
what type was that?
That's my fave, actually.
I call it a "rock 'n' roller."
JAKE: Oh, the SR-22.
Uses sonic waves to slow
molecular movement
causing cooling,
but, in that case,
freezing. Why?
HERNANDEZ: We don't know.
We checked the satellite's
hard drives,
but the logs were wiped clean
by the malfunction.
All right. Let's pull up
every "rock 'n' roller"
satellite we have
to see if we can find
any corruption in their logs.
Pull up every "rock 'n'
roller" in the net.
There's gotta be more than
a thousand of them.
Uh, 1,270, to be exact.
And we're gonna scan
each and every one of 'em.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Dana. Hey.
- Hey. What are you doing here?
- (SCOFFS)
What do you mean,
"What am I doing here"?
I work here. I'm your boss.
Yeah, but what are you doing
down from Mount Olympus
and visiting me
in Millennial Village?
Well, I have a bit of
a favor to ask you.
You're the best
at what you do.
(WHISPERS) But I need you
to keep this between us.
Okay.
I have a problem
with my HoloFrame.
Do I look like
a Genius Bar to you?
I'm sorry. I'm sitting here
defending the free world
against state operators
and cyberterrorists
but Grandpa needs help
fixing his phone.
No, but I have a problem
trying to get through
to satellite G-22
over Hong Kong.
So a satellite has a bad comm.
That happens.
No. No, not a satellite.
All of them.
Oh.
I am mildly intrigued. Stay.
MAX: Mmm-hmm.
DANA: (SIGHS) Okay.
It looks like
vanilla line disruption,
bad server relay,
or trunk failure,
or something.
Are you still dating
that Secret Service chick?
What? No.
No, I'm not dating anyone.
Mmm-hmm.
DANA: Wait, look. Oh, my God.
Someone wanted to
block your access
without you knowing
that it was intentional.
But this...
This is very intentional,
and it's very clever.
And I know
what you're gonna say.
You're gonna say,
"Tell no one." And I won't.
But I didn't sign up
to work here
so I could
cubicle-squat 24/7.
So whatever is going on,
I want in on the action.
Well, let's hope
there isn't any action.
(WHISPERS) And yeah,
tell no one.
MICKEY: Miss Fassbinder,
we've just been given
a priority
communication request.
From Climate Command?
The White House.
All right.
So who are the yahoos
in Washington we gotta
deal with on this?
I guess I would be
the head yahoo.
Hello, guys.
Max tells me you don't have
a high opinion of politicians.
I didn't say that.
Well, neither do I.
We went through hell
getting the world on board
for this program.
We've come too far
for it to fail.
You and I both understand
why we cannot let that happen.
Yes, sir.
So if I find anything, I'll
report to you right away.
Actually, you'll be
reporting to Max here.
Good luck.
Have at it.
Thank you, sir.
I'll leave you two alone.
And if you need me,
I'm in my office.
JAKE: Thank you.
- I'll be reporting to you?
- (DOOR CLOSES)
You lied to me.
Again.
No, I just didn't answer
your ridiculous demand.
How do I switch
this thing off?
There's something
you need to know.
We've been having issues
down here
accessing the Dutch Boy
satcom.
We have reason
to believe that it...
(SIGHS) Well, it may not
be accidental.
Might not be accidental?
Oh, well, I've been
trying to access
the Hong Kong satellite.
I knew it. I knew it!
You think it's possible?
Yeah. It's possible.
But even if you could access
the Hong Kong
satellite remotely,
you're not gonna get
the logs you need.
No. We gotta pull
that information
from the actual satellite
up here.
Okay. I can authorize that.
I don't need your
authorization for anything.
I'm sure that's really
scary for you,
but how about
you just count on me
to do my job,
and say thank you?
Oh, count on you.
Remember the first time
I had to bail you out?
Oh, God. Jesus Christ!
Yeah, it was just one week
after Mom and Dad died.
You got arrested
for fighting, hmm?
That's when I realized
that despite everything
I was going through,
I was gonna have to be
responsible for you.
All right, you know what?
Fine. It is what it is.
I guess I got no choice
but to count on you.
But if you ever authorize
anything without my approval,
you'll be on the next
shuttle home.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Transmission ended.
WOMAN: Hong Kong satellite 022
inbound for examination.
JAKE: All right. (GRUNTS)
Let's take this thing apart
and find out
what happened in Hong Kong.
Bring it down.
It should have
come down by now.
(REMOTE WHIRRING)
- (CLANKS)
- UTE: What is that?
I have no idea.
(CLANKING)
- All right, shut it down.
- It's not responding.
DUNCAN: Jesus, Hernandez!
Get down!
(GRUNTING)
Get out of here! Go!
Somebody, open this door, now!
Watch out!
Shit!
(METAL CLANKING)
(ALARM BLARES)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
JAKE: All right,
let's pick up
every single piece
of this thing
and get it down
to manufacturing.
(JAKE SIGHS)
JAKE: Do you think
we can retrieve the logs
from the hard drives?
DUNCAN: Well, the accident
created an electrical short
and fried all the drives.
I mean, look at it.
It's toast.
JAKE: So we've lost
all the drives
with possible corruption?
Not all of them.
UTE: What do you mean?
I was reviewing your video
of the accident
that killed Makmoud.
Each of the panels that blew
has a drive inside.
(MAKMOUD SCREAMING)
And one of them got stuck
in the communication tower.
It looks like the seal locks
are still intact.
If we're lucky, the corrupted
drive will still be inside.
We gotta get that panel back.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yeah, hello?
I just got into DC.
We have to meet.
I figured it all out.
Meet me at 10:00 at the place
across the square
where we used to have lunch.
Back in college.
All right.
Yeah, I'll be there.
(PHONE BEEPS)
MAN: (ON SPEAKERS)
Ready to decompress.
All right. Door's open, kids.
You're clear to exit.
UTE: Step across the gravity
threshold and follow me.
Let's just get the panel,
see what's on those drives.
(EXHALES) Okay.
UTE: There's the panel.
JAKE: Wait. Hold up.
We designed the tower
to have emergency
de-rig ports,
so the bars
can be moved easily.
(GRUNTS)
UTE: Control,
the panel is secured.
WOMAN: Roger that.
Come back now, kids.
Come back.
UTE: We're on our way back.
(UTE GRUNTS)
UTE: Jake, what's happening?
JAKE: (GRUNTS) I don't know!
I don't know!
(JAKE GRUNTING)
UTE: Jake? Jake!
JAKE: I can't control
the damn suit!
What's going on?
WOMAN: His suit
is malfunctioning.
- Jake, do you read me?
- Duncan, tell him to cut it.
Jake, cut off the fuel intake.
JAKE: It's not responding!
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Hang on, Jake.
JAKE: I can't hold it.
(GROANING)
Eject the pack.
Eject the pack!
(GROANING)
Oh, Christ. We're gonna lose
him. We're gonna lose him!
(GRUNTING)
- (GASPING)
- (ALARMS BLARING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Are you all right?
Yeah.
You got the drive?
I grabbed it
when I freed the panel.
You smashed up a dozen
comm links, TCAS sensors...
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
I'm fine, thank you very much.
What happened out there?
Propulsion throttle locked up.
And you lost the door panel,
which means no drive codes.
Back to square one.
(SIGHS) Great.
Why didn't you tell them
about the drive?
Because someone just
tried to kill me.
I know my crew. I trust them.
You think you know them.
But someone doesn't want us
to see what's on this drive.
UTE: Jake, there's
no corruption here at all.
The doors weren't
accidentally blown off.
They were programmed to.
- This wasn't a malfunction.
- JAKE: No.
Someone intentionally
killed Makmoud.
No doubt the same person
that tampered
with the Hong Kong satellite.
The user logins
have been wiped clean.
We have
no digital fingerprints.
No. That's what they think.
Login records are synced back
to the mainframe.
UTE: Yeah,
but that's the problem.
If they're deleted
in one place,
they're deleted everywhere.
No, everywhere
they know about.
When we built Dutch Boy,
we put in
a locked-off library.
Something that would track
and archive everything.
Our saboteur's login info
is gonna be in there.
Nope.
- (BEEPS)
- UTE: You've been locked out.
JAKE: But by who?
The virtual conference room.
How many have access
to those transmissions?
Anyone with level three access
and above.
Dozens of people.
(DISTANT TRAFFIC SOUNDS)
SARAH: Max.
- Max.
- What?
Relax. He'll be here soon.
What, really? I seem nervous?
Just a little.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
He's here.
He's here?
(GRUNTS)
- (GROANS)
- (TIRES SCREECH)
- (SCREAMS) No! No!
- (PHONE BEEPS)
Cheng! My God! No!
This is Agent Wilson.
Yes, I need
an ambulance right now.
- Dupont Circle.
- CHENG: Max...
WOMAN: Agent Wilson, I have
dispatched the ambulance.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- (HORN HONKS)
- (GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
MAX: You got me. You got me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) I'm here.
Look at me. Look at me.
Zeus. Zeus.
What?
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Virtual conference initiating.
Max? You okay?
(PANTING) They said
it was urgent. What is it?
Yeah. Um...
I wanted to
(INHALES DEEPLY) apologize.
Apologize?
(PANTING)
If you had any idea what
I just walked away from...
You're gonna drag me up here
just to apologize?
(SIGHS) All right. Fine.
Uh, apology accepted.
Hey, Max, we don't walk out
on each other.
That's the unspoken code
between brothers.
You remember that day
Dad took us fishing?
Yeah, he dropped his
cell phone in Key Biscayne.
Proof the Lawsons
aren't fishermen.
(CHUCKLES) Four hours,
the three of us
didn't catch a thing.
I tried to sabotage Dad's reel
so we could leave.
That pin at the highest part
of the spool,
pulled it so the level
mechanism would pop out.
Of course,
Dad was a government spy
his whole life,
caught me red-handed.
"Trust me," he said.
"I get it.
No one likes to fail.
"But I'd rather not catch fish
with my family
"than catch 20 fish alone."
(SCOFFS)
I didn't even understand
what he meant back then.
But I do now.
Take care, Max.
End transmission.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Transmission ended.
What was all that?
That was the first
decent conversation
we've had in years.
- Hey.
- (GASPS) Oh, my God!
- (MUSIC PLAYING ON HEADPHONES)
- Would you relax?
What?
Do you have a moment?
Yes! I do. I got your message.
Jesus.
What happened?
Did Secret Service Barbie
dump you?
I need to show you something.
(CLICKS)
MAX: Take a look at this.
You remember that day
Dad took us fishing?
He dropped his cell phone
in Key Biscayne.
(SCOFFS)
Our dad never took us fishing.
Oh.
That's sad.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm not good at the, like,
"Talk about your daddy issues"
kind of friend thing.
I just...
What? No, no, no...
It's a code.
"He dropped his cell phone
in Key Biscayne."
His cell phone number
is the key.
Take a look at the digits.
Okay, you got
your first number,
that's your first word.
Second number, nine,
you move on nine words.
That's your second word.
Third number, nine again.
Another nine, you move on.
Then nine, then two,
then nine, then five,
and so on and so on
until you get
an entirely different message.
So, who came up with this
encryption, a 12-year-old?
No. I was 13.
Oh.
Okay. (SIGHS)
So, one-nine-nine-nine,
two-nine-five-five,
eight-seven-one and go.
Proof of sabotage
at the highest level
of government.
Trust no one.
Well, you said you were
looking for action.
(SIGHS) Yeah,
but I mean, holy shit.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
If you don't wanna take this
any further,
I totally understand.
Oh, no. I do, I do. I just...
I do and I don't.
Kinda like going
on a roller coaster
or eating Chipotle.
What's our next move?
Okay. I need you to find
anything you can
on a file named
"Project Zeus."
(CHUCKLES)
"Project Zeus"?
Yeah.
Okay. Looks like
we have ourselves
a bro-spiracy theory.
(SCOFFS) Just run
the damn search.
DANA: Um...
I am getting a hit. Um...
But it looks like
it's double encrypted.
It's a little OCD.
Can you break it?
Yeah, I could, but,
ah, I can't do it from here.
The file's under a White House
security network,
and it's just not hackable.
I'd have to log in,
and I don't have
- the credentials for it.
- Shit. Neither do I.
(STUTTERS)
I don't know anyone who does.
Yeah, you do.
(KEYS RATTLING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Max?
(CLATTERING)
Freeze.
- Oh! Holy shit!
- (CLATTERS)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Honey, relax!
Who is this girl in our house?
I can explain everything.
Mmm. That sounds really pervy.
- Shut up.
- Okay, I'm sorry. I will.
I broke one of your wine glasses.
(STAMMERS)
It just fell and I promise
I'm gonna reimburse you.
I have the money. I'm sorry.
Talk.
This is Dana.
She works with me in State.
Now, I asked her here
because I need her help
and, uh, as it turns out,
I need your help, too.
(WHISPERS) She's hot!
(SIGHS)
MAX: I know how much
your job means to you.
I took an oath, Max.
We have rules.
Technically, you're not
supposed to be
- sleeping together either...
- Dana.
You're asking me
to commit a crime.
You're soliciting
a Secret Service agent
to break into
the White House server
and illegally obtain files.
And you thought
I would say yes!
I still think
you're gonna say yes.
Why?
Because I'm the one
who's asking you.
And if I'm asking you,
well, then
it must be important.
And you know that it's bigger
than you and me.
"You and I."
BOTH: Shut up.
Please.
One time.
We need to play back
the security cameras
without alerting anyone.
Someone killed Makmoud.
We find out why,
we know who's behind this.
But you can't access
the cameras
without it being logged in.
That's why we're going to
the back-up server room.
- You see?
- (BEEPING)
It comes in handy
that I built the place.
Yes, but I live here.
(BEEPING)
Show off.
Makmoud was prepping
diagnostics on the Afghan sat
while we launched
a replacement.
JAKE: Son of a bitch.
He pulled something off
the sat.
Poor bastard figured it out
and they killed him to
make sure no one else did.
UTE: There are no cameras
allowed in the locker rooms.
Then let's go
take a look for ourselves.
181.
What's the code?
Seven, six, three, six, three.
(BEEPING)
DUSSETTE: What do you think
you're doing?
(COCKS GUN)
You know what happened to me
out there wasn't an accident.
And whoever did that
killed Makmoud.
And what makes you think
it is not me?
Because if it was you,
I'd be dead already.
Dussette, lower your gun.
(GUN CLICKS)
Whatever you're looking for,
it is not in this locker.
I was here
when Makmoud came in.
He put his stuff
in an empty one.
Why didn't you tell me?
You watched the same
security footage as I did.
I was just waiting to see
who was gonna come
and look for Makmoud's stuff.
It's in here.
UTE:
Two, six, six, five, three.
- (BEEPING)
- (MUTTERS)
- (BEEPS)
- (LOCKER UNLOCKS)
Bingo.
This is everything he copied
off the satellite
onto his HoloFrame.
JAKE: That's a virus.
That wasn't generated
by the satellite's
onboard computer.
Because they were planted.
Makmoud found the virus
and got killed
before he could tell anyone.
DANA: Oh, I got it.
All right, here we go.
(TYPING)
Project Zeus.
There are tens of thousands of
storm simulations in here
and each one is starting
in a different place.
MAX: They all end
the same way.
A geostorm.
I mean, unlike anything
we've ever seen.
Dana, can you show us
just, uh, the simulation
that begins in Afghanistan?
Yeah, sure.
(TYPING)
MAX: Okay, now filter those,
so that the second
malfunction's over Hong Kong.
Where are you going with this?
(SIGHS) What if Cheng realized
that someone was following
one of his scenarios?
You know, making it look like
a predicted pattern
of malfunction,
disguising a crime
like a series of accidents.
It might actually be
a series of accidents.
If it were,
they wouldn't have killed him.
Someone has weaponized
Dutch Boy.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Virtual conference initiating.
Hey. (PANTING)
JAKE: New face?
Yeah. A friend.
Uh, she's keeping things off
the monitor channels,
so we're good.
- So you got my message?
- Yeah, I got your message.
It's, uh,
worse than we thought.
Whoever's doing this is using
Dutch Boy to target cities.
Yeah, they're disguising their
moves as malfunctions.
They already killed the man
who found out about this
and I don't think
they're done.
Yeah.
This was my life's work, Max.
(SIGHS) You know,
they said it was impossible,
but we pulled it off.
And it worked
perfectly, without fail,
day after day,
year after year.
So what do people do with it?
Turn it into a gun.
I know.
I know. It's not too late.
We can fix this
before it happens again,
but I can't do it on my own.
I need you.
I need you to tell me,
how are they controlling
Dutch Boy?
I know
how they're controlling it.
MAX: How?
A virus.
Well, can you stop it?
JAKE: There's only one way.
We can shut down
Dutch Boy temporarily.
The reboot will flush out
the system,
kill the virus,
and revert back
to the fail-safe OS.
Okay. Let's do it.
I'm authorizing.
Yeah, I think
we've established that
I don't really wait for that.
This isn't a Chromebook.
You don't just put your finger
on the power button.
You need the kill codes.
And the only one who has those
is the president.
So let's just go
to the president
and tell him what we know.
No. You can't go to Palma.
We need way more proof
than I have.
We're talking about
shutting down Dutch Boy.
I mean, even for an hour,
that puts
the whole planet at risk.
No, I don't think
you understand.
Someone sealed off
the backdoor into the system.
A backdoor almost no one
knew existed.
But the president did.
No. Jake, come on. What?
Are you out of your mind?
Not saying it's him.
I'm saying, "What if?"
Who else has the resources
to pull this off?
Murder, cover-up, and a virus
that can only be stopped
with the codes in his pocket.
Why? Huh? Tell me, why?
Why would he do that?
We're two weeks away
from transferring Dutch Boy
to the rest of the world.
Two weeks away from losing
autonomous control.
Now, he talks a good game,
but he's never gonna
let it happen.
A series of disasters,
an international crew
to take the fall
and he'll have to cancel
the handoff.
And who would blame him?
All right. You stay on top
of your satellites.
Max. Hey, Max,
don't do anything stupid.
Let's go.
JAKE: They already tried
to kill me once.
Max!
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Transmission ended.
MAN: President Palma, a couple
questions, please, sir.
Thoughts before you head to
the national convention
in Orlando, sir?
Mr. President, do you care
to make a statement?
WOMAN: Mr. President, a moment
before you head to Orlando?
PRESIDENT: My friends
from Washington, D.C...
I could never get on a plane
without first saying hello
to you. It's impossible.
- (PANTING)
- What are you doing here?
- Are you insane?
- Sarah, look.
Jake needs us to steal
the kill codes from Palma.
Us?
You're asking me to help you
on the word
of your asshole brother,
who you haven't even spoken to
for three years.
Yeah. Think about it.
Afghanistan, Hong Kong,
Cheng, the crazy sim shit,
the death
on the space station. Come on.
Look, you gotta trust me
on this, all right?
I'm not kidding around here.
- Okay.
- Look.
The codes are
on Palma's HoloFrame.
We can't do it on the plane.
Why not?
Too many eyes.
He's never alone.
All right,
then what's the play?
Palma wants
some private time to shower
and make calls
before the after-parties.
You follow.
I'll get you inside.
I can steal the codes
while he's in the shower.
- That's the idea.
- Yes, it is.
(SIGHS)
- AUTOMATED VOICE: Warning.
- MAN: Out of the way.
AUTOMATED VOICE: All satellite
communication offline.
(ALARM BLARING)
All satellite
communication offline.
All crew report
to stations immediately.
Oh, my God.
We have nearly 200 satellites
reporting malfunctions,
most of them nearing critical.
Pull up the satellite
closest to critical overload.
MICKEY: We've lost all control
of the Tokyo satellite.
(ALL CLAMORING)
(GROANS)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
DEKKOM: Max.
Oh. (SIGHS)
I didn't know you were coming
to the convention.
Uh, yeah. You know,
my dad lives in Florida
so, uh, I promised I'd get him
into the convention.
We need every vote, right?
Yeah, well, bring him
to the green room.
We'll do a little photo op.
Oh, that's very kind
of you, sir. Thank you.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
We've got reports of extreme
weather anomalies building
over Brazil, Mexico,
Bucharest, and Belgrade.
There's over
a thousand storm warnings
issued around the world.
(ALL CLAMORING)
(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Rio de
Janeiro satellite critical.
Retrieval routine offline.
Chart a new course!
Get us close to the nearest
satellites going critical.
What are you trying to do?
We're gonna launch
the replacements.
As many as we can,
as fast as we can.
We have to retrieve the other
satellites first.
Or the replacements will crash
into them.
They're programmed to arrive
in the exact same destination.
And they'll knock out
the infected satellites.
- Yeah.
- Of course!
MAN: (ON SPEAKERS)
All crews report to stations
for Rio satellite replacement.
(ALARM BLARING)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Go for launch.
Away she goes.
MAN: Satellite replacement
for Rio on its way.
- (CROWD SCREAMING)
- (PANTING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Warning.
Satellite on collision course.
Disable the retro-boosters.
Don't let it slow down.
(PANTING)
(GASPING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Load 'em up
and keep 'em coming!
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Warning. Geostorm alert.
(ALARM BLARING)
Time to geostorm,
one hour, thirty minutes.
CROWD: Four more years!
Four more years!
Thank you. As you know,
the environment
was my late wife's
great passion and purpose.
And I know that she would be
extremely proud...
REPORTER: (ON TV) Caused by
the worst hailstorm
in recorded history.
There has been another
extreme weather event,
this time in Rio de Janeiro.
An offshore cold front moved
rapidly across land,
plunging the city into
dangerously low temperatures.
There are reports
of numerous casualties,
but we don't know
how many at this time.
We're also hearing
that a cargo plane
may have crashed
in the city itself,
possibly related
to the freezing cold.
Tokyo and now Rio
are the first catastrophic
weather events
since the launch of Dutch Boy.
Stay tuned after the break,
when we'll be joined
by our reporter Sally Jones.
MAX: Oh, God.
DEKKOM: Hey, Max!
- Where's your daddy?
- Oh. (CHUCKLES)
You know what?
He got so caught up
in all the excitement.
I recruited you
for this position.
I know everything about you.
Your brother,
and your mother's death,
your father's death,
everything.
Why'd you lie to me? Hmm?
Why'd you insist
on making this trip?
Tell me what's wrong.
Maybe I can help you,
maybe I can't.
All right, look.
I gotta tell you something.
Come here.
(PANTING)
We are 90 minutes away
from a global storm
we won't recover from.
And I need
the president's kill codes.
(CHUCKLES)
Come again?
We gotta shut
Dutch Boy down, now.
You're serious.
You say you hired me
because you believe
in me, right?
All right, well, I need you
to believe in me now.
Well, we've gotta brief the president.
Get to Cape Canaveral.
No, no, no.
We can't do that, sir.
Why not?
I believe he's the one
who initiated it.
United we stand.
United we can.
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Four more years!
You better be
goddamn sure of yourself,
making accusations like that.
With all due respect, we don't
have time to argue about this.
Palma and I go way back.
Why would he do that?
That's insane.
Yeah, well, he's doing it.
What's your proof?
Yeah, I got proof.
Dozens of files, all right?
In Project Zeus.
It's all there.
Well, we can't get the
kill codes from the president.
Why not?
Because the president
is the kill codes.
Biometrics. Ten fingerprints,
two retina scans.
Well, what do we do?
I'll have to reason with him.
We'll have to reason with him.
MICKEY: Satellites are
going critical over Florida.
JAKE:
Load a replacement sat, now.
(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Station self-destruct
sequence initiated.
Phase one commencing now.
Okay. Shut that down!
MICKEY: I can't.
I'm locked out.
We built in
backdoor overrides.
Yeah, I'm trying them.
If we lose the station,
we won't be able
to control the satellites.
Self-destruct?
Why would you build that
into the station?
In case it fell to Earth.
Where's Duncan?
He's the only one with
enough programming expertise
to override the commands.
Duncan.
- (EXPLOSION)
- (RUMBLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
That's the fuel tanks.
They're the first to go.
Then section by section
until command and retrieval.
Okay, everybody,
get to the shuttles!
Evacuate!
Come on, we gotta hurry!
Go, go, go!
Jake, what are you
still doing here?
(GROANS)
That felt good.
Been wanting to do that
since I first met you.
Have you gone mad?
- Yeah, pretty much.
- (GROANS)
The virus.
You're the only one that could
have put it in the system.
You're the only one
who could've sealed off
the backdoor.
The only one that could've
helped to pull this off.
I need the overrides
for the self-destruct
to the station, now!
DUNCAN: I mean, what for?
I'm not gonna be here
when it blows.
But you will.
Come on, man. Why'd you do it?
Well, you know what us
lowly scientists get paid?
Take that times a thousand.
What difference is it
gonna make?
If you don't stop, there's not
gonna be a planet
to spend it on.
Please. We're gonna keep
all the best bits.
Aren't you
a little bit curious
to watch the world burn?
No. 'Cause millions of people
are gonna die.
And one of them's my daughter.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(BOTH STRAINING)
(GLASS CRACKING)
Oh, shit.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Holding room for the president
down on the left.
We'll confront him there.
Project Zeus.
Did Cheng tell you
anything else?
Cheng?
(DOOR BEEPS)
MILLER: (ON SCREEN)
But this president knows
that hope is not a plan.
This president knows
that despite
how far we've come,
there is much more work ahead.
Working to save our planet
is my first priority
- as vice president.
- (APPLAUSE)
This is but a stepping stone
to the success
and greatness
that can and will be
the future of our society.
Excuse me.
MILLER:
That's why I'm here tonight
with the Speaker of the House,
the Senate pro tempore,
and President Palma's
whole cabinet.
We all stand united
in support...
Palma doesn't leave
the building.
- Yes, sir.
- Let's go.
Where have you been?
Come here.
It's not the president,
all right? It's Dekkom.
Dekkom? How do you know?
Because he just tried
to kill me. That's how I know.
Look, the sim shows Orlando
is the next city to be hit.
Here? Why would he do that?
Because Dekkom wants Palma
trapped here, all right?
And everyone else who's next
in line for the presidency.
Are we still
stealing the codes?
The president is
the kill codes,
all right?
They're biometric.
If Palma dies,
Dutch Boy can't be stopped.
Sure, kidnap the president.
That sounds like
the reasonable move.
Yeah, well it's the only move
we've got.
Unless you wanna steal
his fingers and his eyes.
Huh?
We go now.
You get us a car.
I'll get us a president.
All right, good.
MILLER:
The program did not gain
the immense international
support that it...
Gunman spotted.
POTUS is compromised.
Evac to secure location Alpha.
AGENT: Get him out,
get him out!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
AGENT: Go, go, go.
(RUMBLING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Secret Service!
Get back! Get back!
You got a twenty
on the shooters?
Front mezzanine by
exit two-one-two!
Two men with automatics!
- I'm on it! You get POTUS!
- You two,
secure this entrance! No one
comes down this hallway!
Nobody gets through!
Hard room, Lammy.
- Got it!
- SARAH: You two,
clear the emergency exit now!
(GRUNTS)
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
You need to come with me.
SECURITY GUARD:
This exit is off limits!
WOMAN: (ON PA)
Please remain calm.
SARAH: Seriously?
A self-driving cab?
Dana jacked it remotely.
It was all I could get.
What the hell's
going on here, Lawson?
Please, sir.
Look, I'll explain
everything in the car.
Please, sir!
We don't have much time!
(GUNSHOTS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Keep moving!
Get to the shuttles!
(CLAMORING)
Keep going!
Quick!
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Time to geostorm, 55 minutes.
(WHIRRING)
(PANICKED SCREAMING)
Sir, I can barely hear you.
The storm is causing
too much static.
DEKKOM:
The Secret Service will be
homing in on the beacon
on the president's HoloFrame.
You have got to get to him
before they do.
Under no circumstances
can he make it out of Orlando.
Our man on the space station
did his job.
- Now you do yours.
- Copy that. Got it.
Dekkom?
MAX: It's the perfect
weapon, sir.
All right, Dekkom is trying to
change the map of the world.
And what?
Blame it on a computer glitch?
Yeah, well,
that and a dead president.
He'll take office
after wiping out everyone
in the line of succession.
(THUNDERCLAP)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
PRESIDENT: Dear God.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Get to cover!
Under the bridge.
Sir.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- (BARKING)
- (BOY SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(PHONE CAMERA CLICKS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
You are implicating the
Secretary of State in this.
Do you realize
you're committing...
Treason. Oh, yeah.
I kidnapped the president.
I've stolen state secrets.
Anything I'm forgetting,
honey?
Honey?
Guilty.
It took years
for Dekkom to plan this, sir.
A president's schedule
always changes last minute.
This is the one day and date
he could be sure
wouldn't move.
Having my brother and I lead
the investigation
was a setup from the start.
Think about it.
He hired us to fail.
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- Get down!
(METAL CREAKING)
All right, it's saying
we're back in the clear,
where the four meets the 91!
Just gotta take care
of a little problem first.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hold on!
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- MAX: No!
Marry her.
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(GROANING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
WOMAN: No. We're fine here.
REPORTER: (ON TV)
A lightning storm in Orlando
has caused a horrific
explosion at the DNC.
There is no official word
on the whereabouts
of the president...
I don't know. I don't know.
I just can't
get in touch with Jake.
REPORTER: And we have reports
now of explosions
on the space station.
Honey, the Orlando storm
is getting really close
to your dad's place.
I can't get through to him.
Has he texted you?
He's not there.
He's there.
REPORTER: ...of a major issue
on the space station.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Attention all crews.
Now loading final shuttle.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Please board your designated
evacuation shuttles
immediately.
Shuttle launch
sequence initiated.
Jake.
- I'm not coming.
- What?
When my brother
gets those kill codes,
someone has to be here
to execute the program.
No. We need to go.
We haven't heard
from him in hours.
I trust him.
You know the reboot
has to be done manually.
Then I stay.
I'm the commander.
No.
I'm the only one my brother
will trust with the codes,
so I need your HoloFrame.
You have to insert it manually
at the core of the mainframe.
You can find it, yes?
- Yes.
- Good.
Goodbye, Ute.
Auf Wiedersehen, Jake.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
DEKKOM: Pull over here.
The president's beacon
shows him
heading right towards us.
DIXON: You really wanna
drive back into that?
Yeah, right after it passes,
I'll be the sole survivor,
ready to be sworn in as
the next President
of the United States.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Here they come.
Fire.
(GRUNTS)
You thought the president was
the only one
who could be tracked?
- How in hell did you...
- PRESIDENT: How?
Because I'm the goddamn
President of the
United States of America.
You're done, Leonard.
(SIRENS WAILING)
He's all yours.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Wait, wait! Wait a minute.
I've given you an opportunity,
Mr. President.
You should take it.
An opportunity? Let him go!
It's genocide, Leonard!
You say genocide,
I say preemptive strike.
You've lost your mind!
Tomorrow the sun will rise.
All our enemies will be gone.
Wiped away
as if by the hand of God.
Why would you do this?
Because no one else would.
I'm turning the clock
back to 1945,
when America
was a shining city on a hill,
not just a bank
disguised as a country.
By playing God?
What the hell is Dutch Boy
if not playing God?
Ask Max. He knows.
Science is all about
playing God.
Sometimes God
doesn't play so nice.
Yeah, well, you know what
my brother would say?
What?
Get him outta here!
PRESIDENT: Let's go, Lawson!
That's my fiancé.
(LOW RUMBLING)
(URGING HORSE)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
MAN: Get the president
to cover! Hurry!
(ALARM BLARING)
Mr. President.
We got the kill codes.
You'll have to hurry. The
station is in full shutdown.
What about the crew?
Safe.
But Jake decided to stay.
To reboot the satellites.
Your brother
is waiting for you.
Come on.
(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Virtual conference initiating.
Hey.
MAX: Jake.
Jake, it was Dekkom.
Well, I did say
I might be wrong.
Mr. President.
- How's Hannah?
- Oh, she's good. She's safe.
Atlanta wasn't hit.
Thank God.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Identity verified.
Shutdown protocol
transfer initiating.
It's gonna take
60 seconds to upload.
How long till
the self-destruct?
Eight minutes,
give or take.
Mr. Lawson,
we thank you
for your sacrifice.
Wait. What the hell's
going on?
You've done your part, Max.
Jake, what is going on?
Now it's time for me
to do mine.
No, no, no.
The kill codes don't stop
the self-destruct, do they?
Do they?
No, only the geostorm.
The station self-destruct
can't be reversed.
Come on, come on.
There must be a way, huh?
Come on. It's all my fault.
I'm the one
who put you up there!
Hey, it's okay.
I wanted to go.
It was my choice.
God knows
I haven't always made
the right ones.
You know, you were right,
little brother.
I was supposed
to look after you.
But you looked after me.
Can you forgive me?
Yeah, always.
Look after my little girl.
Stay in her life.
I will.
We should've done this
a long time ago, huh?
Yeah.
You're a good man, Jake.
I'll see you, kiddo.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Transfer complete.
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Time to geostorm,
5 minutes, 51 seconds.
(ALARM BLARING)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Warning.
Core rotation has terminated.
REPORTER: (ON TV) We don't
know what's happening up there.
We just know
the station has suffered
a devastating accident
of some kind.
We're being told now
it is beyond repair
or salvation.
Honey.
He's coming back.
He promised me.
We will keep you updated
with any new developments.
- (ALARM BLARING)
- (PANTING)
(PANICKED CLAMORING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Self-destruct
entering phase four.
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPING)
Code invalid.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
UTE: Need a hand?
Wrong door.
(BEEPS)
What're you doing here?
I told you. I live here.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Time to geostorm,
1 minute, 40 seconds.
(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Uploading kill codes.
(CAR ALARMS SOUNDING)
(RUMBLING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Satellite shutdown in process.
JAKE: When the last satellite
cycles down, let me know.
I'll manually reboot
the entire system.
That should
flush out the virus.
UTE: Okay.
(YELLING INDISTINCTLY)
(RUMBLING)
Five to go.
Three.
- Come on, baby.
- Two.
And one.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Manual reboot activated.
(POWER SHUTTING DOWN)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL CHEERING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Status: rebooting.
UTE: The net is back up.
The virus is gone.
Transferring control
of the net back to NASA.
(EXCITED CONVERSATIONS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
Jake!
I've got you!
AUTOMATED VOICE: Warning.
Self-destruct
entering final stage.
Best seat in the house.
Ute,
do you believe in a Hail Mary?
Follow me. We gotta get
to the satellite.
(GRUNTS)
JAKE: I've got you.
We've gotta get away
as far as we can
before the final detonation.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Dock releasing.
(STATIC BLARING)
REPORTER: (ON TV)
And it appears
we have lost
the space station.
A tragic ending for
the two heroes still aboard.
(BEEPING)
Hey, Max, take a look.
I'm picking up exhaust flares
and they're pulsing
in a Mayday pattern.
See if we can turn
one of the shuttles around.
JAKE: Hopefully,
someone sees this.
Fingers crossed.
(SIGHS)
(RUMBLING)
(WHIRRING)
(LAUGHS)
Hernandez, you son of a bitch!
Thank the Mexican.
(LAUGHS)
(ALL CHEERING)
Yes! Come here. Yes!
(EXCLAIMS IN TRIUMPH)
(SHOUTING)
(DOG BARKING)
(BOY SPEAKING HINDI)
REPORTER: (ON TV)
A miracle indeed.
The shuttle you see
is bringing home
all the ISS crew members
who remained on the station.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
- (ALL CHEERING)
- (SIRENS WAILING)
Hi, Jake.
I'm Sarah, Max's fiancée.
Oh, welcome to the family.
Well done, well done,
both of you.
Sorry I doubted you,
Mr. President.
Yeah, well,
you were wrong, Jake, again.
Well, how many times
do I have to tell you?
Never listen to me.
(LAUGHS)
God, it's good
to have you back, man.
Good to be back.
MAX: It's a nice place
you got here, Jake.
JAKE: Thank you.
So when you heading back up?
- (SIGHS) In a week.
- Yeah?
Yeah, a lot of work left.
But I'll be back.
I know.
(DUCKS QUACKING)
This sucks.
Yeah, seriously,
this is so boring.
You know what? I can't do this
for another second.
Now, why'd you make us do this
in the first place?
I don't know. I was trying
to relive a moment.
MAX: A moment? What moment?
We never went fishing
with Dad.
You made that whole story up.
JAKE: Yeah, but that was
a good story, though, huh?
I mean,
you gotta give me that.
I mean, it had a moral
and everything.
MAX: (LAUGHS) Moral?
What moral?
HANNAH:
You can't undo the past.
All you can do
is face what's ahead.
NASA maintained the satellites
while we rebuilt
the space station.
We made it safer,
made it stronger.
It belongs to all of us now.
One planet, one people.
And as long as we remember
that we share one future,
we will survive.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
Resync by GoldenBeard