Blacktip on the line.
She's a fighter, ek se.
That's what I like
to hear, brah.
Come, bru. Come my bru, help.
Help me, my bru.
Come on...
Yes.
Come on.
- Come on.
- Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Ah, get the hook.
There it is. Get the hook.
I'm holding there.
The hook.
- Ha, ha. 'Kay.
- I'm holding.
Come on, get that fin, my bru.
Get it!
Yes, yes.
Away!
- Away!
- Ha-ha-ha!
- Wow!
- Woo!
All right.
Woo!
- Yeah...
- Woo!
You're a killer, my bru.
Ha!
Come take a selfie.
- Take a selfie.
- Woo. Woo!
Happy.
Attention all mariners.
Any vessel in or around
zone one-seven-nine.
I say again, zone
one-seven-nine.
You are advised to
leave the area.
What's this bullshit, eh?
If you can see orange
smoke on your horizon,
you are in danger. I say again,
if you can see orange smoke,
you are in immediate danger.
Depart for coastal
waters at once.
Um...
Ah, Ru...?
Think we should pull
the lines, my bru?
Are you crazy? Kwame...
they're really
biting today, brah.
I don't wanna go to jail, man.
Besides...
I'm pretty kussed from
that last fight, man.
Don't be a pussy.
Radio didn't say nothing
about the coast guard.
All we know, it's some...
longliner out here, greedy.
We... me and you...
we're going nowhere.
We're gonna fish now, my friend.
Let's fish.
What was that?
- Hey, come, come. You all right?
- Fuck.
That's a big one, ek se.
And that's why we're
out here, baby.
That's solid gold!
Look...
Are you seeing this?
Have you seen sharks
swim like that?
What are they doing?
They're serving themselves up on a platter.
That's what.
Kwame!
Fuck.
Hello?
I can't believe he
didn't eat you.
Well, luckily I wouldn't
taste very good to him.
You know the idea that
great whites are these
malicious killing machines
roving the shorelines
looking for some
swimmer to chomp on
is just pure fiction
perpetuated by Hollywood.
I mean, these magnificent and
unfairly represented creatures
are simply looking for fish.
Or a nice, fat seal to eat.
You know, any time there
is a human attack,
it's just a case of
mistaken identity.
Sharks are an extremely
important part
of our ocean's ecosystem.
And, sadly, they
are being killed
at an average rate of
100 million per year.
For a purpose as frivolous
as a bowl of fin soup.
That is why the institute
my mother founded,
Five Oceans Institute, is fully
dedicated to shark research
and to educating the public
on how important it is
to protect the species.
Yeah.
Your video shows you swimming
with a wide variety of sharks.
Is there any type of shark
you wouldn't swim with?
Bull sharks.
They're the most lethal
of all the shark species.
They tend to blast their
prey with the thick part
of their skull to disable them,
and then, uh, clamp
down like a pit bull.
And their bite is 10 times
that of a great white, so,
yeah, they're quite
intimidating to swim with.
Aaron, you on comms?
Roger, Trent. I got eyes on you.
Open fence section 5F.
You come back with an expression
like that on your face,
I know there's a
story behind it.
Yeah, not one I wanna spread.
We had a jail break today.
How many?
All five.
That's five too many, man.
Yeah, no shit.
I gotta check the
perimeter fence.
Those fish can't get out again.
Lastly, I'd like to thank
you for having me.
Thank you.
Dr. Calhoun.
Yes?
Misty, my name is Craig Burns.
Hi, what can I do for you?
Durant Pharmaceuticals.
I'm not a pharma doc.
What am I missing?
My client, Mr. Durant,
is a fan of your work.
He considers you the
most astute expert
in shark behavior in the world.
He'd like you to consult
on a new project of his.
A conservation project?
He prefers to call it the
preservation of man.
So you continued
your mother's work?
She was the one that taught
you to love the ocean?
She taught me to respect it.
You're not filling in all
the blanks, Mr. Burns.
Why is a pharma company
interested in working with me?
Mr. Durant would love the chance
to answer your questions.
When?
Tomorrow.
Fifty thousand dollars?
- For what?
- To share your expertise.
That's yours, Dr. Calhoun,
whether you decide
to work with us or not.
Call it a down payment.
But should you choose
to come on board,
Mr. Durant is prepared
to fully fund
your work at the Five Oceans
for the next five years.
And from what I've
read recently,
your institute could
use the money.
Something about a grant
withdrawal, if I recall?
Aren't you even a little curious
about what we're doing?
Aaron.
What's the most
important rule here?
Don't piss into the wind and
don't pull on Superman's cape.
Yeah. No, no,
that's-that's the second
most important rule, of course.
The first most important rule is
always keep the fences green.
Which they are, dude.
They were green this morning,
they'll be green tonight.
I don't sleep on my job.
Then how do you explain
five sharks going for
a goddamn joy swim?
Hey, man, look, that's...
That's not possible.
I swear, look.
You see?
System's working perfectly,
just like I programmed.
Yeah, and I'm telling you,
those sharks were out
in the open ocean.
I don't get... Jesus!
You see?
They avoid that electrical
field like the plague.
Wait a minute.
What the hell?
What is that?
A tunnel?
That's a tunnel under the cable!
Sharks can't do that.
Can they?
We gotta extend the
fence's range.
It'll take us a week to get
more cable down from Cape Town.
We don't have that much time.
Should I notify the boss?
No. No, not yet.
I got an idea.
You have gotta be kidding me.
Misty.
This is Daniel and Leslie Kim.
Daniel is a neurophysiologist.
Leslie is a neurobiologist.
Leslie, Daniel, meet Dr.
Misty Calhoun.
Misty is a marine
conservationist
who has singlehandedly
removed three shark species
- from the endangered list.
- Wow.
So a neurophysiologist,
a neurobiologist,
and a shark conservationist
enter a bar.
What's the punchline?
No punchline, just an
international murderer's row
of brilliant minds.
If you'll excuse me, I need
to talk to the captain.
We should arrive at the
complex by 1500 hours.
Did you guys sign this NDA?
I got a headache just
trying to get through it.
Oh, good, so it's not just me.
It's some lawyer trying
to justify his job.
But you did sign it?
Oh, yeah, we've been waiting
for this opportunity.
You act like we already
know it's great.
It's a big if, Daniel.
But it's Carl Durant.
I mean, the guy's made of
money, and he gets things done.
And after this weekend,
funding won't be something
we need to worry about anymore.
Yeah, he is throwing
his money around.
We're newlyweds, so
don't mind the PDA.
Sorry.
It is crazy to pack
an overnight bag,
and head out to sea not
knowing what we're in for.
Yeah, I did a little
research myself,
but nothing's really adding up.
I'm baffled as to why I'm here.
Well, I guess we'll all
find out together, then.
This is it? Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Of course.
- Watch your step.
- Thank you.
Mike.
Welcome to Akheilos.
You mean Akheilos?
As in the child Zeus
turned into a shark?
That's the one.
Please, follow me.
Okay, power it up.
Mike, recharge the battery.
I need to lay down
another set of rings.
I think you need a new DPV.
Gets the job done.
I see you've met our head of
operations, Trent Slater.
Trent,
this is Dr. Misty Calhoun.
You mind if I ask
what those are for?
We're reinforcing the
fence perimeter.
This entire complex is
surrounded by those rings?
No, we're surrounded
by electrical cable
that runs along the sea floor.
These rings are
coated in graphite,
an excellent conductor
of electricity,
as I'm sure you're aware.
We're using these
rings to extend
the range of the electric field.
Just an extra bit of insurance.
What exactly are you
guys trying to keep out?
It's what we're
trying to keep in.
Those are bull sharks.
What are you doing with
bull sharks in containment?
Welcome, welcome.
I see you've met
our test subjects.
How many do you have?
Five, including Bella. I'm
Carl Durant, you must be...?
Uninterested in small talk.
You mind explaining to me what
it is you're doing with...
what is it, you
referred to them as?
Your test subjects?
Very important test subjects.
You know, sharks
aren't lab mice.
I love your passion.
Yeah, but do you mind, I'd like
to finish the introductions.
Yeah, I'm Misty.
Well, hello.
That's Dr. Daniel Kim and Dr.
Leslie Kim.
Daniel, Leslie, Carl Durant.
Now everyone knows everyone.
What you may not know is that
those are a disaster
waiting to happen
I'm sorry, when I
asked you here,
you must have assumed I
was working with sharks.
Well, I never make assumptions,
but working with bull sharks is
a bad idea.
Yes. They are
a bit more dangerous than
traditional lab rats,
but no one is gonna
get hurt out here.
You can't guarantee that.
Actually, I can.
Would you all please
follow me topside?
I have something I'd
like to show you.
You really busted his chops.
I was just telling the truth.
Yeah, well, don't stop.
We could use some more
of it around here.
Well, the floor is
yours, young man.
Well, as Mr. Durant said,
we have an extensive
safety protocol, which...
Seriously?
- Swim, dude!
- Somebody do something!
Hang on, dude!
Whoa!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, I don't see him.
- I don't see him!
- Where'd he go?
Are you guys not going
to do anything?
Do you guys see this?
Hey, stay calm! Stay calm!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my gosh.
Help's on the way!
Be quick!
- Oh, my God.
- Are you okay?
This is not what I call okay!
Oh, God!
You can make it! Oh, my gosh!
- Swim faster!
- Oh, my God.
Five more seconds.
- Don't look back!
- Come on!
Come on, you guys.
Come on.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my gosh.
Come on, you're almost there.
- Come on, guys.
- You can make it!
Oh, my God, oh, my God.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Better get a raise for that.
Sorry, Aaron. I have a
flair for the dramatic,
but you were perfectly safe.
Did you think that was funny?
I think it was an
effective demonstration.
You're condition training bull sharks.
That's impossible.
Impossible? Really?
After what you just saw?
How did you teach them
to swim in a formation?
I'll explain everything
later, but first,
please put on some dry
clothes, settle in,
and we'll reconvene in
the wet lab in an hour.
You could get incited for this.
Relax, I'll talk to him.
Come on...
Relax?
One of your sharks bit my foot.
You're imagining things.
Look at my fricking shoe, dude.
He has playing with me, like...
He was toying with
me or something.
Sharks don't play jokes, Aaron.
You and I both know these
aren't normal sharks.
Well, it's a good thing they
don't like the taste of nerds.
Ha.
FYI, this nerd keeps this
whole place running.
Come in.
We have a problem.
Wh-what's the problem?
Sharks got out this morning.
What?
Apparently, they dug a tunnel
under the electric fence.
There was an accident.
Trent thinks they may have
killed some fishermen.
He thinks.
Meaning he didn't see it.
He was concerned enough
to mention it to me.
Okay.
So the sharks burrowed a tunnel
under the electric fence,
and then they followed
Trent back here.
Yeah?
Exactly.
And do you know why?
Because they're problem solving.
They're learning how to learn,
and they like it.
Which means the
drugs are working.
Each day, their genetic
structure evolves.
My sharks are getting smarter.
If it gets out those
sharks hurt someone,
the liability will be enormous.
There's no coming back
from that kind of PR...
The sharks are alive because
I allow them to be.
Plain and simple.
I created them.
And once my research is
completed, I will end them.
What the f... What
does that mean?
They have trackers
imbedded in their fins.
We can always find them,
whether they're here,
or out in the deep blue sea.
And once my experiment is over,
I will simply kill them.
All of them. So don't worry
about the liability.
There will be no evidence.
How can you be hungry right now?
Tsk. You know I eat
when I'm excited.
So you aren't having
second thoughts?
After Durant's stunt out there?
Yeah, he's... eccentric.
But his money's still good.
If you say so.
Hey. Look at me.
Babe, look at me.
Look, we won't regret this.
I promise. Okay?
But, um... There is something
I need to tell you.
You're gonna find
out soon anyway.
What is it?
Ahem.
I've been working with Durant
on the design of his
delivery molecules,
making them smaller,
so they effect DNA
structure more quickly.
And... I also gave him
access to some of your work.
I can't believe this.
How long?
Seven months.
You've been lying to
me for seven months?
No, not lying. Just
leaving something out.
Why would you do that?
I thought we were partners.
We are partners.
But I knew you'd be hesitant,
because of Durant's
shady reputation.
So you just decided
to go around me?
Just to check it out.
I mean, if this goes the way I
think it will, we'll be rich.
I did not get into
science to get rich.
Yeah, but with money we
can achieve so much more.
No more groveling and
having to beg for grants.
Look... You say the word,
and we can leave right now.
I mean it.
We're already out here.
I guess...
I'm sorry.
Don't ever do that again
to me, Daniel, I mean it.
I need to trust you.
I promise. All right?
We're a team.
No more secrets.
Please just stop
complaining about it.
- It wasn't cool, man.
- You're fine.
It wasn't cool.
Welcome!
Welcome, please come in.
Now, I'm sure you're all curious
as to why I asked you here.
Not everybody.
So you finally told her.
Ah. Yes.
Good for you.
Well, I've asked you here
because I need your help.
I've reached a critical
phase in my research.
Leslie, if I may
call you, Leslie,
you and your husband study
traumatic brain injury?
Among other things.
And that includes smart drugs?
Nootropics.
My company is one of
the leading producers
of biopharma drugs, including...
Performance enhancers.
You've been sanctioned by the
World Anti-Doping Agency.
In this case, intelligence
enhancers, Nootropics.
You're talking about
drugs like Adderall?
Well Nootropics can
improve memory access,
increase concentration, even
speed up your decision making.
So basically just stimulants?
That's right.
Nothing can increase
native intelligence.
Until now.
You see, I've
developed compounds
that can actually alter the
genetic structure of the brain.
Speeding up evolution
in the direction of
greater intelligence.
Much greater.
And we deliver these compounds,
using targeted antibodies.
From sharks.
You're testing these
drugs on sharks?
That's absolutely inhumane.
It's not inhumane at all.
Let me show you.
- Aaron.
- Trent,
we're ready for Bella.
All right, she's out.
They got her.
Easy, easy, easy.
All right.
Mike, you got her?
Aren't you scared,
being that close?
Nah. Sharks don't worry me.
Vitals are online.
BP 34 over 68.
Heart rate 42 bpm.
Respiration rate and
oxygen levels steady.
She's looking good.
As you can see, our treatment of
our sharks is totally painless.
If we bind a drug on
a molecular level
to the shark's antibodies,
we can then mainline that drug
to whatever area of
the brain we want.
We've already increased
Bella's base intelligence
by a thousand-fold.
And you actually
think you can get
the same results
in human beings?
I think it's an
absolute necessity
if we want to maintain the
supremacy of mankind.
Artificial intelligence is
becoming stronger every year.
Soon, quantum
computing will begin
an exponential acceleration
of the ability
of our computers to
teach themselves.
And when that happens, we'll
lose control of them,
and our world, in an instant.
Man himself...
will become obsolete.
And they will... destroy us.
But there's another way.
The human brain has a
hundred billion neurons.
Our potential is greater
than any machine.
It just needs to be...
unleashed.
So you're the savior of
the entire human race?
I think you've got
a God complex.
When I'm successful,
we can all be gods.
Or monsters.
You realize that it was
much of your research
that helped lead me in
the proper direction
in the first place?
Is your boss always
such a piece of work?
He just started taking
the new drugs himself.
They seem to kinda hop him up.
It's not exactly a secret.
He's administering the drugs to himself?
That's insane.
Dude built a multi-billion
dollar empire out of nothing.
And he's a scientific genius.
Who am I to tell him what to do?
Look, it happened.
Have you noticed any negative
side effects on the sharks
from these so-called
wonder-drugs?
I wouldn't call them negative.
Her eyesight has improved.
And she seems to be
able to communicate
with the other bulls.
- You're kidding?
- Nope, I'm not.
So what's going on here?
You know, I'm not really sure
why you brought me here.
What exactly are you
expecting of me?
Well Bella's been displaying
some unusual behaviors
that don't seem to
be directly related
to her increased intelligence.
I was hoping that you
could tell us why.
She's pregnant.
What?
That's impossible. I do blood
draws on her every week.
We'd know if she was knocked-up.
Did you do an ultrasound?
I've been swimming with sharks
since I was 7 years old.
I know a knocked-up
shark when I see one.
Why wouldn't this show up
on her hormone panels?
You said your drugs
alter her DNA.
Maybe they do more to
her than you thought.
- It's possible.
- Hey Trent?
What the hell?
You might be right.
I should have seen this myself.
Maybe you were too busy
patting yourself on the back.
Possibly.
The gen's been damaged. The
boat slammed up against it.
And on top of that, there's
a couple hundred gallons
- of fuel in the lagoon.
- What the hell, man?
What happens if the fuel
hits the electric fence?
We've got oxygen tanks stored
in the underwater bin.
Yeah, I know.
Gotta get a throat culture.
Oh, shit!
Jesus Christ!
She was supposed to be
out for another hour!
Is Bella all right?
Yes, she's fine.
- Are you sure?
- Yes!
And I'm fine too,
thanks for asking!
What was that?
"Mr. Durant has been displaying
increasingly erratic behavior,
"and questionable judgment,
ever since he began
"his nootropic regimen.
I have repeatedly
advised him against..."
Oh! What is it?
Oh my G... What's going on?
- What was that?
- I don't know.
Oh, my God.
What the hell is happening?
Does that mean the
fence is down?
Yeah, only partly.
- What do you mean only partly?
- I mean I can fix it!
- Was that an explosion?
- This whole place is on fire.
- Is that Bella?
- Yeah, she's the red one.
Does... Does she normally
separate herself from...
No, Dr. Calhoun, she does not!
What the...
Hello?
Oh, shit...
No, no, no! Come on, you
gotta be kidding me!
She's taking out the cameras.
She can do that?
What the heck?
Damn it! Hull integrity
has been breached!
Release the pressure so we
don't lose the wet pool.
You got it.
This corridor is flooding!
This is trouble.
Aah!
What is it?
Did you see that? Those
sharks tore Craig to pieces.
I've never seen a shark-bite
pattern like that before.
We're all gonna die, aren't we?
No, we're not.
Everybody calm down.
Aaron. Aaron, what's our status?
This is bad. This is really bad.
Aaron! Hull status. Are
there multiple breaches?
Only the eastern corridor...
so far.
Don't say "so far." Why
would you say that?
I've never seen
them act this way.
They're in a frenzy.
Can you please tell me a frenzy
isn't as bad as it sounds?
It means they're in
serious hunting mode.
This is so messed up.
That's why they aren't leaving,
even though the fence is down...
They're all staying to get us?
Wait a minute, wait a minute!
This doesn't make sense.
If all the sharks are
out in the lagoon,
who did that to Craig?
I know I told you not to backup
any of my research in the cloud,
but now you have to.
I can't.
Even if I wanted to, whole
system's gone down.
Oh, my God...
I figured it out.
Figured what out?
What's happening?
What is it? Spit it out.
Bella isn't pregnant anymore.
What?
She had her babies.
The drop into the wet pool
must have triggered labor.
Whatever you crated here,
Durant, is vicious.
These aren't your
typical sharks.
They're just teeth and
muscle and killer instinct.
It's the only thing that can
explain what happened to Craig.
You're talking like they're
a bunch of super-piranha.
They're worse.
Much worse.
- Look at me. Daniel.
- We can use this one...
Daniel, look at me!
Okay, breathe, baby. Breathe.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
We're gonna get through this.
- We are.
- Yeah, okay.
Come on. Come on.
Will you two please settle down.
There's no benefit
to losing our heads.
Aren't you the one who said
your security system
is infallible?
Yeah, it should've been.
Obviously, my work has been
even more successful
than I thought.
If this is success, I'd
love to see failure.
We need to get topside.
I agree.
There's just one problem.
All the exits are underwater.
Maybe they don't realize
there's a hole in the fence?
They know it's there,
they created it.
Why aren't they leaving? Misty?
There's something
here they still want.
Yeah, us.
You wanna know why
chimps are so dangerous?
Because they're smart
enough to hold a grudge!
Just like humans! I
mean, that's it, right?
It's gotta be. Bella's
not only smart,
she's mean and she
wants us dead!
The rest are her soldiers!
They'll do whatever she wants!
We are screwed! We
are so screwed!
Okay. We don't have time
for theories or meltdowns.
We gotta figure out a
way to get out of here.
Is there a way to
make a phone call...
- Like, a satellite phone?
- It only works topside.
More of our fearless leader's
fanatical trade-secret bullshit
that puts everyone else in
danger because he's nuts!
- What did you say?
- I said, fuck you!
What are you gonna do, huh?
Fire me? I quit!
So how do we get out of
here if there's no exit?
There is one other way.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
- Wet pool.
- Heh, heh! Wait, wait...
You want us to swim out of here?
No way in hell, dude. I'm
not getting in the water
with those sharks again!
No! Uh-uh! End of.
Yeah, no, Daniel and I
are not comfortable
- with that either.
- No.
You don't have to swim.
So what? We teleport?
Mike can ride the DPV
to the main hub,
call the Coast Guard
on the topside SAT.
We get help.
Yes, please, I'm a
big fan of help.
Yeah, maybe you forgot
about the baby sharks?
A little important detail there.
They must have come in
with the hull breach.
They've found food in
here, so they'll probably
stick around in here,
for a while at least.
All right, it's a solid plan,
only I'll go.
No, you won't.
You're needed here.
No, I'll go.
- No way.
- I'm going.
No. It's too dangerous
and this is my job.
I'm going whether
you like it or not.
- No need to risk your life.
- It's my life to risk.
We can't afford to lose us all!
Besides, I'm South African,
I live for this crazy shit!
Those sharks can suck my ass!
Mike, wait! Mike!
- Mike!
- Here we go!
Does anybody see him?
- Where'd he go?
- Does anybody see him?
- Where is he?
- There he is.
I see him.
Do you think he's gonna make it?
Yes.
Oh, shit, there's a shark.
- Mike!
- Mike, behind you!
Oh, my God!
- Oh, no! Mike!
- Is he dead?
- He's not moving.
- He's out.
This is not happening.
This isn't happening!
This isn't... This is....
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Come on, Trent.
- He's got him. He's got him.
- He's gonna be okay.
He's coming to the wet pool,
he's coming to the wet pool!
Come on, come on,
come on, come on!
- Can't see them.
- Where are they?
Pull them up! Pull them up!
Give her room! Give her room.
Come on, Mike! Come on, man.
Come on, Mike!
God damn it, come on!
Come on!
Got him! I got him! I got him!
Got him!
What happened?
You got blindsided by a shark.
You were dead, bro.
I knew I should have gone
and watched your six.
I told you...
Those sharks can kiss my ass...
Do we have any more weapons?
Bang-sticks, spear-guns,
strychnine nitrate?
Okay, calm down.
Everybody calm down.
I've got flares on the boat.
That's about it.
You don't... You don't
mean this, all right?
Now, you... You've spent your
entire life protecting sharks.
I help people see
that sharks aren't monsters.
But your sharks?
You've turned them
into monsters!
We cannot let these sharks
leave this complex!
We cannot let them
keep breeding!
hurt any more people!
We have to kill those
fucking sharks!
All right, but you are ignoring
the very valuable research
that they are enabling.
Listen, listen,
I am so close to a breakthrough
that will change the
course of history!
Excuse me, but you might
wanna tell that to Mike.
Oh, no, wait, you can't.
You wanna know why? Because
a shark ate his head!
We're losing pressure control.
What does that mean?
It means it's gonna blow!
Leslie!
Daniel!
Push. Come on, come on!
Come on!
- There's too much water!
- Help me, don't give up on me!
- I can't...
- Push!
Right here.
Ha! I got it!
- Good!
- I got it! I got it!
- You okay?
- Yeah. Are you?
Yeah... Jesus.
Are the different
sections of this complex
sealed away from each other?
You wanna know if
the baby sharks
are locked in the
Eastern Corridor.
Yeah, it'd be nice if they were.
No luck.
They could be anywhere.
How the hell did you end
up working for this guy?
He's out of his mind.
Yeah, only since he started
taking those drugs himself.
He was an asshole before,
but not like this.
I should have quit
this job months ago.
So why are you still here?
Why are you here?
Do you know where we're going?
Is there a way out?
Let's hope it's not flooded.
Yeah, let's hope.
Leslie!
"Come to Cape Town," they said.
- "It'll be fun," they said!
- Keep it down.
Remind me why we're going to
the crew's quarters again.
It's the farthest thing away
from the eastern corridor.
I get that, but shouldn't we
be looking for the others?
Dude, Bella's babies
are on the prowl.
We need to get out
of this water.
I get that but my gut's saying
there's safety in numbers.
Yeah? Well, my gut's telling
me we need to find a way out.
Look, Aaron. Do not
make me do this alone.
Please, man. Come on.
All right, but you better
be right about this.
This way.
Leslie!
We're gonna be fine.
How can you be so
optimistic right now?
I'm clinging to hope, dude.
It's a desperate cling, yeah,
but it's still a cling.
There's the crew's quarters. I
think we'll be safe in there.
I don't know, man, I still think
we gotta be finding
a way out of here.
Dude, we're walking fish food.
We need to get away
from the sharks
and just wait for help to come.
Yeah, and what if it
doesn't come, Josh?
So much for clinging to hope.
By the way,
if I ever ask you for a job
again, just ignore me.
Dude, you were living
in your mom's basement.
Come on.
Hey!
Where is everybody?
Haven't seen a soul.
Everyone must have scattered
through different exits.
You scared, Durant?
Be a fool not to be.
Well, it ain't no fun when
the rabbit's got the gun.
- Is it?
- How about we focus
on getting out of here?
How? We're sealed in.
If we can make it to
the filtration room,
we should be able to climb out
- through the air shaft.
- How?
They put in access rungs
to facilitate maintenance.
Oh, good, didn't
know about that.
It's a good thing
I'm here, isn't it?
- We need to find the others.
- I know...
and we will, but we
gotta get topside
and call for help first. If
there's another hull breach,
this whole thing is
gonna be underwater.
Trent's right...
Don't agree with me.
Makes me nervous.
Is he right?
I don't know.
It's the best option we got.
Let's move.
Leslie!
Can you hear me?
Leslie, where are you?
The filtration room's this way.
Let's get this door closed.
Come on.
God damn it, Aaron,
I told you to get this
goddamned door fixed!
Yeah, Josh, it's not like
I haven't been busy
the last 24 hours.
Did you hear that?
- Oh, God.
- Why did you say, "Oh, God?"
- Get away from the door, Josh!
- Shit!
Dude! Get out of there, man!
Oh, you gotta be
freaking kidding me!
Josh! Josh!
This is so not how I wanna die.
Oh, God...
No! Aaron! Aaron!
No!
- No! No!
- Josh?
No...
Josh?
Josh!
Durant, when we get out of here,
I'm gonna make sure
you're held responsible
- for what you've done.
- Well, that's what I want, too,
but they'll hear
about it from me.
Don't forget, you signed an NDA!
Oh, yeah, good luck finding it.
Or enforcing it.
- Your legal counsel's dead.
- So, you wanna see us destroyed,
all of mankind, so that you
can save what you value.
See, we're not that different,
we just value different species.
Oh, we're about as different
as two people can be.
Okay, okay. If you guys
don't stop arguing
I'm gonna feed myself
to these sharks. Okay?
Leslie?
Daniel?
Daniel!
Inside this pump?
Yes.
Daniel!
What are you doing?
What the hell are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Have you lost your mind?
Let's get out of here.
You might have just killed her!
Those baby sharks
won't get to us now.
I should kill you right here.
Yeah, but you won't.
Because you're not a murderer.
Besides, if we make it topside,
maybe you can get help
in time to save her.
Think of it as incentive.
Ugh!
It's... Ahh! It's jammed!
Durant busted the door!
Get topside! Call for help!
I'm going up.
Try to look for another way
out, but I'm coming back!
I'm coming back down!
Where are you going?
You forgot where
your loyalties lie.
Man, go to hell!
You know, I... I get her.
That woman's a fanatic.
But you've been here,
you've watched what
we've achieved
in such a short time.
You've contributed to it!
I've got the answer right here.
We can access so much more
of our brains' capabilities.
I've done it, I've felt it!
I just need a little
more time to figure out
- how to make it last....
- Anything for the project, huh?
You know, I had commanders
like you in the military!
Soldiers were just
pieces on a chessboard.
It's one of the reasons
I got the hell out.
Well, you need to get back in,
because the war is coming!
- There is no war!
- Man against machine!
You are so paranoid
that machines,
robots, computers, are
gonna wipe us out!
Let me tell you something,
from what I've seen,
man is the real threat,
man is the real problem!
You know, you have really
lost your way, Trent.
I'm disappointed in you.
Then, it's a good thing I don't
give a damn what you think.
Daniel!
Where are you?
Daniel?
Leslie! Leslie!
No! No, no, no!
C'mon! Leslie...
Leslie! No, no!
Don't go that way!
No! No, don't! Come back! Come back!
Come back! No!
C'mon, open this door!
Leslie! It's me! Come here!
Leslie, it's me! Come here!
- Daniel?
- Leslie!
Daniel!
Get out of the water!
Get out of there!
- Get out of the water!
- Daniel! Daniel!
- Daniel! Oh, my God!
- Run!
Help me, Daniel!
- Get off of her!
- Daniel, help me!
Daniel, help! Daniel!
Daniel!
Leslie!
No!
Shit.
Mayday, Mayday, Coast Guard.
This is Research
Facility Akheilos.
Requesting immediate evacuation.
We are taking on water,
we are without power,
and we are on fire.
We've suffered major
structural damage.
Requesting immediate evacuation.
I say again, requesting
immediate evac.
You are rocking this whole
staying alive thing.
Now get to that pipe...
Oh no, no, no, no...
Oh, come on!
No! This is so not fair!
Goddamn it!
Whoa! Whoa!
Daniel?
Leslie...
I'm sorry, man, sincerely, I am,
but right now, right now we
gotta keep moving, all right?
Why?
Just let me go.
I'm not leaving you here.
Just let me die.
Snap out of it, Daniel!
I can't do this on my own.
Leslie wouldn't want you
to give up on her, huh?
Why? She'd want you
to keep fighting.
I know, I know I
barely knew her, man,
but what I do know is
that she loved you.
She'd want you to live.
All right?
So right now, what
you've got to do
is you've got to live for her.
You got to live for her.
- I have to live for her.
- You got to live for her.
You can do this.
I can do this.
Yes, you can.
Come on.
Misty?
- Oh, hey! Misty!
- Oh, my God! You're alive!
- Oh!
- You're alive!
Where are the others?
They didn't make it.
I'm so sorry.
I have to live for her.
Tell me you got a
way out of here.
Yeah, there's an air shaft on
the other side of this door.
Trent's should be
topside right now,
- radioing for help.
- Thank God.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Come on, let's go.
Come on, help me with this door.
- All right.
- Pull! Pull!
Got it. All right,
stop, stop, stop.
What is it?
We're not alone.
Go, go, go. Go!
Wait, what about you...
I'll be right behind you! Go!
Come on.
Shit!
Oh! Shit!
Guys, get out of here! Go!
Come on, Aaron.
Almost there.
One rung at a time.
Oh, shit.
One rung at a time!
Damn it. Ugh.
Hurry, the waters are rising!
All right!
Give me the key.
What? No.
No.
My work's too important to
trust with a hothead like you.
Give me the goddamn
key, or I swear to God,
I will pry it from
your fingertips
and then throw you
to the sharks.
Oh, you feeling froggy?
Then jump.
Here.
Come on!
I'm going back for the others.
Don't be a fool.
They're all dead.
- We're almost there!
- Aaron!
- Keep going!
- Aaron! I got you, I got you.
Come on!
Come on, come on.
- Trent!
- Come on! Come on, I got you.
Are there others?
Daniel, Daniel's in here.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Fuck.
Dude, I led 'em on.
Shit, he's gone.
Look at this.
Holy shit, it's Misty.
Misty!
Misty, come on!
- Don't look back, come on!
- Misty, come on, swim!
Come on, faster!
Misty, come on!
Come on. Come on.
All right, come on,
come on, come on.
- Why did you...?
- I went through the wet pool.
You left me down there to die!
I should throw you in
there, you asshole!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Get off of me!
It's okay, there'll be
time for that later.
Aaron, where's Daniel?
He didn't make it.
You're the devil.
- I'm the devil?
- Yeah.
Copernicus, Galileo, Darwin.
At some point, all
scientific revolutionaries
were considered devils.
Heh, you're psychotic.
- Psychotic?
- Yeah, you're psychotic.
You just stay away from me.
Hey...
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Stay away!
Coast Guard!
They must have sent a drone
to see if my call was real.
- We're here!
- Hey!
- Hey! Hey, we're down here!
- Right here!
- Hey!
- We're down here!
- Here!
- Hey!
Why can't we catch a break?
Just one break!
Hell, I'd take half a break!
Oh, my God, my sharks
are incredible.
Yeah, maybe they'll put
that on your tombstone.
What the hell was that?
The dock structure's
starting to give.
And that means...?
It means that this dock
is gonna be in the water
in a couple of minutes.
We're dead.
No, we're not. Look.
We gotta swim for that boat.
There are still sharks in the
water, those odds aren't good.
Yeah, well, maybe
they finally left.
Maybe they're still
munching on the damn drone.
Absolutely not. We're waiting for
the Coast Guard to get here.
By the time the Coast Guard
gets here, we'll all be dead.
Christ.
- We don't have much time.
- He's right!
I am not getting in the water
with those sharks, forget it!
- You can do this.
- Oh, come on,
there's gotta be another way.
Hey, if you got a better
idea, I'd love to hear it.
This is for your own good.
Whoa!
- It's satisfying, right?
- Shut up.
Okay, let's go.
Aaron!
Oh, no.
I told you I was Bella's master!
Where's Bella?
I don't see her.
I don't see her!
Where... Where is she? Fuck!
I shouldn't have
- pushed him in.
- Don't do that!
- What?
- You were trying to save him.
Oh, hey, she's back.
She's back!
Come on!
Trent, she's gonna
tear this boat apart.
Come on!
Damn straight.
Oh! I thought you were dead!
Yeah, so did I.
He had me down again, but
this time he just let me go.
And I used this thing to
hang near the bottom.
I told you they don't
like the taste of nerd.
Yeah, this one's got a
fetish for my shoes.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Wait, wait a sec. Wait.
No. No, can't we just go home?
We can't let those
sharks survive.
Trent.
Hold on.
What's that?
Remember what Aaron said
about Durant being
ultra-paranoid
about protecting
his trade secrets?
It's true.
No frickin' way.
You gotta be kidding me.
I am not kidding.
Just like in the movies.
Yeah, just like in the movies.
My last job sucked.
They didn't try and eat me.
I'm moving back to
Silicon Valley.
All right,
let's get the hell out of here.
Come on, let's go.
I don't want to go out too deep.
What if there are
sharks out there?
There are no sharks at
this beach, I promise you.