Subtitles by explosiveskull
Sister Catherine, I come
on behalf of the devil.
You are an enemy of
Satan and you will burn
with hellfire if you
do not cooperate.
Come on, I know you're here!
Sister, are you here?
Sister, are you...
Get out!
Shit, too far.
Too far.
Hello?
Somebody!
What the hell?
No, no, no, no please, no!
Oh God, please no!
Hey, 21.09.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Have a good one.
Wait.
21.09.
You gave me 21.06.
It's three cents.
I don't have three cents.
Want some
help with that?
No, I think I got it.
Are you sure?
Ooh, pizza!
Done?
I think so.
Thank God.
Can't believe your aunt
let us stay here this long.
She has three houses.
She probably forgot
we were here.
God, three houses.
I'm excited to finally
have one house.
You didn't think
it would happen.
I didn't.
We've come a long way.
That is an understatement.
Where did you find this?
Your sister
gave it to me.
Can we lose it in the move?
No, you'd regret it.
Yeah, maybe you would.
You're not gonna make me, like,
change my look or
anything, right?
Like, ditch the nose
ring, go blonde?
Are you serious?
I mean, we're moving to
such a nice neighborhood,
and your position's so big, I...
Never.
That's who I married.
Just don't go back
to the '08 look.
Deal.
Hey, Anna, it's Lex.
Uh, call me.
I heard you and Mike are finally
moving out of his aunt's house.
I know I shouldn't be calling,
but I'd like to see Claire
before you move out.
Gettin' cleaned up, you know,
and I don't care
what some judge says,
she's my daughter
too, and I've got a.
Claire?
Hmm, where is she?
She's got a big day tomorrow.
Maybe she's under here!
No, hmm.
What about in here?
No.
I hear something though.
Maybe she's under here!
Mom?
Well you're a good hider.
I wasn't hiding.
Sure.
Did you brush your teeth?
Perfect.
Are you excited to move
into your own room tomorrow?
Very!
Can you believe it,
your very own room?
This is my own room.
No, not some old guest
room, your own room.
One that you can decorate
however you want.
I'm just glad I
don't have to sleep
on the floor like I
did in the old house.
Me too.
Oh, Daddy dropped
something again.
Again?
He's clumsy, isn't he?
Goodnight, love bug.
Night.
Jesus, Mike.
What?
Was that you?
Was what me?
Did you knock something over?
Not this time.
Comin' to bed?
Yeah, one sec.
Oh my God!
You asshole!
I didn't mean to scare you.
Yes you did!
I swear I didn't.
Yeah, okay.
You know what?
Better watch your back, Michael.
Watch my back?
Mhmm.
Michael?
Am I actually in trouble?
I thought of a way to repay you.
Oh my God.
You know,
I think Claire's
really excited about tomorrow.
Yeah, I know.
I'm just still not sure about
this private school thing.
What's wrong with
private school?
Private school's
like second place
awkward to home school.
I went to private school.
Yeah, and look at
you, you're a mess.
Mmm, yeah.
You know, it's not too
late to change your mind.
Nah.
I mean their gifted program
is supposed to be amazing.
They'll give her the
attention she needs there.
I still think you should
have gone to a gifted school.
As if!
No, no Claire did not
get her brains from me.
She sure as hell didn't
get 'em from her dad.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to bring him up.
No, um, it's actually interesting
that you mention him.
He's not calling again, is he?
No, no, nothing like that.
Um, I don't know.
Stuff with the move is
just reminding me of him
and all that shit with the
divorce and then going to rehab.
And I'm just realizing
how far I've come.
It's a good thing, right?
Of course, yes.
I guess it's just hard to stop
associating yourself
with all that.
The only thing
you need to worry
about now is moving
past all that.
Maybe I should go blonde.
Be my trophy wife?
Yeah.
I think I've always been
a blonde on the inside.
Oh, totally.
A very very very dark blonde.
Mhmm.
What, no scrubs?
Nah, I wanna
look professional.
Yeah, but I like that whole
hunky medical show vibe.
Oh yeah?
Mhmm.
Well, get to work.
Those damn teeth
don't pull themselves.
They better not.
Meet ya at the new house at six?
Yeah, yeah, I'll drive
the moving truck over.
Perfect.
Are you ready for my Aunt Donna?
Oh yeah, and I've
got a gun in my purse
in case she gets too feisty.
There she is.
Look at you!
You excited?
Yeah.
Don't be shy.
I know.
Being shy's the last thing
she's gotta worry about.
Yeah, well, you
didn't get that from me.
Goodbye, love you.
I love you too.
You ready?
Yeah.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh thank God you're here.
I can never find the right key.
I'm Donna Winslow,
I'm Michael's aunt.
Yeah, we've met.
Many times.
I'm here to check the
house before you go.
Sure, um, well
I just need to...
I'm in a hurry, I
left my dog in the car.
Oh, okay.
Um, well can you start upstairs?
It's my house, I'll
start where I want.
On second thought,
turn on my AC.
I want to be thorough.
Oh no.
Oh no, what?
Uh, was that you
in the spare room?
I was in the office.
The paint on the
wall is chipped.
It costs $55 to repaint it.
I'll need that by Thursday.
That better not
be a busted pipe.
The hardwood is scuffed.
It will cost $200 to fix it.
I'll need that by Thursday.
Don't forget your dishes.
They'll need to be
out by Thursday.
So between the paint,
the writing on the wall,
the hardwood...
Whoa, what
writing on the wall?
In the guestroom.
There's crayon on the wall.
What, no, I was just in there.
I didn't see anything.
I'm calling my
maintenance guy.
You will be here all day, right?
I don't like having
him here alone.
Do I need to be?
I kinda have to be at
the new house by six.
Yes, I'll have
him come at 6:30.
Oh God.
Hello?
Anna!
Oh my God, finally.
Uh...
Shit.
God!
Somebody help!
Get me out!
Let me out!
Please, I can't breathe!
Help!
Please help!
Barney's Pizza,
what can I get ya?
What?
Hello?
No, I need help.
Wait a second,
you're the lady
who didn't pay for her food!
What?
You know, I came
up short because of you.
9-1-1, what's your emergency?
Hello, hello, I need help.
My name is Anna Winter, I'm at...
Didn't your
mother teach you
not to hang up on people?
Listen, asshole!
No, you
listen, you little bitch!
You deserve what's
coming to you.
Who is this?
Stay with me, Anna.
Don't leave me
like you left Lex.
Lex almost killed me.
It's
a shame he didn't.
My God!
Help!
Somebody help.
Oh my God.
I didn't mean to.
What?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
You knew I'd relapse.
No, I'll go get help.
It's too late.
You let this happen.
You survived this
before, you'll do it again.
Tell Lex I still love him.
What did you just say?
Shit.
Oh my God.
Lex, Lex!
Lex, over here!
Anna, I'm sorry.
I just had to...
Lex, get
me out of here.
What?
I'm stuck, get me out!
What do you want me to do?
Smash the window.
Actually.
Lex, please.
Why?
You never helped me.
What are you talking about?
You hung me out to dry.
What?
Lex, now's not the time
to talk about this.
I just got back
from rehab, Anna,
and they said you went
through with our divorce.
You left me behind,
you saved yourself,
you destroyed our family.
I did it for Claire!
You robbed her of her father!
It was for her safety!
Don't give me that bullshit.
Like you weren't
popping pills too.
Please.
I can't wait
until you relapse.
Lex, Lex, Lex, Lex!
Mrs. Winter?
I'm here to fix the pipe.
Don't close the door!
Shit.
Wedge my toolbox in the door!
It'll give me room!
Ow, ow, no, pull me in.
No, you don't want that.
I know what I'm
doing, pull me in.
No, I'm stuck in here!
I know, it's the nun!
God, are you okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine, you?
Yeah, I'm fine.
How long have you
been stuck here?
About an hour.
I'm assuming you've
met Sister Catherine?
Yeah, she's a real
bitch for a woman of God.
No, she's great!
Busted pipe?
Apparently.
I wish it were that easy.
What is going on here?
Yeah, well it's the nun,
she's trying to kill you.
Yeah, no shit.
Yeah, well her name's
Sister Catherine.
Get out!
Shit.
Go on!
Come on.
That won't help.
It's all we've got.
Well you've got your
strength and you're wasting it.
K.K.
Anna.
I'm guessing you're
not really a mechanic?
No, actually I am.
I do all of Donna's houses.
It's actually how I
met Sister Catherine.
She's tried to kill me
every time I come here.
But you keep coming back?
Well, no one believes me,
so might as well try
to prove her existence.
Any luck?
Not yet.
But today looks promising.
I just wanna get out of here.
Hey, don't worry.
That's the easy part.
Her name is Sister
Margaret Catherine.
She's a ghost now, obviously.
Well, she thinks
she's in purgatory,
and over 100 years ago this
place used to be a convent.
You know, a holy land.
Well she's convinced
herself that she
needs to protect this
land to prove herself
to God to get into heaven.
Whoop!
But if she thinks
you're a threat to that,
well she'll chase you
away, or kill you.
I think she's
taking the kill route.
Yeah, me too.
It's a textbook
haunting, really.
You know, a tortured
soul can't rest
in peace after an
untimely death.
I've seen it a million times.
Wanna see how she died?
Yeah.
I threw up the
first time I saw it.
Oh my God.
Wait, no.
Throw something first.
Uh.
Something small.
Should have seen that coming.
God, I have hallucinating
like this since she showed up.
That's just her physical form.
It's how she moves around,
it's how she gives you visions,
it's how she messes
with the damn pipes.
Have you ever seen
the movie Ghost?
Oh my God, that's
like my favorite movie!
Great.
So you know how it
takes Patrick Swayze
a ton of energy to move
around in the physical world?
Well yeah, okay, it's like...
Exactly.
So what we need to
do is wear her out
so she won't be able to
use that physical form,
and then we can get
the hell outta here.
Follow me.
Okay, it is June 17th.
I'm here with Anna
Winter attempting
to speak to Sister Catherine.
Okay, that's an EMF reader.
The higher it gets,
the closer she is.
And if it passes
five milliguass,
it'll beep and we're fucked.
You're kidding.
What?
That's a toy!
Well so is Chucky.
It doesn't matter.
Well does it work?
No, I put it out
for decoration.
Yes, it works.
Okay, so if anything
happens, use this.
It's a pentagram.
Sometimes it scares her away.
Most times it'll
just piss her off.
Sister Catherine, Anna and
I are here to apologize.
I am not a threat
and I wanna leave.
Nope, nope, screw that.
No, no, no, no, no,
please stay, please stay.
That's normal, that's normal.
She's a little stubborn.
Stay.
Protect?
What?
Stay.
Stay with me, Anna.
It's my time to go.
You must take my place.
Sister, you don't want me.
I'm...
Your
life is not worth living.
You're strong.
Replace me as I
ascend into heaven.
No, I won't!
Then I'll force you!
Pick it up!
What'd she say?
What'd you see?
Anna!
K.K.?
K.K., I'm coming!
I'm in here.
I should
have done something.
It was her own fault.
She was always
so scared of relapse.
There was nothing
you could have done.
What about Claire?
What about her?
She's your daughter.
It doesn't feel like it.
I haven't seen her
since the split.
Anna kept her away from you
with that restraining order.
I know, and I
resent her for that.
I don't blame you.
He was dangerous.
And so were you.
I didn't do anything to you.
Then why are you so guilty?
She never could get past it.
Do you still love me?
Do you still love him?
Mike, I...
After everything
he did to you?
Mike, please!
Come here.
Get away from me.
Stay with me, Anna.
Why?
Tell my mom I miss
her and I love her.
Tell her my noose, and
I'm skipping 5th grade.
Ask her what she did.
It's an accident.
Mom?
Oh baby!
What are you doing here?
We moved back.
Are you a ghost?
What?
No, no, of course not, no.
Why would you ask
me that, honey?
You never came
to the new home.
They found you in the hallway.
Help.
Somebody please, help.
Am I dead?
Yes.
But Dad said ghosts aren't real.
He's wrong, honey.
He's so wrong.
She wants you to go.
She's here to take
you to heaven.
Who?
Your guardian angel.
Sister Catherine.
She says you won't go.
Are you with me. Mama?
I'm not going anywhere, Baby.
I'll be right here.
I'll stay.
Shit.
One, two, three.
Nice try, bitch.
Anna!
K.K., where are you?
In the attic!
I'm coming!
K.K.?
I'm up here!
'Sup?
How did you get up here?
I don't know, I
just woke up here
after you used the pentagram.
My bad.
It's part of, it's
part of the job.
Are you okay?
Oh, I'll be fine.
She just, she chewed
up my leg a little bit.
What happened?
I have no idea.
I had another one of those
silly hallucinations.
I think I saw my mom.
God, those visions
are too real.
Anna.
Stay with me, Anna.
Can you hear her?
No.
I think she's gone.
Anna, help!
Oh my God, K.K.!
Don't listen
to her, I'm right here!
Anna, I'm right over here!
I need help!
K.K., I'm coming.
Don't.
You're gonna get
yourself killed.
Anna, I can see her.
I have to do something.
She's behind
you, Anna, run!
I'm opening the door!
No!
Come on, we have to get help.
We have to go.
Give me your hand.
Give me your hand, come on.
Come on.
Sit right here.
Okay, just keep
pressure on it, okay?
Or do that, okay.
Oh God.
Just hold that there.
Keep pressure on it, okay?
Just keep pressure on it.
I'm not gonna make it.
Yes you are, just
keep holding it down!
Okay.
Hey, Anna, hey, hey,
hey, keep talking to me.
Keep talking to me.
I've been through
a lot of shit.
But killer nun is not
how I expected to go.
You're not gonna go, you're
gonna make it through this.
Sorry you didn't
get your proof.
We're walkin' proof.
Holy shit.
Come on, let's go!
Let's go!
Let's go, you can do it!
Let's just get down the steps.
Donna!
Donna, open the door!
That stupid kid.
Donna, you bitch,
open the door!
Let us out!
Come on.
Donna, you bitch,
open the goddamn door!
I don't have time for this.
She can't.
She can't hear us.
Hey, hey, our only chance is
if she actually opens the door.
Okay?
What happens if she doesn't?
Don't go, Anna!
No, Anna, come on!
Come on, stay with
me, Anna, come on!
You're home.
Come on, stay up,
Anna, don't lose.
Come on!
I'm sorry, Anna.
I'm sorry.
He better not be
screwin' that goth chick.
Kenneth, where...
Anna!
Oh my God, this
better not be my blood!
Hey, hey, we're gonna be okay.
We got out.
We're gonna get you some help.
I'm not gonna be ready
to show the house
because of this.
Look at this, look
at this blood!
Donna, Donna,.
Is she gonna be okay?
I don't know, we just
have to wait and see.
Code blue, room 305.
I love you, Anna.
I always will.
All doctors to the E.R.
Hi.
Hi there.
Sleep okay?
Mhmm.
First good sleep in a while.
Claire's still
at her sleepover.
Wanna go somewhere?
Yeah.
Hop to it, then.
Okay.
How's it looking?
Better.
Does it still hurt?
No, it's just sore.
Still don't remember anything?
No.
The last thing
that I remember is,
I guess picking up
the moving truck.
Wow.
Honestly, though,
I don't think
I wanna remember being stabbed.
That's fair.
You know that other guy, K.K.,
he doesn't remember
anything either.
I still think he
could be a suspect.
Yeah well, we'll let the
police worry about that.
Doctor Palmer gave you these?
Yeah.
But they're...
I know.
Does he think that's safe?
Well, all the other
medicines made me sick.
But I think I'll be fine
as long as we keep an eye on it.
As long as you feel safe.
I do.
I can handle it, now.
This has really changed you.
Yeah, most near-death
experiences do.
True.
It's not a bad change, is it?
No, not at all.
You just feel peaceful.
Well that's a good word.
Peaceful.
I don't even know how to shop.
I wear like the same
10 black t-shirts.
That makes it easy.
You just pick anything, though.
That's different.
Wow.
Good wow or bad wow?
Good wow.
You look amazing.
Thanks!
Honestly, I am surprised
at how much I like it.
I think this is the first time
I've seen you wearing not black.
I hope you're not doing this
because you think I like it.
No, I want to.
I'm shocked, frankly.
I wanna move on.
I wanna leave the old me behind.
I'm proud of you.
Thanks.
I'm not ditching the
attitude, though.
I wouldn't want you to.
One sec.
Yeah.
Hey, Anna, it's Lex.
Call me.
I heard you and Mike finally
moved out of his aunt's house.
I was thinking about
stopping by later.
I'm getting cleaned
up, you know, and uh.
Hey Mike, we should get
one of these for Claire.
What is it?
Well look at you!
You're not all
brains, after all!
Nope.
You still thinking about going
out for basketball next year?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Gosh, I still can't believe
that they let you
skip 5th grade.
I'm excited for middle school
Nobody should be
excited for middle school.
Hey!
Dad!
It's true!
Ooh, pizza!
I'll get it.
Hey, 21.09.
Here you are.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Yeah, have a good night.
Hey wait!
21.09, you gave me 21.06.
It's three cents.
I don't have three cents.
I'm sorry, that's all I got.
I'm so excited.
Yes!
Thank you.
Can I have the first slice?
Only if you hold it.
'Kay.
I'm gonna go get plates.
What?
Deja vu.
We had pizza in
the moving truck.
That's probably what it is.
Yeah.
Hey Mike?
What?
Did I take my pills
earlier in the car?
I don't think so.
You sure?
Positive.
Who was that that
called earlier?
Mmm, it was, uh, the doctor.
Everything okay?
Yeah, yeah, no, he was
just checking up on me.
Good.
You forgot this.
No, I didn't.
I took one in the bathroom.
When I was in there?
Yeah, I asked you.
No you didn't.
I swear I did, and if not,
then I definitely
took one in the car.
Take it just in case.
I'll take it first
thing in the morning.
I think you
should take it now.
I'm going to bed.
Anna, take it.
Michael, you never
talk to me like this.
Take it, now.
Hey, baby, are you okay?
I took too many
of those pills.
I screwed up.
Can you forgive me.
Can we talk about
this in the morning?
Sure.
Here, this will help
you feel better.
What is it?
From when I
had my stomach flu.
Mike, that's mine.
I don't know what you're...
What are
you talking about?
Get that away from me!
I wouldn't
do that to you.
I'm not taking it!
But...
I said no!
Fine.
Lex.
Um, I was just about to leave.
I thought that
maybe we could talk.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
Anna, I just wanna talk
to you one more time.
I really gotta go, I'm sorry.
Don't wreck this.
Lex, please.
Anna, I need to
tell ya something.
You're breaking the
restraining order.
I still love you.
I'm calling the cops.
And I know that you
still love me too!
I mean it!
Stay with me, Anna.
I'll shoot.
You're worth dyin' for.
Go on, hmm?
Do it.
Hmm?
Go on, do it.
Do it!
Ah!
Jesus Christ,
all right, all right!
Nothing?
Nothing.
No flashes or anything?
The only thing I remember
is the name Sister Catherine.
Okay, well, does
this ring a bell?
That's mine.
Yeah, and I remember
you telling me to use that
in case of an emergency and
putting it in my pocket.
I bought this on a
ghost hunting project.
Ghost hunting?
Um, it's a hobby of mine.
Okay, well we must have been
messing with it in
that rental house.
Doubt it.
I mean, I fixed some
pipes there once,
and I thought there might be
something paranormal going on,
but that was really it.
Okay, then how did
I end up with this?
Does it matter?
Look, strange stuff has been
happening at my house, okay?
And I think that
it has something
to do with what
happened that day.
No, you're crazy.
K.K., please.
No, no.
Anna, I really don't
have time for this, okay?
Okay, we need to find
out what happened that day.
It's over, Anna.
You gotta move on.
What the hell is this?
My medication?
Yeah, why are they all gone?
I haven't touched them.
Don't bullshit me.
You're hooked.
Mike, I swear to God,
I haven't taken one
since I got sick!
How could you do this?
Do you want a repeat of
what happened with Lex?
I didn't take them!
You're lying.
Where are you going?
Oh my God!
Everything okay?
Get away from me!
Hey baby, come with
mom.
Mom?
Come, come, come, okay.
Mom!
No, no, no, no.
Go!
You okay?
Yeah.
Anna, let me in.
Go away!
I'm serious,
something's going on.
I can't trust you!
Lex is in the house.
Daddy!
Don't you call him that!
Give me my daughter!
Stay with me, Anna.
Sister Catherine?
Leave this life behind.
What did you do to Mike?
Mike's gone.
Next I take you
or your daughter.
You don't want this
life, this struggle.
The past will never leave you.
The addiction, the
abuse, it all comes back.
You've seen it first hand.
It's you or the girl.
No, no, no, don't
die, don't die.
K.K.?
Yeah, yeah it's
me, there you go.
Where am I?
You're in the bathroom.
You got hurt in the attic.
I was stabbed.
Yeah.
Okay, in the rental house.
This is the rental house.
No, no, no, no.
No, I was out.
What are you talking about?
What do you mean?
No, no.
No, I was out!
Shit, no!
You're gonna make it worse.
You're just gonna make it worse.
Come on.
I was out.
What the hell are
you talking about?
I was out, K.K.
Oh God, it had
been three months.
And I was in the new house,
and I saw her, her face,
and she looked.
She's losing, she's
losing her physical form.
Oh my God, I've read about this.
I never thought I'd
actually see it though.
She listens to us.
Maybe that's where
she gets the visions.
I think I know what to do.
Follow my lead, okay?
We need to get out of here!
No, there's no way!
We'll go through the attic.
The fan in the attic.
We could pop it out
and get out from there.
Yes, exactly!
Okay.
Help me up.
What?
Go up there.
There's not actually
an exit up there.
Look, lure her up there
and then meet me in
the kitchen, okay?
Oh, so I'm bait, now?
Trust me, okay?
Yeah, but...
K.K.
Fine, fine.
It is June 17th.
I'm here with Anna Winter
attempting to speak
to Sister Catherine.
Sister Catherine, we surrender.
Anna has agreed to stay so
as long as you spare my life.
Isn't that right, Anna.
Yeah.
Kenneth, I know you're
in here, I heard you.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
Do your job!
Nice to see you.
You disobeyed me.
Do your job!
Keep your promise!
I can't.
Okay, okay.
Oh, thank God.
Okay, okay follow me.
Come on, K.K., let's go.
I'm sorry, Anna.
Don't be, come on.
K.K., move!
I don't really wanna
do this, I'm sorry,
but I have no choice.
No, no!
Anna, I've been
dead for three years.
She killed me in this house!
And she won't let me leave
until I kill her replacement.
K.K. don't do
this!
I tried to save us both.
If we got rid of
her, we'd be free.
No, it's not too late, K.K.
You can't beat her,
she's too powerful!
I thought we could,
but I was wrong.
Anna.
Anna!
Why'd you do it?
Like you, my life
was not worth living.
Father Don said that
if I killed myself
I would go to hell,
and I didn't care!
And then I was blessed
with a chance to return
to this land and
prove myself to God.
I wanna give you the
same opportunity.
In the name of the Father, and
the Son, and the Holy Ghost.
the Son, and the Holy Ghost!
No, no, no, no.
Anna?
Mike?
I'm here.
Where?
Mike, Mike.
Oh my God, Anna!
Sorry, sorry!
Oh, should have read
the room, sorry, sorry.
It's me.
K.K.
It's K.K., yeah.
Yeah.
Hey, I saw some spooky shit too.
I guess I'm kinda
spooky as well.
Hey, but you know
what that means?
That means we're losing
our physical form.
Okay?
Hey, hey, hey, you wanna
know how to beat her?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, Anna.
Stay with me, Anna.
Stay with me and your demons
will no longer hurt you.
Stay, Anna.
Stay with me, Anna.
Don't do this.
Don't leave me, Anna.
God!
Mike, Mike, no, Mike, no!
Oh shit!
Mike, Mike!
Mike!
Shit!
Anna?
Hi, who are you?
I'm Kenneth, a
friend of Donna's.
I'm looking for my
wife, Anna Winter.
I was supposed to
meet her two hours ago
and I haven't seen her.
Well if you wanna,
you know, come inside,
we can call her or look
for her or something.
Yeah, yeah.
Mike, don't go in there!
Mike!
Get away.
Please don't move.
Mike.
Get away from there.
Tell her to come here.
No, I'll die for her.
Dude, please, just please?
Mike, don't go in there.
Anna, get back in the truck!
What?
Get back in the truck, now!
Mike!
Anna!
It's him or it's you!
Go Anna!
Take me instead!
What, no, no!
Trust me, Mike!
No, Anna!
Wait.
Anna, no.
It's okay.
I'm sorry, Anna.
What's gonna
happen to you, K.K.?
Heaven, hopefully.
I mean, if I didn't
screw up too much.
What about Catherine?
Well, I mean, she
kinda like burst
into flames, so it
usually means hell.
Bye, K.K.
Bye.
Just hold on, just hold on.
One, two, three.
I'm gonna call 911, okay?
Mike.
It's gonna be okay.
What?
I'm so ready for dinner.
Look at you!
You're not all brains after all.
Yeah, I don't know about that.
Still wanna go out
for track next year?
Yeah, depending on
the coach, though.
Gosh, I still can't believe
they let you skip 5th grade.
I don't think I'm
ready for middle school.
No one is ready
for middle school.
That's the truth.
Ooh, pizza!
I'll get it.
All right,
so look at this cat.
Hey, 21.09.
There you go.
Thanks.
Have a good one.
Wait.
Never mind, my bad.
Oh my God, my floor!
Subtitles by explosiveskull