(THRILLING MUSIC)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(CRUNCHING)
(KNOCKING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(SLURPING)
KURT: You speak English?
(MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Kru Po he teaches you right?
(THUDDING)
Listen, I wanna train with Kru Po!
I have cash.
(CLANKING)
(THUDDING)
I just wanna train.
(CLANKING)
(MEN YELLING)
- (THUDDING)
- (KURT GRUNTING)
What the hell man?
I can't take you to Kru Po
if you have no skills.
(THUDDING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(CLANKING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(MEN MURMURING AND LAUGHING)
- Hey!
- (SNAPPING)
Prove it!
(MEN YELLING AND LAUGHING)
- (GROANING)
- (THUDDING)
(MEN CHEERING AND LAUGHING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(MEN CHEERING)
- (THUDDING)
- (MEN CHEERING)
- (GROANING)
Kavi fights better when he's drunk.
Yeah, he's so drunk
it's almost a fair fight.
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(MEN GASPING AND CLAPPING)
(MEN CHEERING)
- He's very fast.
- No, you're very slow.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GROANING)
(MEN AWING AND CLAPPING)
Por favor.
- (YELLING)
- (THUDDING)
(MEN CHEERING AND CLAPPING)
(HARD BREATHING)
(WATER SPLASHING)
Thank you.
MAN: I just lost my
position as doorman.
- You started it.
- What?
KURT: You attacked me.
I come a long way.
I wanna train with Tong Po.
I wanna train with Master Po.
(SCRUBBING)
Put it back.
(THUDDING)
And the money.
You know what, keep it.
- All of it?
- Yeah.
You need it more than I do.
(SIGHING)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SILVERWARE CLINKING)
MAN: You ﬁghters from
around the World
have been invited to train with Master Po.
And Witness the impossible.
Now, you might think that Master Po
has run out of the unthinkable.
But he'd like to challenge
himself and stay creative.
And continue to inspire you all
with an infinite imagination.
Check it out!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
The universe is composed of particles.
Which are subjected to
the power of the focus.
Quiet mind.
Again I say!
Check it out!
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(ROCK CRUMBLING)
(ROCK CRASHING)
(MEN CHEERING)
And can I get an amen?
ALL: Amen!
MAN: That's what I'm talking about.
The fight will begin.
(MEN CLAPPING)
Unless first, somebody
wanna challenge Master Po.
You mean to tell me there's
nobody here batshit crazy enough
to go a couple rounds with the master?
- Can I get another amen?
- ALL: Amen!
Let's fight.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(MEN GASPING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(MEN CLAPPING)
The next round we will add weapons.
(THRILLING MUSIC)
- (CLANGING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (SLICING)
(MEN CLAPPING)
(GROANING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
TONG PO: You come here to kill me?
Sloane.
Your brother was brave,
your brother was a warrior.
Unlike you.
Such a coward.
Come to my home with a gun
to kill me in my sleep.
- (CLANKING)
- (GROANING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Ladies and gentlemen
my brother Eric Sloane,
world champion.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Come on, you do it.
- We're gonna do this?
- Absolutely.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Alright.
(SLAPPING)
One more time, one more time.
Ready?
- (SLAPPING)
- (GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
ERIC: I need a drink.
- I'm gonna get some wine.
- ERIC: Well, look who it is.
(SCOFFING)
What brings you to this side of town?
Here to see the fabulous Eric Sloane.
- You look great.
- Thank you.
You've made a quiet a name for yourself.
I'm working on it.
Almost a modern day warrior.
Almost.
MARCIA: Heard you won the gold.
- (SIGHING)
- Yeah, I did.
So, what's next?
ERIC: I don't know.
Probably expand the gym,
get some new equipment.
Well, I have an idea.
I bet you do my dear.
You're gonna have to talk to Kurt
because he's my manager
now as well as my trainer.
Always looking out for baby brother,
- I love that about you.
- Taking care of him?
Are you kidding me, he takes care of me.
This kid always pushes me
in the right direction,
and pulls me with no
strings attached unlike
- some people in this game.
- Hm. Right.
So, who wants to go to Thailand?
Jesus, can you give a
guy a moment of victory?
We're having a party here.
- I'm talking immortality.
- Immortality.
-No rules, no ref.
Just your wit and skill to keep you alive.
What do you mean no rules?
No wait, I heard about these
underground fights over here,
But, uh, what's in it for us?
Well 200K right now.
And 200 when you land.
And the chance to be
remembered for a lifetime.
Alright, now we're talking.
Keep going.
I've got this fighter
by the name of Tong Po.
He's an undefeated Muay Thai champ.
And I think you can take it, and make
us all a ton of cash while doing so.
Kurt, wanna go to Thailand?
You know what let's talk about it later.
Let's have a drink!
It's a party!
KURT: Just don't let her
get into your head.
ERIC: It's not her getting
into my head,
have you ever seen this
kind of cash before?
We could buy this place
and be set for life.
Eric, if you decline it's okay.
It's not for everyone.
KURT: She comes in, looks
at you, smiles at you,
and you fall into her trap?
She's a crook!
She's a fight promoter
Kurt, they're all crooks.
Our job is to get as much
cash load as we can while I'm on top.
You don't know what you're walking into.
(SIGHING)
Jesus Christ, Kurt,
you're driving me crazy with this already.
You know that Thai champ
should be worried about me.
I'm a badass, you know that?
Stop being a coward.
I'm looking out for you and your career.
No, stay here and do what
you do best, just worry.
You really think you can take
the Thai champ at his sport?
Are you that arrogant?
Well, I know you don't, so
I guess I'll be doing this alone.
Thanks for the party.
- You're just gonna walk away?
- I'm walking toward a future.
(SIGHING)
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(RUSTLING)
- (SNEAKERS SCREECHING)
- (THUDDING)
Hey, Kurt!
WOMAN: Kurt!
You got something from Eric.
-He's fighting in a week.
His gold medal?
I gotta go to Thailand.
(AIRPLANE SOARING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING AND YELLING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Get up!
Come on!
(CROWD CHEERING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (GROANING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Eric! Get out!
(GROANING)
(THUDDING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GUN FIRING)
(CLANKING)
(CROWD YELLING)
Eric!
(WOMAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm so sorry.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Kurt.
- You set him up.
- We got him the best trainer.
He trained his ass off.
Eric knew what he was
getting himself into.
Sometimes these things just happen.
- (SLAMMING)
- You killed him!
(SLAMMING)
This is on you.
This is all on you!
(GROANING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
I'm just gonna say
goodbye and then I'll leave.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
ERIC: Taking care of him?
Are you kidding me, he takes care of me.
This kid always pushes
me in the right direction
and pulls me with no strings attached.
Who's this?
OFFICER: I think this is your
brother's trainer.
I think he may have something for you.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Do you mind?
I'm training him.
(SIGHING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- OFFICER: Are you Durand?
- Yes I am.
-This is Eric's brother.
(SIGHING)
-Here.
(BREATHING HARD)
This is Eric's fee for his fight.
He wanted you to have this.
If anything happened to him.
And of course,
it did.
- KURT: You're making a joke.
- Do I look like I'm laughing?
KURT: You trained
my brother Muay Thai?
Yes I did.
Why would you let him fight that monster?
I train people.
I don't tell them when to fight
and who to fight.
(SCOFFING)
You didn't train him well enough, did you?
We have to go.
Kurt! Let's go!
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
OFFICER: I'm putting you on a
plane out of the country.
If you stay, come back,
you will go to jail.
You get it?
MAN: Oh, Mr. Sloane.
We normally would welcome you
to Master Po's humble home,
but it's clear that you're
here with dubious intentions.
But when Michael Corleone
was sitting in the restaurant
across from the two man who
attempted to kill his father,
many argued that he was
wrestling with his conscious
to whether or not he could
kill them in cold blood.
I however believe that
the decision were made
the night he visited his father.
And saw him barely alive in the hospital.
He had no choice really.
He had to pull the trigger.
(IMITATING GUN POP)
And as for you Mr. Sloane,
all you had to do was pull the trigger.
I should have.
(MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(HANDCUFFS CLINKING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
You're coming with me.
(HANDCUFFS CLINKING)
(MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
By going after Tong Po like that,
you made things very hard on yourself.
And on my investigation.
You're the only eye witness
wiling to come forward
and now you're credibility's
gonna be questioned.
Credibility?
(SIGHING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(ELEPHANT TRUMPETING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(ELEPHANTS SQUEALING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
Hi-ya!
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING)
LIU: I guess I should thank
you for saving my life.
I'm the one that put you there.
You know I have orders to arrest you?
What about those guys in the street?
We'll take care of them.
In the meantime your
brother's trainer has agreed
to shelter you here.
- When did that happen?
- It's just for a few days.
(SIGHING)
Train me to fight Tong Po.
I failed Eric.
What am I gonna do with you?
(THUNDERING CRACKING)
You're gonna help me make this right.
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GROANING)
(BREATHING HARD)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (SLAMMING)
- (BREATHING HARD)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GROANING)
-(BREATHING HARD)
I will train you.
We wake up at five.
No coffee break.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (RUSTLING)
- (THUDDING)
(GASPING)
- What's going on?
- Forgot to numb the nerves.
- (WHIPPING)
- (YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
- (WHIPPING)
- (YELLING)
Shh.
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HARD)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(GROANING)
- LIU: Oh, my God.
- What?
- What are those from?
- Training.
What kind of training does that to you?
Training with Durand.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
LIU: Why are you putting
yourself through that?
KURT: When I'm training,
when I'm in that place
the pain just turns my brain off.
I don't feel anything.
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HARD)
(WATER DRIPPING)
DURAND: That's good.
(WHISTLING)
How do you feel?
(GASPING)
- You're crazy.
- I'm crazy?
One more time.
(GRUNTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Just give me a minute to catch my breath.
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(WHEEZING)
Why would you do that?
Do you think Tong Po
would give you a break?
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
Splits?
We have more to do.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- You look tired.
- Are you tired?
- He gets tired so easy.
- Why don't you rest?
-He won't let me.
DURAND: Let's have a coconut break.
- Coconuts!
- Coconut break!
You like coconuts?
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
You're supposed to try
to crack open the coconuts.
Let me show you.
- (CRACKING)
- (GRUNTING)
Kurt.
- (THUDDING)
- (GROANING)
- (GRUNTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- (THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
KURT: I'm ready Durand.
- You're ready?
- I am ready.
See? I am ready.
DURAND: Oh. You think you're ready?
Let's get a drink.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD CHATTING)
(GRUNTING)
(CRASHING)
(GROANING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
- (CRASHING)
- (GROANING)
(CROWD CLAPPING AND CHEERING)
JOSEPH: Oh, he was unlucky wasn't he?
- Huh?
- (LAUGHING)
Is there anyone that can beat my fighter?
Five thousand baht.
If you can last two rounds
gets you 50,000 baht.
Anyone?
Aw.
Master Durand.
- Lovely to see you again mate.
- (LAUGHING)
Ah, you've brought me some
more easy money have ya?
- (LAUGHING)
- I'm just messing with ya.
Joseph King by name.
- Joe King by nature, huh?
- (LAUGHING)
Eh, looks stuck up this one, yeah?
- DURAND: Yeah.
- JOSEPH: What can I do for ya?
Two rounds.
(LAUGHING)
JOSEPH: Your funeral.
- 5,000, two rounds?
- That's right.
- With him?
- You're ready, no?
- (THUDDING)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
(CROWD GASPING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(CRASHING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(GROANING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(CRASHING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GROANING)
- (THUDDING)
- (CROWD GASPING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(KURT BREATHING HEAVY)
This way.
Like I said before, just stay put.
You cannot leave this compound.
Do you understand?
It's just not safe for you out there.
Just come by anytime, I'll be right here.
Wait a second, you said he was in
training. Training for what exactly?
I'm a trainer.
That's what I do.
You stay away from Tong Po.
I'll keep him busy.
Don't worry.
And just stay put, okay?
Don't make me bring you an ankle bracelet.
- (CAR STARTING)
- Great distraction.
And not a distraction.
What are you doing here?
MAN: They kicked me out.
KURT: He's from
Tong Po's camp.
Please, come.
(SIGHING)
Just go for a second,
I need to talk to him.
Why did you come here?
Maybe you came here to get a
reward from the cops, right?
Or maybe you came here
because of your master,
Tong Po.
- Look, master Durand.
- Yes?
Maybe... Maybe you should
have trained Eric better.
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(CRACKING)
Tell me the truth.
Okay, I work for Tong Po.
Now you work for me.
And Kurt.
- How am I gonna get paid?
- Get paid?
You will keep your teeth.
Laundry.
Stop drinking and start to train.
You're good.
(SCREAMING)
- (PINGING)
- (GRUNTING)
Not impressed by your performance.
Never gonna win going back.
(GRUNTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(GROANING)
(GIGGLING)
- (CLANKING)
- (GRUNTING)
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
DURAND: Tighter.
- (GRUNTING)
- Tighter.
(GASPING)
Yeah, that's good.
Come from the inside.
Push up the chin.
Hands up, break hard.
(GRUNTING)
(THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (MUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
If you're afraid to die
in a fight with Tong Po,
you're dead.
I don't want to lose two sons.
(SCOFFING)
Tong Po's head.
(GRUNTING)
(THUDDING)
(CLANKING)
(YELLING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- (GRUNTING)
Tong Po! Tong Po!
- (THUDDING)
Tong Po!
Come on, Tong Po!
I challenge you to a fight!
Storm!
KURT: Let's go, bring it.
- (YELLING)
- (THUDDING)
(BREATHING HARD)
- (GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
Master Po has gladly
accepted your challenge.
Be prepared.
Master Po has gladly
accepted your challenge.
MARCIA: Eric's little brother
Wants revenge.
(TYPING)
A grudge match.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
KURT: Tong Po!
I challenge you to a ﬁght!
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Huh?
Wattona, darling?
What seems to be the problem?
Your place is compromised.
Do you know what we could
do with this information
knowing that she's listening?
We could send her to a
much better place for us.
WATTONA:
It's been her crusade for years.
Without her,
none of this would be happening.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Without her, doesn't that sound ideal?
You want it clean or messy?
Make her an example.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GUNSHOTS)
(BREATHING HARD)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SLAPPING)
You don't have to do this.
(MOANING)
- (BREATHING HARD)
- (CLOTHES RIPPING)
(BIRDS SINGING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
LIU: This is for your own good.
(YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
You're both under arrest.
You're a fugitive.
You're harboring a fugitive.
(SIGHING)
Love and Muay Thai don't mix.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(JAIL DOOR SLAMMING)
So your girlfriend won't
let you fight Tong Po.
We have to get out of here.
Okay.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(WHISTLING)
(LOCK CLICKING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Vous parlez Francais?
(CLICKING TONGUE)
(WHISTLING)
(THUDDING)
Hey.
Forgot about me?
OFFICER: Hey!
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(THUDDING)
Sorry.
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(WHISTLING)
(GRUNTING)
- (WHISTLING)
- OFFICER: Hey!
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
KURT: Come on!
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Whoops.
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
Let's go.
(MEN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(DRUMS BEATING)
Just let everyone know initial bets
can be placed before the first round.
No betting during fight time.
- (DRUMS BEATING)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
(GONG RINGING)
A man's strength in Muay Thai
is not just his destructive capacity.
There are often 30 to 50
deaths in the ring each year.
One of those deaths
occurred not so long ago.
Right here on this spot.
Another will occur today, right here.
Let's meet the challenger!
(CROWD BOOING)
(GROANING)
Kurt Sloane.
The brother of the last man
who died by Tong Po's hand.
His fury over the death of his brother
has led to one attempt at Tong Po's life.
He wants revenge so much
that he broke out of jail
just to be here with us today
and face his formidable enemy
in mortal combat!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Ladies and gentlemen,
the undisputed champion of all champions,
the man who defies the laws of physics.
The man who is responsible
for more than half the deaths
in the ring in the last two years,
usually in the first round.
- I give you Tong Po!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
Tong Po!
ALL: Tong Po, Tong Po, Tong Po!
Tong Po, Tong Po, Tong Po!
Tong Po, Tong Po, Tong Po...
You know what to do.
Don't think about anything else.
That champion's amulet has been
around his neck for too long.
Now you have the spirit
of Muay Thai in you
and he's going down.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(CROWD CHANTING)
(CROWD CLAPPING)
Fighters!
The rounds will be progressive,
weapons will be added,
chosen by me.
But the first round is only on
the eight points of contact.
Ready to die...
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(MAN LAUGHING)
KURT: After you.
Back to your corner!
Champion!
Challenger.
Fight!
(GRAZING GENTLY)
(CROWD CHEERING)
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GROANING)
(BREATHING HARD)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(THUDDING)
Come on, up.
(GROANING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GONG BANGING)
Is it done?
Half of 'em lined up.
MARCIA: Anyone betting on Kurt?
MAN: Couple of guys
went for the odds.
Just about three mil on Tong Po.
I'm gonna have Po stretch it
out a round, even the odds.
(BREATHING HARD)
- (CROWD YELLING)
- (GATE CLINKING)
Sit down.
(BREATHING HARD)
You're doing well.
What fight are you watching?
DURAND: This one, come on.
You're doing exactly what I want, okay?
You're doing very well.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GONG RINGING)
Surprise, surprise, surprise.
The challenger is still alive.
So let's up the ante.
Second stanza, glass.
Place your bets.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(CROWD CHANTING)
(GLASS BREAKING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
ALL: Tong Po, Tong Po, Tong Po...
(GLASS CLINKING)
(CROWD CHANTING)
(SCREAMING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GRUNTING)
Come on, get up.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GROANING)
(SIGHING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Again.
(GRUNTING)
(GONG RINGING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(SIRENS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Sit down.
Okay.
- How you doing?
- Not good.
Remember,
he's just a man.
Like you, his bones can
break and he can bleed.
Now go in there and take
that son of a bitch out.
Come on.
Let's go.
(BREATHING HARD)
(EXHALES)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
You're under arrest.
(GIGGLING)
Look, you should really check this out
before you do something stupid.
I've got some juice down in Metro.
Yeah, I know all about it.
It'll come out in prosecution.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
I'll be out in a day.
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- (SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GONG RINGING)
I am in a state of shock,
Sloane's heart is still beating.
He's proven himself a worthy
opponent for Master Po.
And with that we move
into our final round,
and the weapons shall
be our double swords.
Death is imminent.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Fight!
(CLANKING)
Get up. The swords.
Get up!
(SLICING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GROANING)
TONG PO: Your brother was brave.
Your brother was a warrior.
(SNAPPING)
Unlike you, such a coward.
If you're afraid to die
in a fight with Tong Po,
you're dead.
I don't Want to lose two sons.
You don't have to do this.
- (THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Come on.
(YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(CROWD CHANTING)
DURAND: You're a warrior
and he's going down.
- (GRUNTING)
- (THUDDING)
Come on.
(THUDDING)
That's my boy.
(GROANING)
(CROWD CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Coconut.
Again, coconut!
Come on.
(GRUNTING)
- Yeah!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
(BREATHING HARD)
(GRUNTING)
(SLICING)
(CHOKING)
KURT: This is for Eric.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(CROWD CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Eh!